<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Officer-involved shootings on Justin Nix</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/tags/officer-involved-shootings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Officer-involved shootings on Justin Nix</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://jnix.netlify.app/tags/officer-involved-shootings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gun victimization in the line of duty: Fatal and non-fatal firearm assaults on police officers in the United States, 2014-2019</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/33-cpp-gva/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/33-cpp-gva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replication files are available at the top of this page. All analyses were performed in Stata v15.1. For Figure 4, you will need to install Michael Stepner&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://michaelstepner.com/maptile/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;maptile and spmap&lt;/a&gt; commands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gun Violence Against U.S. Police Officers: Insights from a New Dataset</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post10-gvaanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post10-gvaanalysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a forthcoming paper in &lt;em&gt;Criminology &amp;amp; Public Policy&lt;/em&gt;, Michael and I conducted an exploratory analysis of fatal and non-fatal firearm assaults on U.S police officers using six years of public data provided by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gunviolencearchive.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gun Violence Archive&lt;/a&gt;. We adopted the following inclusion criteria:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Victim was a sworn officer employed by a local, state, or special jurisdiction law enforcement agency that routinely responds to calls for service (i.e., officers employed by town, city, or county agencies, sheriff’s departments, state agencies, tribal police, university police, transit police)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Victim was on duty at the time of assault&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bullet struck the victim’s person or his/her equipment (excluding vehicle)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bullet came from a real firearm (i.e., not a pellet/BB gun or shrapnel from an explosion)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The shooter was not a police officer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We excluded off-duty firearm injuries, self-inflicted injuries (whether accidental or intentional), and injuries resulting from friendly fire. Our analysis also omitted cases in which a suspect fired at but did not strike an officer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We identified 1,467 officers who were assaulted by gunfire across 1,185 incidents (1.24 officers per incident). Of them, 249 died and 1,218 survived. This underscores the importance of examining nonlethal shootings alongside fatal shootings in order to understand the true prevalence of potentially lethal violence against police officers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the national level, the rate of firearm assaults per 100,000 sworn officers has fluctuated between 29.9 and 44.1 over the last six years. Though there was a notable spike in 2016, the data don’t provide clear evidence of a significant increase in firearm assaults of police officers over this period. This finding is in line with a recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1177/1098611120919441&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;analysis&lt;/a&gt; by Michael White that focused on ambush-style attacks on police: despite some single-year spikes, there is no evidence of a longitudinal increase in ambushes against police.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the state level, the number of firearm assaults ranged from a low of 2 (in Delaware, Montana, North Dakota, Rhode Island, and Vermont) to a high of 143 in Texas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/GVA1.png&#34; alt=&#34;GVA1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ordering is unsurprising for a simple reason: there are far more officers in Texas than most other states. To account for differences across states in the number of police officers, we calculated state-level rates per 1,000 officers using Police Employee data provided by the FBI. Using these rates provides a different view of the relative incidence of firearm assault across states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/GVA2.png&#34; alt=&#34;GVA2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of being at the top of the list, Texas falls to 18th. California, which has the 2nd highest frequency of firearm assault on police, falls to 38th when using a rate. Overall, rates varied from a low of 0.06 firearm assaults per 1,000 officers in Connecticut to a high of 1.56 per 1,000 in New Mexico (at first glance, Mississippi’s rate is higher, but this rate is biased by statewide underreporting of Police Employee data to the UCR).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at things spatially, some interesting patterns emerge. Generally, Northeastern states have a lower firearm assault rate than states in the South Eastern and South Western United States. However, the story is not strictly regional: Utah and California’s rates, for example, are more similar to New York and Massachusetts than to nearby Arizona and New Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/GVA3.png&#34; alt=&#34;GVA3&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The behind the scenes work with GVA data also provides some really important lessons for future work. Early on, we made the decision to manually vet each case by using the news story URLs that GVA includes with each assault record. In cases where links were dead or missing, we did manual searches using the listed date, location, and other details to try and find an online record with which to verify case details. I shudder remembering about how long this took us (thanks to Kateryna Kaplan at Rutgers SCJ for her help with this arduous task!), but it proved to be a valuable experience. We ultimately excluded &lt;strong&gt;510 incidents&lt;/strong&gt; from the original dataset which didn’t meet our inclusion criteria—&lt;strong&gt;over 25% of the raw data we received from GVA!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A handful of cases were &lt;em&gt;incredibly&lt;/em&gt; difficult to adjudicate and illustrate just how challenging it can be to boil down complex social realities into even seemingly straightforward variables like fatal/nonfatal. Consider Sgt. Ron Helus of the Ventura County Sheriff’s Department, who was shot six times while responding to an active shooter situation. Five of those shots were fired by the suspect, but the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/officer-killed-responding-to-thousand-oaks-mass-shooting-was-fatally-struck-by-friendly-fire-police-say/2018/12/07/e7405186-fa52-11e8-8c9a-860ce2a8148f_story.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Coroner&lt;/a&gt; ruled that the sixth and ultimately fatal shot was fired from the rifle of another officer. We decided to retain this incident as a &lt;em&gt;nonfatal&lt;/em&gt; shooting because, though we were certain he was shot by a suspect, we could not say whether he would have died had he not been struck in the heart by friendly fire. Others might have coded this incident differently. What is very clear is that this sort of data must be coded and analyzed with caution and transparency. Taking GVA data (or &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; crowdsourced data, for that matter) at face value is not advised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finish out the paper with discussion of future directions for research and data collection efforts focused on force by and against police. It’s scheduled for inclusion in the August 2020 Special Issue on Policing but will appear &lt;em&gt;online first&lt;/em&gt; sometime before then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt; In the meantime, click on the PDF button above to download the post-print (accepted) version of our paper.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome your feedback!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&#34;2&#34;&gt;* &lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: I’ll accept positive feedback but please direct any negative feedback to Michael 😄&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Shooting Research and the Conditional Probability Mistake</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post9-response-to-aw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post9-response-to-aw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, Andy Wheeler &lt;a href=&#34;https://andrewpwheeler.com/2020/01/26/statement-on-recent-officer-involved-shooting-research/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; a summary of the problems with recent studies about officer-involved shootings, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/1745-9133.12269&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; my colleagues and I published in February 2017. As usual, Andy’s criticisms were thoughtful and spot on. And I hope I can take him up on that conference beer soon, even though he’s at a new job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, I do want to push back just &lt;em&gt;a little&lt;/em&gt; about the motivation for our paper. Brad and I had the idea for it because journalists and activists were getting the denominator wrong when they tried to interpret the (at the time) new WAPO &amp;amp; Guardian data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember daily conversations with Brad and Geoff about what we could and could not learn from these new crowdsourced data in the absence of a meaningful benchmark. Ultimately, we felt it was informative to determine whether - strictly in this universe we had data on (i.e., fatal shootings) - race was correlated with having been unarmed while controlling for threat. At the very least, we thought it was a more reasonable way of analyzing the data than how it was being used at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really tried to be transparent about the limitations of the data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/AW1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AW1&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/AW2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AW2&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/AW3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AW3&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, with the benefit of hindsight, we’d be even more careful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree wholeheartedly with Andy that &lt;em&gt;the question of whether &amp;ldquo;the police&amp;rdquo; are racially biased is a facile question.&lt;/em&gt; But I also recognize it’s a question that journalists, activists, and others routinely try to answer simply by looking at raw numbers reported by WAPO or &lt;em&gt;Mapping Police Violence&lt;/em&gt; (or at most, benchmarking them against the general population). Consistent with the first retort Andy said he often hears, I feel it is our responsibility as social scientists to learn what we can from the data we have, and push for better data so that we can continue to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/AW4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AW4&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, I’ve written extensively about the importance of using better benchmarks to understand disparities in policing. See for example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0735648X.2018.1547269&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/07418825.2019.1675748&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0047235219304398&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s complex, to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And now, thanks to Knox, Lowe, and Mummolo’s fascinating &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3336338&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;forthcoming paper&lt;/a&gt;, I realize it’s even more complex than a lot of us thought.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, Andy hit the nail on the head here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/AW5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;AW5&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got some pretty nasty emails after that CPP paper, and occasionally still have my motives questioned by folks on both sides. It’s unfortunate, because I think that sort of thing scares a lot of really sharp people away from doing this research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New preprint: Do police killings of unarmed persons really have spillover effects?</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post8-bor-replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post8-bor-replication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018, &lt;em&gt;The Lancet&lt;/em&gt; published a quasi-experimental &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(18)31130-9/fulltext&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by Jacob Bor, Atheendar Venkataramani, David Williams, and Alexander Tsai (hereafter BVWT) that alleged &amp;ldquo;police killings of unarmed black Americans have effects on mental health among black American adults in the general population&amp;rdquo; (p. 302). From this, BVWT extrapolated that police killings of unarmed black Americans may cause as many as 55 million poor mental health days each year among black adults in the US, an effect &amp;ldquo;nearly as large as the mental health burden associated with diabetes&amp;rdquo; (p. 308).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thelancet.com/pdfs/journals/lancet/PIIS0140-6736(18)33043-5.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;written correspondence&lt;/a&gt; published alongside the study, James Lozada and I pointed out several cases in their data that were misclassified as involving unarmed decedents, when in fact they were in posession of deadly weapons. We also argued that individuals in posession of toy/replica firearms should have been coded &amp;ldquo;armed&amp;rdquo; instead of &amp;ldquo;unarmed.&amp;rdquo; BVWT &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(18)33060-5/fulltext&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;replied&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;[a]lthough some degree of misclassification of exposure is possible, it is improbable to have substantially affected our estimates or conclusions.&amp;rdquo; Surprisingly, they did not revisit their data or analyses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to December 2019. &lt;em&gt;Science Advances&lt;/em&gt; published a &lt;a href=&#34;https://advances.sciencemag.org/content/5/12/eaax7894&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; which employed a similar methodology and claimed to show a causal relationship between exposure to police killings of unarmed black persons and decreased birth weight among black infants in California. The article was &lt;a href=&#34;https://advances.sciencemag.org/content/5/12/eaba5491&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;retracted&lt;/a&gt; 8 days later after a reader found several misclassified incidents which, when corrected, rendered the author&amp;rsquo;s primary finding non-significant. Seeing how this played out, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if the same might be true of BVWT&amp;rsquo;s article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a new &lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/preprints/socarxiv/ajz2q/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;preprint&lt;/a&gt;, James and I reexamined 303 police killings in BVWT&amp;rsquo;s study that were classified as involving &amp;ldquo;unarmed black victims.&amp;rdquo; We identified 91 incidents that were misclassified (i.e., 30% of all &amp;ldquo;unarmed black victims&amp;rdquo;). The table below summarizes them (additional details are available in the study&amp;rsquo;s appendix).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/bor_rep_tab1.png&#34; alt=&#34;bor_misclassifications&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, many of the misclassified incidents involved people who were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(1) not killed intentionally by on-duty police officers (n=52)&lt;/strong&gt;, or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2) armed with a weapon/struggling for officer&amp;rsquo;s firearm (n=13)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another &lt;strong&gt;26 incidents&lt;/strong&gt; involved individuals in posession of toy/replica firearms or objects that might have reasonably resembled a deadly weapon (e.g., David Andre Scott told SWAT officers he wasn&amp;rsquo;t coming out of his house without a fight, then came out screaming and pointing a black object at officers, which they later discovered was a small box shoved inside of a black sock). Whether these individuals should be coded &amp;ldquo;armed&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;unarmed&amp;rdquo; is debatable. BVWT remarked &amp;ldquo;the fact that 12-year-old Tamir Rice was armed with an Airsoft replica gun did little to assuage concerns in the community about the conduct of former officer Timothy Loehmann.&amp;rdquo; Seemingly, their point was that community members may believe police killings of persons armed with toy guns are injustices on par with police killings of persons who have neither a weapon nor anything resembling a weapon. Thus, BVWT suggest it is reasonable to lump them all together as &amp;ldquo;unarmed victims.&amp;rdquo; We respectfully disagree, but this is ultimately an empirical question. As such, BVWT should have conducted a supplemental analysis whereby anyone with a toy gun was treated as armed. In this way, they could have determined whether their findings were sensitive to the coding of these highly controversial incidents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dataverse.harvard.edu/dataset.xhtml?persistentId=doi:10.7910/DVN/VGYI0E&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;data and code&lt;/a&gt; made available by BVWT, we first successfully replicated the results reported in Table 3 of their study. Then, we dropped the 52 individuals who weren&amp;rsquo;t killed intentionally by on-duty cops, and re-coded as &amp;ldquo;armed&amp;rdquo; 13 individuals who were misclassified as &amp;ldquo;unarmed.&amp;rdquo; Upon re-estimating the authors&amp;rsquo; models, we found that all of the coefficients decreased in magnitude and were no longer statistically significant. Finally, we recoded the 26 individuals who had toy guns or objects resembling weapons as &amp;ldquo;armed&amp;rdquo; and again re-estimated their models. Again, the coefficients were smaller than in the original study and not statistically significant. In other words, using the corrected data, &lt;strong&gt;we did not find a statistically significant &amp;ldquo;spillover effect&amp;rdquo; of police killings of unarmed black persons on the mental health of black Americans&lt;/strong&gt;. Furthermore, our failure to replicate BVWT&amp;rsquo;s findings was not due to our fundamental disagreement about how to code individuals with toy guns. It was because BVWT failed to remove dozens of incidents that should not have been included in their analyses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two final points are in order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;First: researchers, journalists, and others who study/write about police use of deadly force &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; be cautious when analyzing crowdsourced data, and describe their methods and results carefully. In the introduction of their paper, BVWT claimed &amp;ldquo;police kill more than 300 black Americans - at least a quarter of them unarmed - each year in the USA.&amp;rdquo; A closer inspection of their data revealed this claim is, at best, terribly misleading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second: we really need to move beyond reducing police deadly force incidents to whether the person was armed or unarmed. That&amp;rsquo;s not to suggest it isn&amp;rsquo;t useful information. But on its own, it&amp;rsquo;s a poor measure of the appropriateness of officer actions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;PDF&lt;/strong&gt; button above to download a copy of our preprint from SocArXiv.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to Justin Pickett, Michael Sierra-Arévalo, Natalie Todak, Scott Wolfe, and John Paul Wright for their helpful comments on earlier drafts of this manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Police Killings of Unarmed Persons Really Have Spillover Effects? Reanalyzing Bor et al. (2018)</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/preprint-bor_replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/preprint-bor_replication/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considering Violence Against Police by Citizen Race/Ethnicity to Contextualize Representation in Officer-Involved Shootings</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/30-jcj-oisbenchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/30-jcj-oisbenchmarks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My co-author &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Shjarback_CCJ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;John Shjarback&lt;/a&gt; summarizes the paper nicely in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Shjarback_CCJ/status/1204790201714958344&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowdsourced police shooting data: What we know and what we&#39;re missing</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/talk/asa2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/talk/asa2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At an invited session hosted by the Section on Crime, Law, and Deviance, Geoff Alpert and I discuss the strengths and weaknesses of crowdsourced OIS data. Other panelists include Malcolm Holmes (University of Wyoming); Gregory Zimmerman, Emma Fridel, and Keller Sheppard (Northeastern University); and Mitchell Chamlin (Texas State).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to download a copy of our presentation.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That new study in PNAS on fatal officer-involved shootings</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post3-that-new-pnas-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 13:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post3-that-new-pnas-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new study published in PNAS, titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pnas.org/content/early/2019/07/16/1903856116&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Officer characteristics and racial disparities in fatal officer-involved shootings&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is getting lots of &lt;a href=&#34;https://pnas.altmetric.com/details/63894008/news&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;attention&lt;/a&gt; (34 news articles and tweeted by 1,808 users with an upper bound of 9.8 million followers as of 7/30/2019). It concludes, among other things, that &amp;ldquo;White officers are not more likely to shoot minoritiy civilians than non-White officers,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Increasing diversity among officers by itself is unlikely to reduce racial disparity in police shootings.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DrPhilGoff/status/1155916041924431872&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Others&lt;/a&gt; have been &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jonmummolo/status/1153686295845244929&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;critical&lt;/a&gt; of the study, for good reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I commend the authors for being up front about a key limitation of their work: &amp;ldquo;Our analyses speak to racial disparities in the subset of shootings that result in fatalities, and not officers&amp;rsquo; decisions to use lethal force more generally.&amp;rdquo; But unfortunately, this gets lost in &lt;a href=&#34;https://abcnews.go.com/Health/fatal-police-shootings-race-officer-predictive-civilians-race/story?id=64563567&amp;amp;cid=clicksource_4380645_null_headlines_hed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;media coverage&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/PoliceOne/status/1155914391973441536&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.com/post/post2-fatality-rates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;posted&lt;/a&gt; about this before. Fatal OIS are not a random sample of all OIS, so statistical analyses of them may serve to mislead us rather than shed light on the truth. Take a look at Table 2 on page 3 of their study:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/pnas_table2.png&#34; alt=&#34;pnas_table2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The million dollar question here is: how often did each &amp;ldquo;variable&amp;rdquo; occur in 2015 when officers &lt;strong&gt;did not use deadly force&lt;/strong&gt;? As but one example, how often did police officers encounter suicidal civilians? In a &lt;em&gt;small subset&lt;/em&gt; of these incidents, officers fatally shot the suicidal citizen. That&amp;rsquo;s what is being analyzed in Table 2 for evidence of racial disparity. Not included in Table 2 are numerous incidents wherein the outcome was something other than a fatal OIS (e.g., nonfatal OIS, less lethal force, no force). Without knowing the racial breakdown of these counterfactual incidents, it isn&amp;rsquo;t possible to conclude anything about the &amp;ldquo;likelihood&amp;rdquo; of officers shooting minorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next month, at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://convention2.allacademic.com/one/asa/asa19/index.php?cmd=Online+Program+View+Session&amp;amp;selected_session_id=1479837&amp;amp;PHPSESSID=2b88b5bc2glse47gdg2iriajh5&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ASA meeting&lt;/a&gt; in NYC, Geoff Alpert and I will be discussing the benefits and drawbacks of analyzing crowdsourced OIS data. Chief among the drawbacks is that most track only fatal OIS, and the racial breakdown of fatal OIS often differs substantially from the racial breakdown of &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; OIS. Here&amp;rsquo;s a table I made with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.vice.com/en_us/article/a3jjpa/nonfatal-police-shootings-data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;VICE data&lt;/a&gt; I mentioned in my last post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/asa_comparison_table.png&#34; alt=&#34;asa_comparison_table&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among 21 jurisdictions with near complete data (&amp;lt; 5% missing) on the race of citizens shot by police from 2010-16, you can see that as you move from examining just fatalities to examining all OIS, %white decreases while %black increases. In some cities, the differences are more pronounced than others. Take Nashville, for example, where there were 39 OIS (only 11 of which were fatal):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/asa_nmpd.png&#34; alt=&#34;asa_nmpd&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, %white and %black basically flip from fatal OIS to all OIS. Perhaps the differences would be nonsignificant in a national database, but that remains unknown since no national database includes nonfatal OIS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We need to know about every time an officer shoots at a person, regardless of whether the person is killed.&lt;/strong&gt; We also need to know about the universe of incidents wherein it might have been reasonable for officers to use deadly force, but they &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/0011128718756038&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;refrained from it&lt;/a&gt;. But as others have &lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3336338&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;pointed out&lt;/a&gt;, police administrative records are themselves biased if officers racially discriminate when choosing whom to investigate (the implication is we also need to know who they &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; stop). There are no easy answers here. But for now, I see no reason why we can&amp;rsquo;t track nonfatal in addition to fatal OIS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-info&#34; role=&#34;info&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt; Click the CODE button at the top of this page to replicate these figures using Stata. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The problems with OIS data that only capture fatalities</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post2-fatality-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2019 13:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post2-fatality-rates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few years, several websites that compile fatal officer-involved shooting (OIS) data have become available. These include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Washington Post&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2019/national/police-shootings-2019/?utm_term=.0968583ac95c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fatal Force&lt;/a&gt; data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://killedbypolice.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Killed By Police&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://fatalencounters.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fatal Encounters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mappingpoliceviolence.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mapping Police Violence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/ng-interactive/2015/jun/01/the-counted-police-killings-us-database&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Counted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These databases are useful for answering some of the most basic questions about OIS. For example, a few years ago my colleagues and I &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/0011128716686343&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;analyzed the Killed By Police data&lt;/a&gt; and found that fatal OIS have neither increased nor decreased significantly since the shooting of Michael Brown in Ferguson, MO (despite claims to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://theundefeated.com/features/fatal-police-shootings-on-the-rise/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;contrary&lt;/a&gt;). More recently, we used The Washington Post&amp;rsquo;s data to discuss the strengths and weaknesses of various &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0735648X.2018.1547269&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;benchmarks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; that can be used to make sense of racial disparities in fatal OIS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I worry gets lost on many people is that these data only capture &lt;em&gt;fatal&lt;/em&gt; OIS. But if an officer purposely discharges his/her firearm at a person, the officer has used deadly force &lt;em&gt;regardless of whether the person is killed&lt;/em&gt;. And in fact, OIS frequently do not result in death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 1980s, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/07418828800089691&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;James Fyfe summarized seven studies&lt;/a&gt; that had analyzed OIS and found that fatality rates ranged from a low of 21% in Philadelphia (1975-78) to a high of 41.7% in Los Angeles (1974-78). A few years ago, &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/1745-9133.12174&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;David Klinger and colleagues&lt;/a&gt; analyzed 10 years&amp;rsquo; worth of OIS by the St. Louis Metropolitan Police Department (2003-12), and found that 230 OIS resulted in 37 citizen fatalities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, VICE News compiled &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.vice.com/en_us/article/xwvv3a/shot-by-cops&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; on both fatal and nonfatal OIS in 47 of the largest 50 jurisdictions in the United States from 2010 to 2016. They documented 4,400 OIS - at least 1,382 of which were fatal (31.4%). Even if we assumed all of the 288 OIS with &amp;ldquo;unknown&amp;rdquo; outcomes were fatal, the overall fatality rate would increase only to about 38%. But the overall fatality rate, whatever it is, masks a ton of variation within this sample:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/vice_table.png&#34; alt=&#34;vice_table&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focusing just on the jurisdictions with 100+ OIS, you can see that fatality rates during this time ranged from a low of 16.8% in St. Louis to 51.9% in Phoenix. Now consider some of the conclusions you might draw if you only had the &amp;ldquo;fatal&amp;rdquo; columns. You would probably conclude that police in Las Vegas shoot citizens over twice as often as police in St. Louis (47 v. 20). But the reality is that their OIS totals were virtually identical (115 v. 119). Similarly, while Boston and Atlanta each had 10 fatal OIS, Boston had just 4 additional nonfatal OIS, while Atlanta had an additional 32. And keep in mind these are just raw counts which don&amp;rsquo;t account for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0735648X.2018.1547269&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;differences in population or violent crime rates&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many factors at play which likely influence whether an OIS results in a fatality, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;type and caliber of gun used by officer(s)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;number of rounds fired&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;proximity to the nearest Level 1 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMsa052049&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trauma Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;departmental policy on rendering aid&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if/how many bullets hit vital organs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last factor can come down to centimeters, which is a big part of the reason why OIS data that only capture fatalities can be misleading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear, even complete data on fatal and nonfatal OIS (which Texas and a few other states are now &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/0735648X.2018.1547353&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;collecting&lt;/a&gt;) would leave important questions unanswered. Ultimately, to make sense of patterns/trends in OIS, we need to be able to compare incidents that resulted in OIS to a comparable universe of incidents that did not result in OIS. As Andrew Wheeler and his colleagues &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1525107118759900&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;have demonstrated&lt;/a&gt;, we really need data on all instances in which officers draw and point their firearms, regardless of whether they ultimately shoot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our understanding of OIS has come a long way since Fyfe&amp;rsquo;s pioneering work in the 70s and 80s. But we&amp;rsquo;ve still got a long way to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validity of details in databases logging police killings</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post1-the-lancet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/post/post1-the-lancet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thelancet.com/journals/lancet/article/PIIS0140-6736(18)31130-9/fulltext&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; published last year in The Lancet concluded that &amp;ldquo;police killings of unarmed black Americans have adverse effects on mental health among black American adults in the general population.&amp;rdquo; They used &lt;a href=&#34;https://mappingpoliceviolence.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mapping Police Violence&lt;/a&gt; data, wherein individuals are coded as &amp;ldquo;unarmed&amp;rdquo; if they had a toy/replica gun or if they were &amp;ldquo;alleged to be armed by the police, but multiple independent witnesses maintain the person was unarmed.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are &lt;strong&gt;hugely&lt;/strong&gt; important caveats. Toy/replica guns can be nearly indistinguishable from actual guns, especially in a matter of split seconds. This is why similar databases compiled by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/graphics/2019/national/police-shootings-2019/?utm_term=.ea6193d6288e&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/series/counted-us-police-killings&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; are careful to label such incidents as involving toy/replica guns, rather than no weapon at all. Likewise, it is debatable whether we should dismiss police accounts of an incident simply because two or more witnesses disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One Saturday last summer, my colleague, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ww2.mc.vanderbilt.edu/physcifaculty/53075&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;James Lozada&lt;/a&gt;, and I decided to take a closer look at 110 fatal officer-involved shootings (OIS) that occurred from 2015 to 2017 involving a black citizen who MPV coded as &amp;ldquo;unarmed.&amp;rdquo; We focused specifically on OIS deaths because (1) these account for the vast majority of citizen fatalities at the hands of police, and (2) WAPO&amp;rsquo;s data do not include deaths by other means. Among these 110 OIS, &lt;strong&gt;36&lt;/strong&gt; involved individuals &lt;strong&gt;who were not unarmed&lt;/strong&gt; according to WAPO and The Guardian. Most had a toy/replica firearm, but four had an actual firearm, one had a knife, and three were undetermined according to WAPO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/lancet_table.png&#34; alt=&#34;lancet_table&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lancent published our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thelancet.com/pdfs/journals/lancet/PIIS0140-6736(18)33043-5.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;written correspondence&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year, though unfortunately, we were limited to 250 words. Our original submission was approximately 1,000 words and included tables that listed the discrepancies between MPV and WAPO/The Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our main takeaway was that the study&amp;rsquo;s conclusions may have been overstated, since MPV technically miscodes so many incidents each year. In fairness, the difference between an OIS involving someone who was &amp;ldquo;unarmed&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;holding/pointing something that looks like, but is not, an actual gun&amp;rdquo; may be irrelevant in terms of how the community views the incident after the fact. But the authors could have easily recoded these incidents and run sensitivity models to see if their substantive findings changed. At a minimum, researchers must be clear about these little, but critical, details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;PDF&lt;/strong&gt; button above to download a copy of our original submission (i.e., before we were asked to trim it to 250 words).
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of 2018 Use of Deadly Force by the Phoenix Police Department</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/report-pf_phx_ois/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/report-pf_phx_ois/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disparity Does Not Mean Bias: Making Sense of Observed Racial Disparities in Fatal Officer-involved Shootings with Multiple Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/23-disparity-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/23-disparity-bias/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domestic Disturbances and Fatal Police Shootings: An Analysis of the Washington Post’s Data</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/17-domestic-ois/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/17-domestic-ois/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Number of Citizens Fatally Shot by Police Increasing in the Post-Ferguson Era?</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/15-are-fatalois-increasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/15-are-fatalois-increasing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of _When Police Kill_</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/bookreview-when_police_kill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/bookreview-when_police_kill/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bird&#39;s Eye View of Civilians Killed by Police in 2015: Further Evidence of Implicit Bias</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/6-birds-eye/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/6-birds-eye/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
