<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 07:04:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Pretti’s death ruled homicide after Minneapolis shooting by federal agents</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4365188/posts</link>
      <description>The death of Alex Pretti, the Minneapolis man killed by federal agents, has been ruled a homicide, the Hennepin County medical examiner’s office said. Pretti was shot Jan. 24 during a chaotic encounter with federal immigration officers in Minneapolis. Citing …</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inquest into police shooting of 16-year-old Eishia Hudson begins</title>
      <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/manitoba/eishia-hudson-fatality-inquest-winnipeg-police-9.7070897</link>
      <description>A fatality inquest into the police shooting of a 16-year-old girl following a car chase in Winnipeg has started.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arizona man accused of human smuggling is a repeat offender who once 'threw rocks' at Army helicopter: docs</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/arizona-man-accused-human-smuggling-repeat-offender-who-once-threw-rocks-army-helicopter-docs</link>
      <description>Suspected human smuggler shot by federal agents near Arizona border is repeat offender, officials say. Patrick Schlegel allegedly fired at agents.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shooting in Georgia hotel room leaves 1 officer killed, another seriously wounded: 'Unprovoked attack'</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/shooting-georgia-hotel-room-leaves-1-officer-killed-another-seriously-wounded-unprovoked-attack</link>
      <description>A Georgia police officer was killed and another was wounded after a suspect allegedly opened fire in a hotel room as he was being questioned.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 08:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police officer killed, another critically wounded in shooting at Georgia hotel - ABC News</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180718578</link>
      <description>Police officer killed, another critically wounded in shooting at Georgia hotelABC News Gwinnett County officer dead, another officer injured in ‘unprovoked attack’ at hotelWSB-TV Gwinnett Police: Suspect who killed one officer, injured another had long crimin…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 03:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police officer killed, another critically wounded in shooting at Georgia hotel</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/police-officer-killed-critically-wounded-shooting-georgia-hotel-129755947</link>
      <description>Gunfire broke out after two officers were dispatched on a call reporting fraud.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 20:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antifa Member Declares 'Guerrilla War' Against ICE After Minnesota Shooting of Armed Suspect</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4365027/posts</link>
      <description>A Minneapolis man who calls himself “Antifa” urged his nearly 36,000 Instagram followers to “get your f***ing guns” and “stop” federal law enforcement, after a Border Patrol agent fatally shot an armed man in his city. Kyle Wagner, a self-described “entrepren…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 19:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE shooting suspect had prior violent encounter with agents, records show</title>
      <link>https://www.naturalnews.com/2026-02-01-ice-shooting-suspect-prior-violent-encounter-with-agents.html</link>
      <description>Alex Pretti, killed by ICE agents on Jan. 24, had a violent altercation with federal officers just a week earlier, resulting in a broken rib. Medical records confirm his injury, complicating activist claims that he was a peaceful protester. Pretti allegedly o…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Naturalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 days before he was shot and killed by ICE, Alex Pretti kicked out a vehicle taillight and got wrestled to the ground</title>
      <link>https://fortune.com/2026/01/29/alex-pretty-new-videos-show-previous-conflict-with-ice/</link>
      <description>At no point in the newly uncovered videos does Pretti reach for his gun and it is unclear whether the federal agents saw it.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fortune</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MORNING GLORY: Minnesota tragedies aren't instant replay calls you make from the couch</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/opinion/morning-glory-minnesota-tragedies-arent-instant-replay-calls-make-couch</link>
      <description>America's criminal justice system requires patience and complete evidence, not instant replay mentality, argues Fox News contributor Hugh Hewitt following Minnesota police shootings.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s A Reason Many Police Dept’s Ban Shooting At Moving Vehicles: It Saves Lives Without Putting Officers In Greater Danger</title>
      <link>https://www.techdirt.com/2026/01/28/theres-a-reason-many-police-depts-ban-shooting-at-moving-vehicles-it-saves-lives-without-putting-officers-in-greater-danger/</link>
      <description>Minneapolis is once again the focus of debates about violence involving law enforcement after an Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killed Renee Nicole Good, a 37-year-old mother, in her car. The incident quickly prompted dueling narratives.…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 23:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Techdirt</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Officer-involved shooting reported at Cobb County police headquarters</title>
      <link>https://www.wsbtv.com/news/local/cobb-county/officer-involved-shooting-reported-cobb-county-police-headquarters/F6BSWV56Y5GCPKNMVCFOLCUHR4/</link>
      <description>Police are investigating a shooting involving an officer at the Cobb County Police Department headquarters.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 22:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WSB Atlanta</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knife-wielding nut allegedly asked Christian his religion – then stabbed him and dog before police shot him</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/knife-wielding-nut-allegedly-asked-christian-his-religion-then-stabbed-him-dog-before-police-shot-him</link>
      <description>Armed Washington suspect died after police shooting following alleged stabbing attack on man and dog that occurred after asking victim about Christian faith in Parkland on Sunday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A second U.S. citizen was killed by federal forces in Minneapolis. Here's what we know</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/a-second-u-s-citizen-was-killed-by-federal-forces-in-minneapolis-heres-what-we-know</link>
      <description>The fatal shooting of Alex Pretti, the second U.S. citizen to be killed by federal forces in Minnesota this month, has intensified the public outrage over tactics used by immigration agents in the state and united unlikely bedfellows in calling for a full inv…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>PBS</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
