<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 06:49:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Judge grants restraining order against DHS after Border Patrol kills Alex Pretti in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-chat/4363995/posts</link>
      <description>Federal agents shot and killed a 37-year-old man in Minneapolis on Saturday morning, less than three weeks after an ICE agent fatally shot Renee Good and amid an ongoing surge in immigration enforcement action across the city. U.S. District Court Judge Eric T…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 05:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump was surging after the Venezuela raid—then came Jerome Powell, Greenland and Minnesota. Now it feels like a ‘historic hinge moment’</title>
      <link>https://fortune.com/2026/01/25/trump-resistance-jerome-powell-federal-reserve-greenland-minnesota/</link>
      <description>&quot;It's not acceptable for American citizens to be killed by federal agents for exercising their God-given and constitutional rights to protest their government.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 01:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fortune</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breanna Stewart holds up 'Abolish ICE' sign ahead of Unrivaled game</title>
      <link>https://www.cbssports.com/wnba/news/breanna-stewart-holds-up-abolish-ice-sign/</link>
      <description>Stewart's statement comes in the wake of the deaths of two people who were fatally shot by federal immigration officers in Minneapolis</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS Sports</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Pretti’s Family Slams Trump’s ‘Sickening Lies,’ Gov. Walz Mobilizes National Guard As Democrats Threaten DHS Funding Block</title>
      <link>https://bossip.com/4313443/alex-pretti-family-donald-trump-sickening-lies-gov-walz-national-guard/</link>
      <description>Alex Pretti’s family is speaking out after the 37-year-old Minneapolis resident was shot and killed by federal immigration agents, accusing President Donald Trump and his administration of spreading “sickening lies” about what happened. The Guardian reports t…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Bossip</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis shooting: NRA stress right to carry guns after fatal shooting of Alex Pretti by federal agents</title>
      <link>https://indianexpress.com/article/world/minneapolis-shooting-nra-stress-right-to-carry-guns-after-fatal-shooting-of-alex-pretti-by-federal-agents-10494787/</link>
      <description>The NRA criticised comments made by a senior federal prosecutor, saying it was “dangerous and wrong” to suggest that people who legally carry guns risk being shot by police.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:33:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Indian Express</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota CEOs Seek De-Escalation After Border Police Shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.livemint.com/companies/minnesota-ceos-seek-de-escalation-after-border-police-shooting-11769381712742.html</link>
      <description>More than 60 chief executive officers of Minnesota-based companies called for an immediate “de-escalation of tensions” between state, local and federal authorities as the state reels from another fatal shooting of an American by immigration agents.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 22:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Livemint</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump demands Democrats 'cooperate' with ICE in dark screed to deport 'illegal criminals'</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/trump-2675023640/</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump issued a dark, winding screed on Sunday evening following the latest incident where an immigration agent shot and killed a U.S. citizen. On Saturday, immigration agents shot and killed 37-year-old ICU nurse Alex Pretti at a protest agai…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 22:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Republican calls are growing for a deeper investigation into the fatal Minneapolis shooting</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/Politics/wireStory/republican-calls-growing-deeper-investigation-fatal-minneapolis-shooting-129548735</link>
      <description>A growing number of Republicans are pressing for a deeper investigation into federal immigration tactics after a U.S. Border Patrol agent fatally shot a man in Minneapolis</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 22:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Reveals ICU Nurse Killed By Feds Was Holding Phone, Not a Gun</title>
      <link>https://screenrant.com/reveals-icu-nurse-killed-by-feds-was-holding-phone-not-a-gun/</link>
      <description>Recently released video contradicts authorities' claims, showing Alex Pretti holding a phone when shot by federal agents in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 22:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Screen Rant</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some in GOP call for probe after Minnesota shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.bostonherald.com/2026/01/25/some-in-gop-call-for-probe-after-minnesota-shooting/</link>
      <description>A growing number of Republicans are pressing for a deeper investigation into federal immigration tactics in Minnesota after a U.S. Border Patrol agent fatally shot a man in Minneapolis, a sign that the accounting of events by President Donald Trump's administ…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 22:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Boston Herald</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Pretti's 'life was just starting,' mentor says</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/alex-prettis-life-starting-mentor/story?id=129548473</link>
      <description>Alex Pretti, an ICU nurse, was shot and killed by federal agents in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 21:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Left Doesn’t Want You to Know This About Alex Pretti, the Man the Border Patrol Shot</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4363928/posts</link>
      <description>When Renee Good drove her car into an ICE agent earlier this month, the left tried to gaslight us into believing she was just some innocent bystander who was just at the wrong place, that she’d just dropped her son off at school and wasn’t supposed to be ther…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 21:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Republican calls growing for deeper investigation into fatal Minneapolis shooting</title>
      <link>https://japantoday.com/category/world/some-republicans-express-concern-over-the-tactics-used-in-minnesota-and-urge-shooting-investigation</link>
      <description>A growing number of Republicans are pressing for a deeper investigation into federal immigration tactics in Minnesota after a U.S. Border Patrol agent fatally shot a man in Minneapolis, a sign that the accounting of events by President Donald Trump's administ…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 21:28:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Japan Today</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Target CEO Joins Minnesota Businesses Urging ‘Deescalation’ After Latest Shooting In Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/zacharyfolk/2026/01/25/target-ceo-joins-minnesota-businesses-urging-deescalation-after-latest-shooting-in-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>At least two U.S. citizens have been shot and killed by federal agents since a major operation began in Minnesota.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 21:08:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Forbes</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Conservatives Veer Off Party Line After DHS Agents Kill Another US Citizen</title>
      <link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2026/01/some-conservatives-veer-off-party-line-after-dhs-agents-kill-another-us-citizen/</link>
      <description>It didn’t take long for the Trump administration to blame 37-year-old Alex Pretti for his own death after a federal immigration agent shot and killed him on Saturday in Minneapolis.  Pretti, an intensive-care unit nurse at a Veterans Affairs hospital, is the …</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 21:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mother Jones</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oklahoma governor says situation in Minneapolis 'a real tragedy'</title>
      <link>https://www.koco.com/article/oklahoma-gov-kevin-stitt-raises-concerns-federal-tactics-minneapolis-ice-minnesota/70130759</link>
      <description>Oklahoma Gov. Kevin Stitt weighed in on the growing tensions in Minneapolis after a man was fatally shot by federal immigration officials Saturday, drawing protests to the streets.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 20:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>KOCO Oklahoma City</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>America's largest labor movement calls for ICE to leave Minnesota before 'anyone else is hurt or killed'</title>
      <link>https://www.businessinsider.com/afl-cio-ice-shooting-alex-pretti-minneapolis-border-patrol-immigration-2026-1</link>
      <description>A federal immigration agent shot and killed 37-year-old Alex Pretti, a US citizen, in Minneapolis on Saturday. He was an ICU nurse at a VA hospital.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 20:19:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Business Insider</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latest shooting in Minnesota enforcement surge fuels more calls for immigration agents to leave (Associated Press)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260125/p56</link>
      <description>Associated Press:
Latest shooting in Minnesota enforcement surge fuels more calls for immigration agents to leave  —  Local leaders and Democrats across the country demanded federal immigration officers leave Minnesota after a Border Patrol agent fatally shot…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 20:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Pretti: Analysing Footage of Minneapolis CBP Shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2026/01/25/alex-pretti-analysing-footage-of-minneapolis-cbp-shooting/</link>
      <description>To stay up to date on our latest investigations, join Bellingcat’s WhatsApp channel here On January 24, Alex Pretti, a 37-year-old intensive care unit nurse at the Minneapolis Veterans Affairs Health Care System, was shot and killed by federal agents on Nicol…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Bellingcat.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Republicans call for investigation after fatal shooting in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.wcvb.com/article/some-republicans-investigation-fatal-shooting-minneapolis/70130455</link>
      <description>A handful of Republicans called for a deeper investigation into federal immigration tactics after a U.S. Border Patrol agent fatally shot a man in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WCVB Boston</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protesters demand immigration agents leave Minneapolis after man killed during crackdown</title>
      <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/protesters-demand-immigration-agents-leave-minneapolis-9.7060134</link>
      <description>Democrats demanded that federal immigration officers leave Minnesota after a U.S. Border Patrol agent fatally shot a man in Minneapolis on Saturday, drawing hundreds of protesters onto the frigid streets and increasing tensions in a city already shaken by ano…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charles Barkley reacts to deadly Minnesota shootings: 'Somebody's gotta step up and be adults'</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/sports/charles-barkley-reacts-deadly-minnesota-shootings-somebodys-gotta-step-up-adults</link>
      <description>Former NBA star Charles Barkley said on Saturday that &quot;somebody's gotta step up and be adults&quot; in reaction to the second federal officer-involved shooting this month in Minnesota.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Sickening lies’: Parents of man killed by federal agent in Minneapolis go nuclear on Trump’s ‘murdering thugs’</title>
      <link>https://www.wnd.com/2026/01/sickening-lies-parents-man-killed-federal-agent-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>'I do not throw around the hero term lightly. However his last thought and act was to protect a woman'</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Wnd.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Pretti’s Sig handgun has history of accidentally firing — offering possible clue to why Border agent shot him</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/01/25/us-news/alex-prettis-sig-p320-may-have-gone-off-accidentally-experts-suggest/</link>
      <description>The P320 model is widely carried by armed civilians and US law enforcement, including ICE — but has been the subject of more than 100 allegations that it has a defect that allows it to fire &quot;uncommanded.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:36:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Pretti, Man Killed by Federal Agents Whom the White House Labeled a Domestic Terrorist, Was ICU Nurse for Veterans</title>
      <link>https://www.jezebel.com/alex-pretti-man-killed-by-masked-federal-agents-whom-the-white-house-labeled-a-domestic-terrorist-was-icu-nurse-for-veterans</link>
      <description>“The sickening lies told about our son by the administration are reprehensible and disgusting,&quot; Pretti's family said in a statement.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:53:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Jezebel</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Third fatal officer-involved shooting in Minneapolis within a month exposes enforcement flaws, may heighten federal-state tension: expert</title>
      <link>https://www.globalsecurity.org/security/library/news/2026/01/sec-260125-globaltimes01.htm</link>
      <description>Authorities confirmed US local time Saturday that the man shot dead by US federal agents earlier in the morning in Minneapolis, Minnesota was a US citizen, marking a third shooting involving federal law enforcement officers in the city this month, the Xinhua …</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 09:46:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Globalsecurity.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOP Sen. Cassidy breaks with Trump over deadly shooting by Border Patrol agent in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/gop-sen-cassidy-breaks-trump-over-deadly-shooting-border-patrol-agent-minneapolis</link>
      <description>Republican Sen. Bill Cassidy calls for full investigation after a Border Patrol agent shot and killed a man in Minneapolis during a DHS operation on Saturday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 08:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man shot and killed by federal officers in Minnesota was an ICU nurse, his parents say</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/man-shot-and-killed-by-federal-officers-in-minnesota-was-an-icu-nurse-his-parents-say</link>
      <description>The man who was shot and killed by a federal officer during an immigration operation has been identified as 37-year-old Alex Pretti, an intensive care unit nurse.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>PBS</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pritzker urges 'unified response' from Democrat, Republican governors after Border Patrol shoots armed man</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/pritzker-urges-unified-response-democrat-republican-governors-border-patrol-shoots-armed-man</link>
      <description>Illinois Gov. JB Pritzker and New York Gov. Kathy Hochul slammed thee Trump administration after Border Patrol shot an armed man in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 19:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man injured in southern Colorado police chase, shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.denverpost.com/2026/01/22/walsenburg-police-chase-shooting/</link>
      <description>A Walsenburg police officer shot at a fleeing domestic violence suspect on Wednesday, according to the Colorado Bureau of Investigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Denver Post</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
