<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 07:02:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Vigils held in Greater Cincinnati for man shot, killed by federal agents in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.wlwt.com/article/vigils-cincinnati-federal-agents-minneapolis-alex-pretti/70179585</link>
      <description>Vigils were held Wednesday night around Greater Cincinnati for Alex Pretti, the man who was shot and killed by federal agents in Minneapolis last Saturday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 03:14:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WLWT Cincinnati</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No charges laid in fatal Victoria police shooting in 2021</title>
      <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/no-charges-fatal-victoria-police-officer-shooting-9.7065864</link>
      <description>There will be no charges laid against a Victoria Police Department officer who shot and killed a man in September 2021, according to the B.C. Prosecution Service.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 02:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s A Reason Many Police Dept’s Ban Shooting At Moving Vehicles: It Saves Lives Without Putting Officers In Greater Danger</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180681172</link>
      <description>Minneapolis is once again the focus of debates about violence involving law enforcement after an Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killedRenee Nicole Good, a 37-year-old mother, in her car. The incident quickly prompted dueling narratives. …</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 23:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Officer-involved shooting reported at Cobb County police headquarters</title>
      <link>https://www.wsbtv.com/news/local/cobb-county/officer-involved-shooting-reported-cobb-county-police-headquarters/F6BSWV56Y5GCPKNMVCFOLCUHR4/</link>
      <description>Police are investigating a shooting involving an officer at the Cobb County Police Department headquarters.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 22:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WSB Atlanta</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Pretti 'had a way of lighting up every room he walked into'</title>
      <link>https://www.advocate.com/politics/national/alex-pretti-remembered</link>
      <description>Alex Jeffrey Pretti, 37, was an ICU nurse at the Minneapolis Veterans Affairs hospital before he was shot and killed by federal agents Saturday morning on Nicollet Avenue. Family and friends, as well as former coworkers and teachers, described him as generous…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 21:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Advocate.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Miller Suggests Federal Agents May Have Diverted From ‘Protocol’ Before Pretti Shooting</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4364426/posts</link>
      <description>The comments by Mr. Miller, the influential White House deputy chief of staff, came after days of blaming Alex Pretti, who was fatally shot by federal agents. Stephen Miller, a top aide to President Trump, has suggested that federal agents “may not have been …</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 20:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tom Morello Will Protest Fascism With ‘Solidarity &amp; Resistance’ Benefit Concert in Minnesota</title>
      <link>http://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-news/tom-morello-minnesota-benefit-show-renee-good-alex-pretti-1235506282/</link>
      <description>Tom Morello, Rise Against, Al Di Meola, Ike Reilly, and more guests will perform on Jan. 30 with proceeds benefiting the families of Renee Good and Alex Pretti, who were killed by ICE agents</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Rolling Stone</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Officer-involved shooting reported in Allegheny County</title>
      <link>https://www.wpxi.com/news/local/officer-involved-shooting-reported-allegheny-county/KSJH2H347FCYZFGCDUCOJTRXGU/</link>
      <description>The Allegheny County Police Department says the shooting happened in the 1100 block of Penn Center Boulevard in Wilkins Township.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WPXI Pittsburgh</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two federal officers fired guns in Alex Pretti shooting, initial DHS report says</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/two-federal-officers-fired-guns-alex-pretti-shooting-dhs-report-rcna256274</link>
      <description>Two federal officers fired their guns during Alex Pretti’s fatal shooting, according to an initial review by the Department of Homeland Security that was obtained by NBC News.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>NBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Truly Scary Part of Minneapolis Protests</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4364185/posts</link>
      <description>The protesting in Minneapolis is not a great thing for anyone, contrary to what some might think. Alex Pretti's death was just the latest incident where someone who was involved ended up being killed by federal agents, though it's the less clear-cut case of a…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:34:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knife-wielding nut allegedly asked Christian his religion – then stabbed him and dog before police shot him</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/knife-wielding-nut-allegedly-asked-christian-his-religion-then-stabbed-him-dog-before-police-shot-him</link>
      <description>Armed Washington suspect died after police shooting following alleged stabbing attack on man and dog that occurred after asking victim about Christian faith in Parkland on Sunday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A second U.S. citizen was killed by federal forces in Minneapolis. Here's what we know</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/a-second-u-s-citizen-was-killed-by-federal-forces-in-minneapolis-heres-what-we-know</link>
      <description>The fatal shooting of Alex Pretti, the second U.S. citizen to be killed by federal forces in Minnesota this month, has intensified the public outrage over tactics used by immigration agents in the state and united unlikely bedfellows in calling for a full inv…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>PBS</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Sickening lies’: Parents of man killed by federal agent in Minneapolis go nuclear on Trump’s ‘murdering thugs’</title>
      <link>https://www.wnd.com/2026/01/sickening-lies-parents-man-killed-federal-agent-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>'I do not throw around the hero term lightly. However his last thought and act was to protect a woman'</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Wnd.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOP Sen. Cassidy breaks with Trump over deadly shooting by Border Patrol agent in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/gop-sen-cassidy-breaks-trump-over-deadly-shooting-border-patrol-agent-minneapolis</link>
      <description>Republican Sen. Bill Cassidy calls for full investigation after a Border Patrol agent shot and killed a man in Minneapolis during a DHS operation on Saturday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 08:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pritzker urges 'unified response' from Democrat, Republican governors after Border Patrol shoots armed man</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/pritzker-urges-unified-response-democrat-republican-governors-border-patrol-shoots-armed-man</link>
      <description>Illinois Gov. JB Pritzker and New York Gov. Kathy Hochul slammed thee Trump administration after Border Patrol shot an armed man in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 19:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
