<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 06:47:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Fury in Minneapolis after ICE agent shoots woman (37) dead in car during immigration raids</title>
      <link>https://www.independent.ie/world-news/north-america/fury-in-minneapolis-after-ice-agent-shoots-woman-37-dead-in-car-during-immigration-raids/a2139122125.html</link>
      <description>An Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) officer shot and killed a woman on Wednesday during the Trump administration’s latest immigration crackdown on a major American city.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Independent.ie</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protests after ICE agent shoots woman (37) dead in car in immigration crackdown</title>
      <link>https://www.independent.ie/world-news/north-america/protests-after-ice-agent-shoots-woman-37-dead-in-car-in-immigration-crackdown/a2139122125.html</link>
      <description>An Immigration and Customs Enforcement (Ice) officer shot and killed a female motorist on Wednesday during the Trump administration’s latest immigration crackdown on a major American city.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Independent.ie</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live updates: Parents identify woman fatally shot by ICE officer in Minneapolis - The Washington Post</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180546161</link>
      <description>Live updates: Parents identify woman fatally shot by ICE officer in MinneapolisThe Washington Post US immigration agent fatally shoots woman in MinneapolisBBC An ICE shooting was filmed from multiple angles. No-one agrees on what happenedAustralian Broadcasti…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video appears to show hysterical, blood-covered wife of Renee Nicole Good, woman killed by ICE, crying out ‘it’s my fault’</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4360968/posts</link>
      <description>A blood-covered woman who identified herself as the wife of Renee Nicole Good hysterically blamed herself for her partner’s killing at the hands of ICE agents, gut-wrenching footage shows. The woman was filmed distraught and sobbing just steps from Good’s wre…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE agent shoots Minneapolis woman, sparking outrage and political firestorm</title>
      <link>https://www.naturalnews.com/2026-01-08-ice-agent-shoots-minneapolis-woman-renee-good.html</link>
      <description>An ICE agent fatally shot a civilian in Minneapolis during an operation, leading to protests and conflicting official accounts. The victim was 37-year-old Renee Good. The Department of Homeland Security claimed Good attempted to use her car as a weapon agains…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Naturalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US immigration officer fatally shoots woman, sparking protests</title>
      <link>https://www.hurriyetdailynews.com/us-immigration-officer-fatally-shoots-woman-sparking-protests-217612</link>
      <description>A U.S. immigration officer shot and killed an American woman on the streets of Minneapolis Wednesday, leading to huge protests and outrage from local leaders who rejected White House claims she was a domestic terrorist.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Hurriyet Daily News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photos released of Renee Nicole Good, the US citizen killed by ICE in Minnesota</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/photos-released-renee-nicole-good-us-citizen-killed-ice-minnesota</link>
      <description>Pictures were released of Renee Nicole Good, the U.S. citizen killed by an ICE agent in Minneapolis during the Trump administration's migrant sweep.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:51:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woman killed by ICE agent in Minneapolis was a mother of 3, poet and new to the city</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/woman-killed-ice-agent-minneapolis-mother-3-poet-129008055</link>
      <description>The woman shot and killed by a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer in Minneapolis was a U.S. citizen and mother of a 6-year-old</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fury in Minneapolis as ICE agent shoots woman (37) dead in car</title>
      <link>https://www.independent.ie/world-news/north-america/fury-in-minneapolis-as-ice-agent-shoots-woman-37-dead-in-car/a2139122125.html</link>
      <description>A US immigration agent shot and killed a 37-year-old woman in her car in Minneapolis yesterday amid an immigration enforcement surge, the latest violent incident during president Donald Trump’s nationwide crackdown on migrants.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 05:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Independent.ie</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE Officer Involved In Minneapolis Shooting (Ashley Brasfield/The Daily Caller)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260107/p171</link>
      <description>Ashley Brasfield / The Daily Caller:
ICE Officer Involved In Minneapolis Shooting  —  A U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) agent shot and killed a woman Wednesday after she attempted run over law enforcement officials with her vehicle in Minneapol…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 04:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Public Schools cancels school Jan. 8 and Jan. 9 after ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.fox9.com/news/minneapolis-public-schools-cancels-school-jan-8-jan-9-after-ice-shooting</link>
      <description>Minneapolis Public Schools announced classes will be canceled on Thursday, Jan. 8, and Friday, Jan. 9, with no e-learning being offered. This comes after an ICE agent fatally shot a woman during an enforcement operation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 03:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>FOX 9</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who was Renee Nicole Good? What we know about the woman killed by ICE</title>
      <link>https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2026/01/07/renee-nicole-good-minneapolis-ice-shooting/88073771007/</link>
      <description>By now millions of people have witnessed the moment that 37-year-old Renee Nicole Good was shot by an ICE agent in Minneapolis. Who was she?</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 03:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>USA Today</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woman fatally shot by ICE agent was out 'caring for her neighbors,' Minneapolis officials say</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/renee-nicole-good-minneapolis-ice-shooting-victim-caring-neighbor-rcna252901</link>
      <description>A joint statement from the Minneapolis City Council described the woman fatally shot by an ICE agent as a resident who was out “caring for her neighbors” when she was killed.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 02:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>NBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kristi Noem Faces Impeachment Threat After Deadly Minnesota Shooting</title>
      <link>https://biztoc.com/x/4b1803cb6795160b</link>
      <description>A congresswoman said she plans to file articles of impeachment against Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem after an Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) agent shot and killed a woman in Minneapolis, Minnesota on Wednesday, sparking fury from proteste…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 02:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Biztoc.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dem Senate candidate mocked after claim about dismantling ICE goes viral: 'Unmask these thugs'</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/dem-senate-candidate-mocked-after-claim-about-dismantling-ice-goes-viral-unmask-thugs</link>
      <description>Maine Senate hopeful Graham Platner, a Democrat, said 'dismantling ICE' was a 'moderate' position after an ICE agent shot and killed a Minneapolis woman.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 02:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Councilmember: ICE Agents 'Could Have Just Moved Out [of] the Way' of Car</title>
      <link>https://www.breitbart.com/clips/2026/01/07/minneapolis-councilmember-ice-agents-could-have-just-moved-out-of-the-way-of-car/</link>
      <description>On Wednesday’s broadcast of CNN’s “The Lead,” Minneapolis City Councilmember Jason Chavez argued that the federal government is “making up fantasies” when it says an ICE officer shot a woman in Minneapolis in self-defense earlier on Wednesday and stated that
…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Breitbart News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota's elected leaders react to woman's fatal shooting by ICE agents</title>
      <link>https://www.kare11.com/article/news/politics/minnesotas-elected-leaders-react-to-womans-fatal-shooting-by-ice-agents/89-064658fd-e477-45fb-94b5-04c1be7854aa</link>
      <description>The Department of Homeland Security said the woman attempted to ram her car into ICE agents before an agent shot her, but multiple leaders dispute the claim.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>KARE11.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE agent behind fatal Minnesota shooting acted in ‘self-defense’ – Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.rt.com/news/630715-trump-defends-ice-minnesota/</link>
      <description>US President Donald Trump has defended law enforcement after an ICE officer fatally shot a woman in Minnesota Read Full Article at RT.com</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:18:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>RT</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE’s violence is no accident</title>
      <link>https://biztoc.com/x/cec2d54c65d61ec3</link>
      <description>In a MS NOW column last May, I wrote that ICE actions were becoming so reckless that a fatal encounter was all but inevitable. On Wednesday, my prediction sadly came true, as an agent shot a woman at close range in Minneapolis during an immigration enforcemen…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 01:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Biztoc.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota governor says he is preparing National Guard amid furor over fatal ICE shooting - abcnews.go.com</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180545199</link>
      <description>Minnesota governor says he is preparing National Guard amid furor over fatal ICE shootingabcnews.go.com Hundreds gather to mourn Renee Good, Minneapolis woman shot and killed by ICE agentMPR News ICE agent shoots, kills woman in Minneapolis5 EYEWITNESS NEWS I…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:53:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What we know about the deadly Minneapolis ICE shooting as protests grow</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/video/breaking-down-deadly-ice-shooting-situation-aftermath-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>Warning: video may be disturbing to some viewers. An ICE agent shot and killed a woman, now identified as 37-year-old Renee Good, Wednesday morning in Minneapolis. CBS News' Nicole Sganga and Anna Schecter report.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woman Killed by ICE Identified as Protesters Take to Streets in Minneapolis and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://www.commondreams.org/news/ice-shooter</link>
      <description>Protests broke out in Minnesota and beyond on Wednesday after a US Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent fatally shot a Minneapolis woman identified by her mother as Renee Nicole Good.Good's mother, Donna Ganger, told the Minnesota Star Tribune that the f…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Common Dreams</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US immigration agent fatally shoots woman in Minneapolis, mayor disputes government claim of self-defence</title>
      <link>https://www.channelnewsasia.com/world/us-immigration-agent-fatally-shoots-woman-minneapolis-trump-ice-5837701</link>
      <description>MINNEAPOLIS: A United States immigration agent shot and killed a 37-year-old woman in her car in Minneapolis on Wednesday (Jan 7) amid an immigration enforcement surge, according to local and federal officials, the latest violent incident during President Don…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CNA</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE officer kills a Minneapolis driver in a deadly start to Trump’s latest immigration operation - AP News</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180545135</link>
      <description>ICE officer kills a Minneapolis driver in a deadly start to Trump’s latest immigration operationAP News ICE agent shoots, kills woman in Minneapolis5 EYEWITNESS NEWS ‘She was an amazing human being’: Mother identifies woman shot, killed by ICE agentStar Tribu…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis driver Renee Nicole Good, fatally shot by ICE agent, had been ‘stalking and impeding’ law enforcement: Noem</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/01/07/us-news/minneapolis-driver-fatally-shot-by-ice-agent-had-been-stalking-and-impeding-law-enforcement-noem/</link>
      <description>“Any loss of life is a tragedy,” Noem said of the shooting death of Renee Nicole Good, before explaining what led up to the shooting.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Gonna upset a lot of people': CNN in awe as Noem 'inflames' Minnesotans with new remarks</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/cnn-2674858732/</link>
      <description>CNN anchor Jake Tapper was in awe at Department of Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem's comments following a deadly shooting in Minneapolis on Wednesday involving an Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent. An ICE agent fatally shot a 37-year-old woman…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State, city leaders clash with feds after deadly ICE Shooting in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://biztoc.com/x/1ff2aea7863f0b32</link>
      <description>State and local officials in Minneapolis are outraged after an immigration and customs enforcement agent fatally shot a woman there. Federal officials accused that woman of trying to run over officers with a vehicle, claiming the shooting was in self-defense.…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Biztoc.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Woman killed by ICE officer in Minneapolis was from Colorado, report says</title>
      <link>https://www.denverpost.com/2026/01/07/minneapolis-ice-shooting-renee-good-colorado/</link>
      <description>The driver shot and killed by a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer in Minneapolis on Wednesday was a 37-year-old woman who moved to the area from Colorado, according to the Minnesota Star Tribune.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 23:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Denver Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walz Puts National Guard—and Trump—On Notice as Protests Erupt Over ICE 'Murder' in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.commondreams.org/news/walz-minnesota-ice</link>
      <description>Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz on Wednesday put his state's National Guard on standby—and the Trump administration on notice—after a federal immigration officer fatally shot a woman in Minneapolis.Walz, a Democrat who was former Vice President Kamala Harris' running…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 23:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Common Dreams</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly Minneapolis Encounter Is the 9th ICE Shooting Since September (New York Times)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260107/p132</link>
      <description>New York Times:
Deadly Minneapolis Encounter Is the 9th ICE Shooting Since September  —  All those targeted in the shootings were fired on while in their vehicles.  —  An ICE agent shot and killed a woman in Minneapolis on Wednesday, the latest in a series of…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 23:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Pride Flag/Pronouns, every single time’: Woman killed by ICE agent identified</title>
      <link>https://www.wnd.com/2026/01/pride-flag-pronouns-every-single-time-woman-killed/</link>
      <description>Another gal at scene shouts: ''That's my wife, I don't know what to do'</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 23:25:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Wnd.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis' police chief gives his perspective of the deadly ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.npr.org/2026/01/07/nx-s1-5670415/minneapolis-police-chief-gives-his-perspective-of-the-deadly-ice-shooting</link>
      <description>NPR's Mary Louise Kelly talks with Brian O'Hara, the police chief in Minneapolis, about the shooting in which an ICE agent killed a 37-year-old woman.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 23:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>NPR</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protester burns American flag in Minneapolis after ICE agent shoots, kills woman</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/01/07/us-news/protester-burns-american-flag-in-minneapolis-after-deadly-ice-shooting/</link>
      <description>Video posted on X shows one man standing in a circle of protestors with the US flag, then setting it on fire until it falls to the ground in flames.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 23:01:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yes, Minneapolis Can Prosecute the ICE Shooter</title>
      <link>https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2026/01/is-minneapolis-ice-shooter-immune-state-prosecution-supreme-court.html</link>
      <description>Shortly after an ICE officer shot and killed a woman in Minneapolis, city leaders began looking into whether the officer had violated state criminal law.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slate Magazine</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis City Council member calls for arrest and firing of ICE agent who shot and killed woman</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/video/minneapolis-city-council-member-calls-arrest-firing-ice-agent-shot-killed-woman/</link>
      <description>A federal immigration officer shot and killed a motorist in Minneapolis on Wednesday. Jason Chavez, a city council member who represents the area where the shooting took place, joins with his reaction. Then, CBS News' Anna Schecter joins with more on the futu…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An ICE Agent Shot and Killed a Woman in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>http://www.thecut.com/article/minneapolis-ice-shooting-agent-kills-woman-during-operation.html</link>
      <description>On Wednesday, the Department of Homeland Security said an ICE officer fatally shot a woman in Minneapolis during what the agency calls its ‘largest immigration operation ever.’</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Cut</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tim Walz Bluntly Tells Trump and Kristi Noem ‘You Have Done Enough’ in Heated Presser</title>
      <link>https://www.mediaite.com/politics/tim-walz-bluntly-tells-trump-and-kristi-noem-you-have-done-enough-in-heated-presser/</link>
      <description>Tim Walz made a direct plea to President Trump and Kristi Noem to not send more federal law officers to his state after an ICE agent shot and killed a woman.
The post Tim Walz Bluntly Tells Trump and Kristi Noem ‘You Have Done Enough’ in Heated Presser first …</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mediaite</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jake Tapper tears into Kristi Noem's 'abjectly false' claim: 'Clear to anyone with eyes'</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/kristi-noem-2674858488/</link>
      <description>CNN anchor Jake Tapper did not hold back when he fact-checked Department of Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem for putting out false information about a lethal shooting where an Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent killed a U.S. citizen on Wednesday…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Minnesota prosecute the federal immigration officer who just killed a woman?</title>
      <link>https://www.vox.com/politics/474434/supreme-court-ice-killer-minneapolis-minnesota-prosecution</link>
      <description>A federal officer shot and killed a woman in Minneapolis on Wednesday, shortly after the Trump administration deployed thousands of immigration agents to the city. Although the full circumstances of the killing remain unclear, video of the shooting shows an o…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:17:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Vox</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Woman Shot By ICE in the Head, Witness Says: 'Blood All Over'</title>
      <link>https://biztoc.com/x/a7d58a1f6acce840</link>
      <description>An eyewitness to the fatal shooting of a woman in Minneapolis by a federal agent on Wednesday told Newsweek that her blood was visible on the snowy ground.
Speaking in the hours after the incident in a residential neighborhood, the witness described the momen…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 22:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Biztoc.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renee Nicole Good identified by mother as woman fatally shot by ICE agent in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/01/07/us-news/woman-fatally-shot-by-ice-agent-identified/</link>
      <description>The woman fatally gunned down by ICE agents in Minneapolis was identified as beloved 37-year-old Renee Nicole Good, a beloved and “compassionate” resident of the Twin Cities, her mother said. Good was publicly identified by her mother hours after she was gunn…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WATCH: Minneapolis mayor tells ICE to leave after fatal shooting</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/video/minneapolis-mayor-tells-ice-leave-after-fatal-shooting-128995792</link>
      <description>Mayor Jacob Frey said he’s “demanding ICE to leave the city immediately” after an ICE agent fatally shot a woman in a vehicle during operations in Minneapolis on Wednesday, according to DHS.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walz gives order to prepare National Guard after ICE officer fatally shoots woman in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/minnesota/news/walz-natinal-guard-ice-officer-fatal-shooting-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz says the state &quot;doesn't need any further help from the federal government&quot; after federal officials reported a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer fatally shot a woman Wednesday morning​ in south Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chilling Footage Shows Ice Agent Shoots Woman Who Allegedly Tries to Ram Officers With Car</title>
      <link>https://www.ibtimes.com/chilling-footage-shows-ice-agent-shoots-woman-who-allegedly-tries-ram-officers-car-3794646</link>
      <description>A fatal shooting by an ICE agent in Minneapolis has ignited protests and official disputes over the use of force, with video and eyewitness accounts challenging federal claims.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:39:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>International Business Times</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE officer kills a Minneapolis driver as Trump's latest immigration operation begins</title>
      <link>https://japantoday.com/category/world/shooting-is-reported-in-minneapolis-where-the-feds-are-conducting-an-immigration-crackdown</link>
      <description>An Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killed a Minneapolis driver on Wednesday during the Trump administration's latest immigration crackdown on a major American city — a shooting that federal officials said was an act of self-defense but th…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Japan Today</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Deadly Shooting in Minnesota (David A. Graham/The Atlantic)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260107/p104</link>
      <description>David A. Graham / The Atlantic:
A Deadly Shooting in Minnesota  —  A federal immigration agent's killing of a woman driving an SUV fits into a tragic pattern.  —  When a federal immigration agent shot and killed a woman in Minneapolis today, the details were …</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Get out of Minneapolis': Mayor's fury after ICE agent shoots and kills woman</title>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/us-immigration-agent-fatally-shoots-womanin-minneapolis/106208464</link>
      <description>The mayor of Minneapolis says the Trump administration's claim that the incident was self-defence is not true and told Immigration and Customs Enforcement to get out of the city.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News (AU)</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Latest: ICE officer shoots and kills a woman during Minneapolis immigration crackdown</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/latest-ice-officer-shoots-kills-woman-minneapolis-immigration-128994317</link>
      <description>An Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killed a Minneapolis motorist during the Trump administration’s latest immigration crackdown in a major U.S. city — a shooting that federal officials claimed was an act of self-defense but that th...</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Walz: There Will Be Full Investigation of ICE Shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.newser.com/story/381569/walz-there-will-be-full-investigation-of-ice-shooting.html</link>
      <description>An Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killed a Minneapolis motorist on Wednesday during the Trump administration's latest illegal immigration crackdown on a major American city—a shooting that federal officials claimed was an act of self-def…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 21:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Newser</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Get the F--- Out!' — Kristi Noem and ICE Destroyed By Minneapolis Mayor After Agent Fatally Shoots Woman</title>
      <link>https://radaronline.com/p/minneapolis-mayor-jacob-frey-kristi-noem-ice-shooting/</link>
      <description>A 37-year-old woman was shot and killed by ICE agents as she was in her car seemingly attempting to drive away.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 20:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Radaronline.com</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
