<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 06:47:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Mark Ruffalo, Jean Smart and Natasha Lyonne Protest ICE at Golden Globes: ‘I’m Here Speaking as a Citizen’</title>
      <link>https://www.thewrap.com/industry-news/awards/golden-globes-celebrities-protest-ice-pins-jean-smart-mark-ruffalo/</link>
      <description>Several A-listers wore pins honoring the memories of Renee Macklin Good and Keith Porter, who were killed by ICE
The post Mark Ruffalo, Jean Smart and Natasha Lyonne Protest ICE at Golden Globes: ‘I’m Here Speaking as a Citizen’ appeared first on TheWrap.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 03:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>TheWrap</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Constitutional crisis in a nutshell': Lawyer calls out JD Vance's latest 'lie'</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/jd-vance-2674873534/</link>
      <description>A prominent voting rights lawyer slammed Vice President JD Vance on Sunday for his latest &quot;lie&quot; about the lethal shooting in Minneapolis. Last week, an Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killed 37-year-old Renee Good as she was in her car tr…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Western Pennsylvania protesters join nationwide movement against ICE after agent shoots, kills woman</title>
      <link>https://www.wpxi.com/news/local/western-pennsylvania-protesters-join-nationwide-movement-against-ice-after-agent-shoots-kills-woman/RL7CZG7KRRANZN4UJJWCQBRHS4/</link>
      <description>Protests held across the country this weekend showed the sharp divide in opinion over a shooting involving an Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent in Minnesota.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WPXI Pittsburgh</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noem says more federal agents coming to Minnesota, protests continue days after fatal ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/video/noem-says-more-federal-agents-coming-to-minnesota-protests-continue-days-after-fatal-ice-shooting/</link>
      <description>Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem says hundreds more federal agents are being sent to Minnesota as protests continue there and across the country, demanding justice after an ICE agent shot and killed Renee Good. Nicole Sganga has more.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump admin sending more agents to Minneapolis despite outrage over fatal shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/trump-admin-deploys-more-federal-agents-to-minneapolis/106219476</link>
      <description>US Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem says hundreds more federal agents are heading to Minneapolis, brushing aside demands by the city's Democratic leaders to leave after an immigration officer fatally shot a female protester.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News (AU)</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mark Ruffalo, Wanda Sykes Wear ‘Be Good,’ ‘ICE Out’ Pins at Golden Globes in Honor of Renée Macklin Good, Mother Killed by ICE Agent</title>
      <link>https://variety.com/2026/film/news/golden-globes-be-good-pins-renee-good-killed-ice-1236628509/</link>
      <description>A sprinkling of celebrities at Sunday’s Golden Globes red carpet wore pins with the messages “Ice Out” and “Be Good” to honor the memory of Renée Macklin Good, who was killed by ICE in Minneapolis this week. Nominees, presenters and guests including Mark Ruff…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:12:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Variety</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrities protest ICE on Golden Globes red carpet</title>
      <link>https://www.the-independent.com/arts-entertainment/films/news/golden-globes-anti-ice-protest-pins-b2898480.html</link>
      <description>Mark Ruffalo is among the names wearing a pin at the ceremony paying tribute to Renee Good after she was shot by ICE agents earlier this week</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 23:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The-independent.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dems force GOP to abandon DHS funding for upcoming debate after ICE shooting: report</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/republicans-2674873476/</link>
      <description>Republicans in Congress moved to strike funding for the Department of Homeland Security from this week's budget debates after an immigration agent shot and killed a 37-year-old mother in Minneapolis, according to a new report. CNN's Sarah Harris reported the …</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 23:16:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump admin sends more agents to Minneapolis despite furor over woman’s killing</title>
      <link>https://www.digitaljournal.com/world/trump-admin-sends-more-agents-to-minneapolis-despite-furor-over-womans-killing/article</link>
      <description>US Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem said Sunday that hundreds more federal agents were heading to Minneapolis, brushing aside demands by the city’s Democratic leaders to leave after an immigration officer fatally shot a woman protester. In multiple TV …</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 21:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Digital Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAGA’s Crackdown on Dissent Started With Pro-Palestinian Activists. It Didn’t End There.</title>
      <link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2026/01/trump-renee-good-ice-roger-williams-wesley-hunt-first-amendment/</link>
      <description>Two days after an ICE agent shot and killed Renée Good in Minneapolis, Rep. Roger Williams issued an ultimatum to the Trump administration’s critics in Minnesota and beyond. “People need to quit demonstrating, quit yelling at law enforcement, challenging law …</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 19:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mother Jones</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kristi Noem Vows ‘Hundreds More’ ICE Agents Heading to Minnesota: It’s ‘Ground Zero’ for ‘Protecting Criminals’</title>
      <link>https://www.mediaite.com/politics/kristi-noem-vows-hundreds-more-ice-agents-heading-to-minnesota-its-ground-zero-for-protecting-criminals/</link>
      <description>DHS Secretary Kristi Noem announced “hundreds” of ICE agents are being sent to Minnesota today and tomorrow during an appearance on Sunday Morning Futures with Maria Bartiromo on Fox News. Their arrival comes days after an ICE agent shot and killed 37-year-ol…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 19:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mediaite</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: ICE are the real domestic terrorists</title>
      <link>https://dailyutahchronicle.com/2026/01/11/opinion-ice-are-the-real-domestic-terrorists/</link>
      <description>On Wednesday, Jan. 7, an ICE (Immigration and Customs Enforcement) agent shot and killed Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis, Minnesota. Department of Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem called Good’s actions against ICE agents “an act of domestic terrorism.…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 19:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Dailyutahchronicle.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1/11: Face The Nation</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/video/011126-face-the-nation/</link>
      <description>This week on &quot;Face the Nation with Margaret Brennan,&quot; Rep. Ilhan Omar joins after being denied entry to a Minneapolis ICE facility amid protests in the city after an ICE agent shot and killed a 37-year-old woman. Plus, Secretary of Energy Chris Wright discuss…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 18:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New video shows minutes leading up to deadly Minneapolis ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/new-video-shows-minutes-leading-up-deadly-minneapolis-ice-shooting</link>
      <description>New video shows moments before ICE agent fatally shot Minneapolis woman Renee Nicole Good. DHS claims footage shows she was &quot;stalking&quot; federal operation.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 18:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHS shares new video of minutes before ICE shooting of Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://www.wgal.com/article/dhs-video-minutes-before-ice-shooting-renee-good/69966509</link>
      <description>New video shows the minutes before an ICE agent shot and killed Renee Good, showing her car partially blocking the street while several cars are able to pass it.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 14:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WGAL Susquehanna Valley Pa.</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US woman killed by ICE agent called ‘domestic terrorist’: What it means</title>
      <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2026/1/11/us-woman-killed-by-ice-agent-called-domestic-terrorist-what-it-means</link>
      <description>Experts say US homeland security secretary misused the 'domestic terrorist' label to justify shooting Renee Good.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Al Jazeera English</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota Attorney General Says Trump Blocked State From Investigating ICE Shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.huffpost.com/entry/keith-ellison-minnesota-trump-ice-shooting_n_6962cd1fe4b0c587cd6bca8d</link>
      <description>Keith Ellison said federal authorities stonewalled his office hours after an ICE agent killed Renee Good.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>HuffPost</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rallies in US after woman shot and killed by ICE agent</title>
      <link>https://www.rte.ie/news/us/2026/0111/1552485-rallies-in-us-after-woman-shot-and-killed-by-ice-agent/</link>
      <description>Thousands of demonstrators took to the streets of Minneapolis chanting the name of the woman killed by a federal agent in the city, amid widespread anger at use of force in the Trump administration's immigration crackdown.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 01:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>RTE</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-ICE protests erupt across Colorado after fatal Minnesota shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.denverpost.com/2026/01/10/colorado-anti-ice-protests-minnesota-shooting/</link>
      <description>Protests over immigration enforcement broke out across Colorado on Saturday after fatal and nonfatal officer-involved shootings in Minneapolis and Portland.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Denver Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NBA Coach Steve Kerr Condemns ICE for Minnesota ‘Murder’ and Trump Adminstration’s ‘Shameful’ Response</title>
      <link>https://www.mediaite.com/media/sports/nba-coach-steve-kerr-condemns-ice-for-minnesota-murder-and-trump-adminstrations-shameful-response/</link>
      <description>Warriors coach Steve Kerr accused ICE of &quot;commit[ing] murder&quot; when an agent shot and killed protestor Renee Good in Minnesota
The post NBA Coach Steve Kerr Condemns ICE for Minnesota ‘Murder’ and Trump Adminstration’s ‘Shameful’ Response first appeared on Med…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mediaite</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tom Emmer pushes back on suggestion that Minnesota anti-ICE protesters have been peaceful</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/media/tom-emmer-pushes-back-suggestion-minnesota-anti-ice-protesters-have-been-peaceful</link>
      <description>Minneapolis protests continue after an ICE agent fatally shot a woman, with House Majority Whip Tom Emmer blaming Democratic leaders for ongoing tensions in the city.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portland Police Chief Begins To Cry As He Reluctantly Confirms Two People Shot By CBP Were Connected To Tren De Aragua</title>
      <link>https://dailycaller.com/2026/01/10/portland-police-chief-cries-tren-de-aragua-shot-cbp/</link>
      <description>Portland Police Chief Bob Day started crying during a press conference Friday after admitting two people shot by federal agents were linked to Tren de Aragua.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Daily Caller</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controversy surrounding ICE killing incident in Minneapolis deepens as new footage of deadly encounter released</title>
      <link>https://www.globalsecurity.org/security/library/news/2026/01/sec-260110-globaltimes01.htm</link>
      <description>Controversy surrounding the incident in which a US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) officer fatally shot a mother of three Renee Nicole Good continued on Saturday. The White House on Friday reposted on social media a video taken from the cellphone of…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 09:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Globalsecurity.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mamdani’s tardy response to two NYPD shootings draws blowback — including a miffed Commish Tisch</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/01/09/us-news/mamdanis-tardy-response-to-two-nypd-shootings-draws-blowback-including-a-miffed-commish-tisch/</link>
      <description>Fledgling Mayor Zohran Mamdani is already facing blowback for his tardy, halfhearted response to back-to-back police shootings – including friction with NYPD Commissioner Jessica Tisch, The Post has learned. Mamdani – who backed off his ardent “defund the pol…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 23:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wife Of Woman Killed By ICE Agent Breaks Silence, Says They ‘Stopped To Support Our Neighbors’</title>
      <link>https://dailycaller.com/2026/01/09/renee-good-rebecca-statement-neighbors/</link>
      <description>'You want to come at us?'</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 23:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Daily Caller</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renee Nicole Good said ‘I’m not mad at you’ before Ice agent shot her, video shows</title>
      <link>https://www.irishtimes.com/world/us/2026/01/09/renee-nicole-good-said-im-not-mad-at-you-before-ice-agent-shot-her-video-shows/</link>
      <description>Clip first posted by partisan outlet Alpha News shows perspective of Ice agent as Good was fatally shot</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Irish Times</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal Expert Analysis: ICE Agent Was Fully in His Rights to Shoot Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://www.westernjournal.com/legal-expert-analysis-ice-agents-fully-rights-shoot-renee-good/</link>
      <description>An ICE agent fatally shot 37-year-old Renee Good inside her vehicle after she obstructed an immigration enforcement operation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Westernjournal.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trumpist lies about this ICE outrage demand a fierce response — including murder charges</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/raw-investigates/ice-shooting-2674862902/</link>
      <description>In Minneapolis, Minnesota, a masked Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent shot and killed another person, the 14
th
 ICE shooting under Trump to date
.Flexing Gestapo power in broad daylight, the agent shot a woman at close range
 as she was driving a…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Minnesota prosecute the federal immigration officer who just killed a woman?</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4361120/posts</link>
      <description>A federal officer shot and killed a woman in Minneapolis on Wednesday, shortly after the Trump administration deployed thousands of immigration agents to the city. Although the full circumstances of the killing remain unclear, video of the shooting shows an o…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 02:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Married couple shot by federal agents in Portland, FBI investigating</title>
      <link>https://www.israelnationalnews.com/news/420635</link>
      <description>Husband and wife hospitalized after being shot by federal agents in Portland, with the FBI leading the investigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 01:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Israelnationalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Ross military past, father and Iraq connection explained amid Minneapolis ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/jonathan-ross-military-past-father-and-iraq-connection-explained-amid-minneapolis-ice-shooting-renee-nicole-good-ice-officer-june-2025-arrest-in-bloomington/articleshow/126422528.cms</link>
      <description>Jonathan Ross military past, father and Iraq connection has come under focus after the ICE officer fatally shot Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis. Reports link Ross to prior ICE incidents, a possible military background, family Iraq references, and ongoing inv…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Times of India</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cops Are Taught Not to Shoot Into Cars. ICE Keeps Doing It Anyway.</title>
      <link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2026/01/renee-good-minneapolis-shooting-ice-trump-cops-taught-not-shoot-at-cars/</link>
      <description>On Wednesday, a masked federal immigration officer killed Renee Nicole Good, a 37-year-old mother and poet, shooting her at point-blank range in her car.  The incident, which has made headlines across the nation, is far from the first time immigration officer…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mother Jones</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis: Attempted ramming attack, suspect eliminated</title>
      <link>https://www.israelnationalnews.com/news/420554</link>
      <description>US officials say an ICE officer shot and killed a suspect who allegedly tried to ram federal agents with a vehicle during an enforcement operation in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Israelnationalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man with machete shot and killed by police, who then find 3 more dead inside home: officials</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/man-machete-shot-killed-police-find-3-more-dead-inside-home-officials</link>
      <description>Police shot and killed an individual armed with a knife in the Garden State on Monday, the New Jersey state attorney general's office noted in a press release.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 19:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-duty deputy shot and killed while working security job in Texas, suspect apprehended</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/off-duty-deputy-shot-killed-while-working-security-job-texas-suspect-apprehended</link>
      <description>Off-duty Caldwell County deputy shot and killed while working security at a nightclub in Austin, Texs. Police investigation ongoing.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 22:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-duty deputy shot and killed while working security job in Texas, suspect remains at large</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/off-duty-deputy-shot-killed-while-working-security-job-texas-suspect-remains-large</link>
      <description>Off-duty Caldwell County deputy shot and killed while working security at a nightclub in Austin, Texs. Police investigation ongoing.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 22:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police officer shoots, kills man who fled traffic stop</title>
      <link>https://www.mlive.com/news/2025/12/police-officer-shoots-kills-man-who-fled-traffic-stop.html</link>
      <description>The 30-year-old man allegedly said he was armed during a foot pursuit, police say.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 22:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>mlive.com</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
