<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 06:43:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Alleged Video Of ICE Shooting From Agent's Angle Given To Right-Wing Website</title>
      <link>https://www.huffpost.com/entry/minneapolis-video-ice-shooter-angle_n_69618ea1e4b024bfe0b94805</link>
      <description>&quot;F*cking bitch,&quot; a voice is heard saying after the ICE agent shot and killed Renee Good.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>HuffPost</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hundreds protest in Moorhead for woman killed by ICE agent</title>
      <link>https://www.inforum.com/news/moorhead/hundreds-protest-in-moorhead-for-woman-killed-by-ice-agent</link>
      <description>The group gathered for a peaceful protest on the busy Eighth Street to honor the life of a woman shot and killed by a U.S. immigration agent earlier in the week in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>INFORUM</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'We had whistles. They had guns,' says wife of Minnesota woman killed by ICE agent</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/we-had-whistles-they-had-guns-says-wife-of-minnesota-woman-killed-by-ice-agent</link>
      <description>The wife of Renee Good, the woman shot and killed in her car by a federal immigration agent in Minneapolis, says the couple had stopped to support their neighbors on the day of the shooting and described the mother of three as leaving a legacy of kindness.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 23:57:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>PBS</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mamdani’s tardy response to two NYPD shootings draws blowback — including a miffed Commish Tisch</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/01/09/us-news/mamdanis-tardy-response-to-two-nypd-shootings-draws-blowback-including-a-miffed-commish-tisch/</link>
      <description>Fledgling Mayor Zohran Mamdani is already facing blowback for his tardy, halfhearted response to back-to-back police shootings – including friction with NYPD Commissioner Jessica Tisch, The Post has learned. Mamdani – who backed off his ardent “defund the pol…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 23:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wife Of Woman Killed By ICE Agent Breaks Silence, Says They ‘Stopped To Support Our Neighbors’</title>
      <link>https://dailycaller.com/2026/01/09/renee-good-rebecca-statement-neighbors/</link>
      <description>'You want to come at us?'</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 23:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Daily Caller</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAGA figures call for arrests of Democrats after ICE kills woman in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/maga-2674865630/</link>
      <description>MAGA figures Steve Bannon and Jack Posobiec sparked outrage Friday by calling for the arrests of multiple Democratic leaders after an ICE agent fatally shot 37-year-old Renee Nicole Good. On his War Room broadcast, Bannon labeled local and state officials “Bo…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 23:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renee Nicole Good dog was safe or got hurt in Minneapolis ICE shooting? Full details emerge from new footage and family statements</title>
      <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/renee-nicole-good-dog-was-safe-or-got-hurt-in-minneapolis-ice-shooting-full-details-emerge-from-new-footage-and-family-statements-alpha-media-agent-jonathan-ross-australian-shepherd-named-hazelnut/articleshow/126445216.cms</link>
      <description>Renee Nicole Good dog was safe or got hurt in Minneapolis ICE shooting remains a key question after new footage surfaced. Renee Nicole Good was shot by ICE agent Jonathan Ross. Online users questioned the dog’s safety. Reports say the dog survived. Family sta…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:43:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Times of India</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renee Nicole Good said ‘I’m not mad at you’ before Ice agent shot her, video shows</title>
      <link>https://www.irishtimes.com/world/us/2026/01/09/renee-nicole-good-said-im-not-mad-at-you-before-ice-agent-shot-her-video-shows/</link>
      <description>Clip first posted by partisan outlet Alpha News shows perspective of Ice agent as Good was fatally shot</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Irish Times</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WATCH: Cellphone video from officer shows moment leading up to fatal shooting of Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/video/cellphone-video-officer-shows-moment-leading-fatal-shooting-129068454</link>
      <description>Tensions continue to flare in Minneapolis after an Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer fatally shot the 37-year-old woman on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Reacts to ICE’s Killing of Renee Nicole Good</title>
      <link>https://www.newyorker.com/news/the-lede/an-ice-killing-puts-minneapolis-on-the-brink</link>
      <description>Tensions are high in the city after an ICE officer fatally shot Good while she was in her car. Kristi Noem and Trump have said the shooting was justified, sparking outrage from mayor Jacob Frey and Governor Tim Walz.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 21:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The New Yorker</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Don't mistake my words!' CNN anchor shuts down ex-Trump official in fiery exchange</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/minneapolis-shooting-2674866751/</link>
      <description>A CNN anchor got into a fiery exchange Friday with a former Trump administration official over the leaked cell phone video capturing a confrontation in Minneapolis moments before a federal immigration agent fatally shot 37-year-old mother Renee Nicole Good. C…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man police shot in Brooklyn hospital was former NYPD officer, police said</title>
      <link>https://gothamist.com/news/man-police-shot-in-brooklyn-hospital-was-former-nypd-officer-police-said</link>
      <description>Brooklyn Methodist where police say they shot a former NYPD officer
 

Michael Lynch, 62, of Fort Greene, Brooklyn, resigned from the NYPD in the 1990s, according to police officials and his family. [ more › ]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Gothamist</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WATCH: Cellphone video from officer shows moment of fatal shooting of Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/video/cellphone-video-officer-shows-moment-fatal-shooting-renee-129066992</link>
      <description>Newly obtained video by ABC News shows the moments leading up to the fatal shooting of Renee Good. Tensions continue to flare in Minneapolis ICE officer fatally shot the 37-year-old woman.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Couple Shot by Federal Agents in Portland Connected to Venezuela Gang, DHS Says</title>
      <link>https://www.dailysignal.com/2026/01/09/couple-shot-by-federal-agents-in-portland-connected-to-venezuela-gang-dhs-says/</link>
      <description>The state of Oregon is investigating the shooting of two people by a Customs and Border Patrol agent in Portland on Thursday. According to the... Read More
The post Couple Shot by Federal Agents in Portland Connected to Venezuela Gang, DHS Says appeared first…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Daily Signal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PPB Monitors Protest Activity Near ICE Facility; Six Arrests Made - City of Portland, Oregon (.gov)</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180555086</link>
      <description>PPB Monitors Protest Activity Near ICE Facility; Six Arrests MadeCity of Portland, Oregon (.gov) US Border agent shoots, wounds two people in Portland that DHS says are gang membersKATU What We Know About the Border Patrol Shooting in Portland, OregonThe New …</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal agents shoot 2 in Portland after an ICE agent killed a woman in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.npr.org/2026/01/09/nx-s1-5672502/minneapolis-portland-ice-shootings</link>
      <description>Officials are calling for transparent investigations into controversial shootings involving federal agents. Here's a recap of the latest developments in Portland and Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>NPR</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surveillance footage shows immigration activist blocking road before fatal ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/surveillance-footage-shows-immigration-activist-blocking-road-before-fatal-ice-shooting</link>
      <description>Surveillance footage shows moments before immigration activist was allegedly shot by ICE agents during enforcement operation in Minneapolis area.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A cold-blooded murder — In Minneapolis on Wednesday, an ICE agent shot and killed Renee Good, a 37-year-old mother of three. (Robert Reich)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260109/p63</link>
      <description>Robert Reich:
A cold-blooded murder  —  In Minneapolis on Wednesday, an ICE agent shot and killed Renee Good, a 37-year-old mother of three.  The shooting occurred on a residential street in south Minneapolis (less than a mile from where George Floyd was kill…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Trump disgrace was almost as chilling as Renee Good's murder</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/ice-shooting-2674863864/</link>
      <description>In Minneapolis on Wednesday, an ICE agent shot and killed Renee Good, a 37-year-old mother of three. The shooting occurred on a residential street in the south of the city, less than a mile from where George Floyd was killed by police in 2020.Donald Trump cla…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mamdani Reacts Carefully to Two Police Shootings on Same Day</title>
      <link>http://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/mamdani-reacts-carefully-to-two-police-shootings-on-same-day.html</link>
      <description>In the first test of Mamdani’s handling of the NYPD, weapon-wielding suspects were killed by police in Brooklyn and Manhattan on Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Magazine</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Border Patrol Officer Shot Two People in Portland</title>
      <link>http://www.thecut.com/article/portland-shooting-border-patrol-oregon.html</link>
      <description>A border patrol officer shot two people in Portland, a day after an ICE officer killed a woman, Renee Nicole Good, in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Cut</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outrage and Mistrust Mount at Federal Agents Who Shot Two People in Portland One Day After Renee Good’s Killing</title>
      <link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2026/01/federal-agents-shot-and-injured-two-people-in-portland-one-day-after-renee-goods-killing/</link>
      <description>US Border Patrol shot and injured two people in Portland on Thursday, just one day after an Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent named Jonathan Ross shot and killed US citizen Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis.  People in Portland were already protesting …</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mother Jones</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inquest report exonerates Mountie in fatal shooting of machete-wielding attacker</title>
      <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/manitoba/inquest-report-exonerates-mountie-in-fatal-shooting-of-machete-wielding-attacker-9.7039277</link>
      <description>An inquest report into the fatal police shooting of a man — who moments earlier had used a machete to attack someone in a vehicle — praises the actions of the officer and makes no recommendations on how the incident could have been handled differently.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Knows How to Resist This Violence</title>
      <link>https://newrepublic.com/article/205067/renee-good-george-floyd-minneapolis-resistance-violence</link>
      <description>Just over five years after the police murder of George Perry Floyd Jr., Minneapolis is again taking to the streets over an unjustified killing by law enforcement. This time, the victim is Renee Nicole Good, a 37-year-old woman who was shot by ICE agent Jonath…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:42:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The New Republic</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agent pulls out gun in woman's face amid ticking time bomb...</title>
      <link>https://www.themirror.com/news/us-news/ice-agent-pulls-out-gun-1608459</link>
      <description>Minnesota Gov. Tim Walz deployed the National Guard to assist local law enforcement as protests broke out across the state and country after an ICE agent fatally shot a Minneapolis woman</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Themirror.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portland agitators clash with police after 2 shot by federal immigration agent</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/portland-agitators-clash-police-after-2-shot-federal-immigration-agent</link>
      <description>Portland demonstrations erupt near ICE building after Border Patrol shooting, leading to police clashes and more arrests now totally at least 79 people.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:43:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Border Patrol agents shoot two in Portland after ICE officer killed Renee Good in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/video/border-patrol-agents-shoot-two-in-portland-after-ice-officer-killed-renee-good-in-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>Another immigration official-involved shooting occurred in the U.S. this week. In Portland, Oregon, two people were shot and injured during a car search by Border Patrol agents. This comes after the fatal shooting involving an ICE officer in Minnesota. CBS Ne…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 15:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Border patrol agent shoots two in Portland and Russia attacks Ukraine with new weapon: Morning Rundown</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/border-patrol-agent-shoots-two-portland-iran-protests-morning-rundown-rcna252936</link>
      <description>Two people are wounded in a shooting involving a Border Patrol agent in Portland, just one day after the fatal incident in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 12:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>NBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal Expert Analysis: ICE Agent Was Fully in His Rights to Shoot Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://www.westernjournal.com/legal-expert-analysis-ice-agents-fully-rights-shoot-renee-good/</link>
      <description>An ICE agent fatally shot 37-year-old Renee Good inside her vehicle after she obstructed an immigration enforcement operation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Westernjournal.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trumpist lies about this ICE outrage demand a fierce response — including murder charges</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/raw-investigates/ice-shooting-2674862902/</link>
      <description>In Minneapolis, Minnesota, a masked Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent shot and killed another person, the 14
th
 ICE shooting under Trump to date
.Flexing Gestapo power in broad daylight, the agent shot a woman at close range
 as she was driving a…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Minnesota prosecute the federal immigration officer who just killed a woman?</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4361120/posts</link>
      <description>A federal officer shot and killed a woman in Minneapolis on Wednesday, shortly after the Trump administration deployed thousands of immigration agents to the city. Although the full circumstances of the killing remain unclear, video of the shooting shows an o…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 02:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Married couple shot by federal agents in Portland, FBI investigating</title>
      <link>https://www.israelnationalnews.com/news/420635</link>
      <description>Husband and wife hospitalized after being shot by federal agents in Portland, with the FBI leading the investigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 01:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Israelnationalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Ross military past, father and Iraq connection explained amid Minneapolis ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/jonathan-ross-military-past-father-and-iraq-connection-explained-amid-minneapolis-ice-shooting-renee-nicole-good-ice-officer-june-2025-arrest-in-bloomington/articleshow/126422528.cms</link>
      <description>Jonathan Ross military past, father and Iraq connection has come under focus after the ICE officer fatally shot Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis. Reports link Ross to prior ICE incidents, a possible military background, family Iraq references, and ongoing inv…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Times of India</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cops Are Taught Not to Shoot Into Cars. ICE Keeps Doing It Anyway.</title>
      <link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2026/01/renee-good-minneapolis-shooting-ice-trump-cops-taught-not-shoot-at-cars/</link>
      <description>On Wednesday, a masked federal immigration officer killed Renee Nicole Good, a 37-year-old mother and poet, shooting her at point-blank range in her car.  The incident, which has made headlines across the nation, is far from the first time immigration officer…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mother Jones</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis: Attempted ramming attack, suspect eliminated</title>
      <link>https://www.israelnationalnews.com/news/420554</link>
      <description>US officials say an ICE officer shot and killed a suspect who allegedly tried to ram federal agents with a vehicle during an enforcement operation in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Israelnationalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man with machete shot and killed by police, who then find 3 more dead inside home: officials</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/man-machete-shot-killed-police-find-3-more-dead-inside-home-officials</link>
      <description>Police shot and killed an individual armed with a knife in the Garden State on Monday, the New Jersey state attorney general's office noted in a press release.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 19:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-duty deputy shot and killed while working security job in Texas, suspect apprehended</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/off-duty-deputy-shot-killed-while-working-security-job-texas-suspect-apprehended</link>
      <description>Off-duty Caldwell County deputy shot and killed while working security at a nightclub in Austin, Texs. Police investigation ongoing.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 22:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-duty deputy shot and killed while working security job in Texas, suspect remains at large</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/off-duty-deputy-shot-killed-while-working-security-job-texas-suspect-remains-large</link>
      <description>Off-duty Caldwell County deputy shot and killed while working security at a nightclub in Austin, Texs. Police investigation ongoing.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 22:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police officer shoots, kills man who fled traffic stop</title>
      <link>https://www.mlive.com/news/2025/12/police-officer-shoots-kills-man-who-fled-traffic-stop.html</link>
      <description>The 30-year-old man allegedly said he was armed during a foot pursuit, police say.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 22:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>mlive.com</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
