<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting Research Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-research/</link>
    <description>Recent academic research on police shootings and use of deadly force</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:15:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Prevention of Destructive Fishing in the Waters of Tual City: Effective Surveillance and Law Enforcement Strategies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54660/.ijmrge.2025.6.1.2089-2094</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; . et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; International Journal of Multidisciplinary Research and Growth Evaluation&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Destructive fishing in the waters of Tual City remains a significant environmental and socio-economic issue, threatening marine biodiversity and the livelihoods of local fishermen. This study analyzes the problem using a SWOT approach, identifying strengths such as existing government regulations and rich marine resources, weaknesses including limited enforcement capacity and economic dependence on harmful fishing practices, opportunities such as growing global demand for sustainable sea...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2089 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>International Journal of Multidisciplinary Research and Growth Evaluation</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encounters with Photobooks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.11116/9789461667434</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Carlin, Briony&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Journal&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Photobooks are an art form on the move. They travel physically, as copies are bought, traded, treasured, forgotten, and rediscovered around the world. They move conceptually, as their meanings evolve through changing use and value. Photobooks combine languages of photography, text and design into a distinct medium that breaks from the confines of galleries and libraries, entering unexpected or intimate environments, such as our homes.

Encounters with Photobooks marks a shift in scholars...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Unknown Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-destructive adhesive cure assessment in carbon fiber reinforced composites using dielectric spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ndteint.2025.103621</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Rahman et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; NDT &amp;amp; E International</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>NDT &amp;amp; E International</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police Violence and White Supremacist Terrorism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/9780197653463.003.0005</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Wolfendale, Jessica&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; American Torture and American Terrorism&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                  &lt;jats:p&gt;Chapter 4 takes up the issue of white supremacist terrorism in America. While much scholarship on this issue focuses on the (very real) threat posed by nonstate white supremacist terrorism, this chapter reveals the complex and longstanding relationship between state and nonstate white supremacist terrorism. The complexity of this relationship makes it difficult to draw a neat distinction between state and nonstate forms of white suprema...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>American Torture and American Terrorism</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police use of force data collection issues in Florida: A minor critique</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.polgeo.2025.103468</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Rose et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Political Geography</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Political Geography</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conflictual encounters with individuals with mental illness from the perspective of police officers: Reasons, challenges, and experiences with escalating and De-escalating factors – An empirical study of German police officers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijlp.2025.102167</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Posch, Lena&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; International Journal of Law and Psychiatry</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>International Journal of Law and Psychiatry</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calibration of Atomic Force Microscope soft cantilevers based on μ-LDV: metrological insight on the constitutive experimental parameters of Sader’s formulas for flexural and torsional effective spring constant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.measurement.2025.120260</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Schiavi et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Measurement</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Measurement</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular dynamic simulation of multi-frequency electrostatic force microscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.micron.2025.103979</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Yuan et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Micron</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Micron</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of simulation on the knowledge, skills, and confidence of entry-to-practice nursing students to recognise and respond to occupational violence and aggression: A scoping review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nedt.2025.106939</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Peddle et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Nurse Education Today</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Nurse Education Today</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An integrated approach for addressing data imbalance in predicting fatality of helicopter accident</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ress.2025.111921</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Zhou et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Reliability Engineering &amp;amp; System Safety</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Reliability Engineering &amp;amp; System Safety</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of an electronic health record model to predict law enforcement presence in pediatric emergency department encounters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ajem.2025.12.010</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Abrams et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; The American Journal of Emergency Medicine</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>The American Journal of Emergency Medicine</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Displaying deadly police violence against Black people through government memorials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1108/pijpsm-09-2025-0171</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Keyes &amp; Keyes&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Policing: An International Journal&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:sec&gt;
                    &lt;jats:title&gt;Purpose&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                    &lt;jats:p&gt;The purpose of this article is to explore the understudied intersection of government-sponsored memorials of Black people alongside the demographics of police officers who were involved in their deaths and the emergence of government-sponsored memorials for Black people slain by police.&lt;/jats:p&gt;
                  &lt;/jats:sec&gt;
                  &lt;jats:sec&gt;
                    &lt;jats:title&gt;Design/methodology/a...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Policing: An International Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who makes the right call? Examining relationships between personality traits and situational performance in police cadets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1108/pijpsm-02-2025-0037</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; AlSabah et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Policing: An International Journal&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:sec&gt;
                    &lt;jats:title&gt;Purpose&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                    &lt;jats:p&gt;Police institutions and practitioners often associate personality traits with an individual’s likelihood of success in policing, emphasizing certain psychological profiles as better suited for handling the stressful conditions inherent in police work. This study investigates personality traits and their potential relationship to critical aspects of police performance under stress–conceptualized as decisio...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Policing: An International Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Binding Effect of Constitutional Court Decisions on Police Regulations (An Analysis of Constitutional Court Decision No. 114/PUU-XXIII/2025)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52249/ilr.v6i1.658</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Firmanto, Kiki&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; IBLAM LAW REVIEW&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;This study examines the binding force of Constitutional Court decisions on administrative regulations issued by the Indonesian National Police, with particular attention to the normative consistency between Police Regulation No. 10 of 2025 and the constitutional meaning articulated in Constitutional Court Decision No. 114/PUU-XXIII/2025. A normative legal research approach is employed through the analysis of constitutional norms, the hierarchy of laws and regulations, doctrines of consti...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>IBLAM LAW REVIEW</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Convenience, Quickness, and Compassion”: Experiences of People Involved in the Criminal‐Legal System Accessing Medications for Opioid Use Disorder Services From a Mobile Unit in Chicago</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/hex.70552</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Martinford et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Health Expectations&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;ABSTRACT&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                  &lt;jats:sec&gt;
                    &lt;jats:title&gt;Background&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                    &lt;jats:p&gt;This study aimed to explore the experiences of people diagnosed with opioid use disorder (OUD) and recently involved with the criminal‐legal system (CLS) as they received addiction treatment services from a Mobile Medications for Opioid Use Disorder (MOUD) programme in Chicago. By assessing perceptions and satisfaction with receiving addiction treatme...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Health Expectations</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book review: Policing the narrative: Book review of Tony Cheng’s “The Policing Machine” and Alec Karakatsanis’ “Copaganda” Policing the narrative: Book review of Tony Cheng’s “
                    &lt;i&gt;The Policing Machine&lt;/i&gt;
                    ” and Alec Karakatsanis’ “
                    &lt;i&gt;Copaganda&lt;/i&gt;
                    ”ChengTony (2024) The Policing Machine: Enforcement, Endorsements, and the Illusion of Public Input. The University of Chicago Press, p.240, ISBN 9780226830650, $20.00 (pbk).KarakatsanisAlec (2025) Copaganda: How Police and the Media Manipulate Our News. The New Press, p.432, ISBN 9781620978535, $31.99 (hbk).</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/17416590251412033</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Grasso, Jordan&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Crime, Media, Culture: An International Journal</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Crime, Media, Culture: An International Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smoke Poetics: The Wapping Coal Riot, the Marine Police, and Romantic Forms of Urbanity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/h15010011</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Whittell, Jesslyn&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Humanities&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;This paper reads coal as a metonym for London’s social fabric in the writings of police theorist Patrick Colquhoun, the archival reports on the Wapping Coal Riot, and the anti-carceral poetry of William Blake. In 1798, at the behest of the West India Committee, Colquhoun had developed the first modern police force, the Thames River Police, which predated Robert Peel’s metropolitan police by over 20 years. Colquhoun’s “Treatise on the Commerce and Police of the River Thames” (1800) center...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Humanities</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of a Daily Undulating Periodization Program on the Physical Performance of Trainee Tactical Police Officers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1519/jsc.0000000000005356</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Robinson et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Journal of Strength &amp;amp; Conditioning Research&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                  &lt;jats:p&gt;
                    Jeremy, R, Ben, S, and Robin, O. The effect of a daily undulating periodization program on the physical performance of trainee tactical police officers.
                    &lt;jats:italic toggle=&quot;yes&quot;&gt;J Strength Cond Res&lt;/jats:italic&gt;
                    XX(X): 000–000, 2026—Specialist tactical police officers, like Special Weapons and Tactics (SWAT) teams, require exceptional muscular strength, power, speed, and aero...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Journal of Strength &amp;amp; Conditioning Research</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chutes and Ladders: Collecting Records of Police Shootings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/9780691260839-004</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Authors&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Deadly Force</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Deadly Force</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5. LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICERS AND THE PRISTINE FOURTEEN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7312/dura20210-007</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Authors&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Justice Required</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Justice Required</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1. THE CONTEXT OF POLICE SHOOTINGS AND PROTEST: DENVER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7312/dura20210-003</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Authors&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Justice Required</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Justice Required</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2. DIVERGENT LIFE CHANCES FOR GETTIN’ SHOT BY THE POLICE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7312/dura20210-004</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Authors&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Justice Required</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Justice Required</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Officer Ranks of the Polish Armed Forces during World War II</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/9798887196855-002</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Authors&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Between Hitler and Churchill</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Between Hitler and Churchill</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 When Police Shootings Kill</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/9780691260839-009</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Authors&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Deadly Force</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Deadly Force</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementasi Pelatihan Vokasional Berbasis IPTEK untuk Meningkatkan Efisiensi Operasional dan Kompetensi Warehouse Operation Officer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.38035/jpmpt.v3i4.1637</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Ashari et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Jurnal Pengabdian  Masyarakat dan Penelitian Terapan&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Kegiatan pengabdian kepada masyarakat ini bertujuan meningkatkan kompetensi sumber daya manusia di sektor logistik melalui program pelatihan dan sertifikasi profesi Warehouse Operation Officer (WOO) yang berlisensi Badan Nasional Sertifikasi Profesi (BNSP). Program ini merupakan kolaborasi antara Institut Transportasi dan Logistik (ITL) TRISAKTI dan PT Sadikun Niagamas Raya, yang dilaksanakan pada 7 Oktober 2025 di Kampus Pascasarjana ITL TRISAKTI, Jakarta.
Metode pelaksanaan menggunakan...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Jurnal Pengabdian  Masyarakat dan Penelitian Terapan</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The impact of officer tenure on injury outcomes in law enforcement encounters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/0032258x251411194</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Lomenzo et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; The Police Journal: Theory, Practice and Principles&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Police use-of-force encounters, though rare, pose serious injury risks. This study examines whether officer tenure predicts injury outcomes for both officers and suspects during use-of-force incidents. Using logistic regression on 762 Miami-Dade cases (2002–2006), this study finds that officer tenure was not linked to officer injury but negatively predicted suspect injury. Experienced officers may manage encounters more effectively, reducing harm. Conducted energy device (CED) use corres...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>The Police Journal: Theory, Practice and Principles</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASSESSING THE PERCEIVED EFFECTIVENESS OF POLICE TRAINING PROGRAMS: A CROSS-SECTIONAL STUDY ON OFFICER PREPAREDNESS AND REAL-WORLD APPLICATION</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.36713/epra25478</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Rhem N. Rick Corpuz et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; EPRA International Journal of Multidisciplinary Research (IJMR)&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Evaluating the effectiveness of police training is essential in ensuring that officers are adequately prepared to meet the demands of modern law enforcement. This study quantitatively examines the effectiveness of police training programs by assessing officers’ preparedness and the practical application of acquired skills in real-life situations. The study focuses on scenario-based training, ethical decision-making, and physical readiness. A cross-sectional survey research design was emp...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>EPRA International Journal of Multidisciplinary Research (IJMR)</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>METHODOLOGICAL AND THEORETICAL FUNDAMENTALS OF FORMATION OF OFFICER PROFESSIONAL CULTURE AS A TOPICAL PROBLEM OF MILITARY PROFESSIONAL TRAINING</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46991/educ-21st-century.v7.i2.139</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Marchenko &amp; Zelenskaya&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Education in the 21st Century&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;The article substantiates the expediency of clarifying the essence of the concept of ‘professional culture of the officer’ from the standpoint of new methodological approaches: axiological, acmeological, competence-based, resource-oriented, and system-synergetic. The extended interpretation emphasizes the relevance of the issue in the modern context of military operations, taking into account the transformation of values, the technological progress of warfare, and the changing requiremen...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Education in the 21st Century</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sex-specific Lean Mass Changes during Marine Corps Officer Candidates School and Associations with Physical Health, Performance and Military Readiness</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1249/mss.0000000000003918</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Koltun et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Medicine &amp;amp; Science in Sports &amp;amp; Exercise&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Individuals participating in military training are subject to physical training that can affect body mass and composition in a manner that may be dependent on sex and relate to physical health and performance.&lt;/jats:p&gt;
                  &lt;jats:sec&gt;
                    &lt;jats:title&gt;Purpose:&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                    &lt;jats:p&gt;This investigation compared changes in body composition between sexes during Marine Corps Officer Candidates School (OCS), and explored potential associations wit...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Medicine &amp;amp; Science in Sports &amp;amp; Exercise</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gender-Based Violence Concerns, Trust in Police and Support for Defunding the Police</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/bjc/azaf119</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Updegrove &amp; Craig&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; The British Journal of Criminology&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                  &lt;jats:p&gt;Public opinion research has yet to fully consider the various contexts in which people evaluate calls to defund the police and how those contexts may relate to or interact with popular constructs like trust in police. Because Americans are socialized to view police as the primary response to gender-based violence, people concerned about gender-based violence may perceive that defunding would negatively impact responses to this issue. Us...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>The British Journal of Criminology</source>
      <priority>true</priority>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
