<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 06:41:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>When an ICE Agent Shot Two Bullets Into Renee Good Through the Driver’s Side Window, He Was Not Engaged in Self-Defense</title>
      <link>https://www.juancole.com/2026/01/bullets-through-drivers.html</link>
      <description>Kristi Noel’s Preposterous Lies About the Killing Confirm That ICE Encourages Agent Violence</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 05:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Juancole.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cynical reason Jacob Frey and Tim Walz chose now to stop calling for chaos</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/01/15/opinion/cynical-reason-jacob-frey-and-tim-walz-chose-now-to-stop-calling-for-chaos/</link>
      <description>Minneapolis Mayor Jacob Frey launched a remarkable 180 late Wednesday: “I’m calling for peace,” he announced after an ICE agent shot an illegal Venezuelan who’d tried to murder him after a car chase.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Score: Renee Good Fatally Shot by ICE; Women Work Longer and Are Paid Less Worldwide; N.Y. Fights Back Against Federal Childcare Freeze</title>
      <link>https://msmagazine.com/2026/01/15/keeping-score-feminist-news-renee-good-shot-ice-women-work-paid-less-new-york-childcare-freeze/</link>
      <description>In every issue of Ms., we track research on our progress in the fight for equality, catalogue can’t-miss quotes from feminist voices and keep tabs on the feminist movement’s many milestones. We’re Keeping Score online, too—in this biweekly roundup.
This week:…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 23:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Ms. Magazine</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New bill addresses police shootings of people in mental health crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.vermontpublic.org/local-news/2026-01-15/bill-prevent-police-shootings-mental-health-crisis</link>
      <description>State lawmakers and the family of a man fatally shot by Vermont State Police laid out a set of reforms they say could help prevent police shootings of people in crisis.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Vermontpublic.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Trump could use the Insurrection Act to pummel Minnesota (Axios)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260115/p110</link>
      <description>Axios:
How Trump could use the Insurrection Act to pummel Minnesota  —  First President Trump flooded the Twin Cities with federal agents.  Now he's threatening to deploy troops to bolster the armed immigration crackdown. … An an ICE agent shot and killed a d…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 21:15:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fed Agent Shoots Second Person, Days After Miller Claims Agents Have “Immunity”</title>
      <link>https://truthout.org/articles/fed-agent-shoots-second-person-days-after-miller-claims-agents-have-immunity/</link>
      <description>Miller lied to ICE agents, saying, “Anybody who lays a hand on you or tries to stop you … is committing a felony.”…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 20:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Truthout</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Police Chief: Rioters 'Are Engaging in Unlawful Acts'</title>
      <link>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2026/01/15/minneapolis-police-chief-rioters-are-engaging-unlawful-acts/</link>
      <description>Minneapolis Police Chief Brian O'Hara noted rioters gathered in response to Wednesday's officer-involved shooting were &quot;engaging in unlawful acts.&quot;
The post Minneapolis Police Chief: Rioters ‘Are Engaging in Unlawful Acts’ appeared first on Breitbart.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Breitbart News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump threatens to use Insurrection Act in Minnesota in response to Ice protests</title>
      <link>https://www.irishtimes.com/world/us/2026/01/15/trump-threatens-to-use-insurrection-act-in-minnesota-in-response-to-ice-protests/</link>
      <description>Protests continue across state and governor urges peace one week after federal agent shot and killed Renee Good</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Irish Times</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Federal Agent Shot Another Person in Minneapolis. Then Trump Threatened the Insurrection Act.</title>
      <link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2026/01/ice-dhs-shooting-protests-minneapolis-insurrection-act/</link>
      <description>The Trump administration’s offensive against immigrants in Minneapolis—and those who seek to help them—continued to intensify Wednesday night and into Thursday after a federal agent shot another person during an immigration operation.  President Donald Trump,…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mother Jones</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE officer shoots Venezuelan man in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.salon.com/2026/01/15/ice-officer-shoots-venezuelan-man-in-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>The shooting escalated tensions in the city as more protests erupted in response</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Salon</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHS says man shot in leg during Minneapolis scuffle, federal officer hospitalized (Tara Suter/The Hill)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260115/p72</link>
      <description>Tara Suter / The Hill:
DHS says man shot in leg during Minneapolis scuffle, federal officer hospitalized  —  The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) said that a federal officer shot a man during a scuffle in Minneapolis that involved multiple people — an in…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 takeaways from new polls of the Minneapolis ICE shooting (Aaron Blake/CNN)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260115/p67</link>
      <description>Aaron Blake / CNN:
5 takeaways from new polls of the Minneapolis ICE shooting  —  Federal agencies Election polls Gun violence Immigration  —  After an Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent shot and killed Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis one week ago, re…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-ICE threat spray-painted on vehicle believed to be used by federal officers during Minneapolis unrest</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/anti-ice-threat-spray-painted-vehicle-believed-used-federal-officers-during-minneapolis-unrest</link>
      <description>Minneapolis rioters vandalized vehicles with anti-ICE messages and threats after a federal agent shot an illegal immigrant during an alleged ambush.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHS says federal officer shot person in leg after being attacked during Minneapolis arrest</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/dhs-says-federal-officer-shot-person-in-leg-after-being-attacked-during-minneapolis-arrest</link>
      <description>A federal officer shot a man in the leg in Minneapolis after being attacked with a shovel and broom handle while trying to make an arrest Wednesday, officials said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:23:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>PBS</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal Agent Shoots Venezuelan Man In Minneapolis; Multiple Suspects In Custody …</title>
      <link>http://www.thehollywoodgossip.com/2026/01/federal-agent-shoots-venezuelan-man-in-minneapolis-multiple-suspects-in-custody-following-chaotic-altercation/</link>
      <description>Reading Time: 3 minutesWe have reports of more violence in the streets of Minneapolis.
Federal Agent Shoots Venezuelan Man In Minneapolis; Multiple Suspects In Custody … was originally published on The Hollywood Gossip.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>The Hollywood Gossip</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump threatens to use the Insurrection Act to ‘put an end’ to protests in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.denverpost.com/2026/01/15/second-federal-officer-shooting-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>Trump made the threat after a federal officer shot a man in the leg in Minneapolis on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Denver Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live updates: Minneapolis ICE shooting, tensions flare after man is shot in leg after allegedly assaulting federal agent | CNN</title>
      <link>https://www.cnn.com/us/live-news/minneapolis-ice-shooting-protests-01-15-26</link>
      <description>Law enforcement and demonstrators clashed last night near where a federal agent shot and injured a man after he allegedly assaulted the agent. The city is reeling over last week’s fatal shooting by an ICE agent of Renee Good sparked nationwide protests. Follo…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CNN</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overnight: 3rd DHS-Involved Shooting in a Week - Officer Shoots Suspect After Being Ambushed by Men With Pole Weapons</title>
      <link>https://www.westernjournal.com/overnight-3rd-dhs-involved-shooting-week-officer-shoots-suspect-ambushed-men-pole-weapons/</link>
      <description>&quot;As the officer was being ambushed and attacked by the two individuals, the original subject got loose and began striking the officer...&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Westernjournal.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal Agent Shoots Man In Minneapolis As Protests Continue</title>
      <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/siladityaray/2026/01/15/federal-agent-shoots-man-in-minneapolis-as-protests-continue/</link>
      <description>The DHS claimed the agent fired a defensive shot after he was attacked with a shovel and broom stick.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Forbes</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tensions Flare in Minneapolis as Federal Agent Shoots A Venezuelan National Following Alleged Shovel and Broom Assault</title>
      <link>https://www.ibtimes.com/tensions-flare-minneapolis-federal-agent-shoots-venezuelan-national-following-alleged-shovel-3795367</link>
      <description>Tensions flare in Minneapolis as federal agent shoots Venezuelan national in leg after alleged assault during immigration stop. Protests clash with police amid second ICE incident in a week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>International Business Times</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE officer shoots Venezuelan immigrant in Minneapolis: What we know</title>
      <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2026/1/15/ice-officer-shoots-venezuelan-immigrant-in-minneapolis-what-we-know</link>
      <description>ICE-related shooting in Minnesota occurred one week after Renee Nicole Good was shot dead by federal officer.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Al Jazeera English</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis anti-ICE protesters hurl fireworks, rocks at officers following shooting of Venezuelan migrant</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/01/15/us-news/minneapolis-anti-ice-protesters-hurl-fireworks-rocks-at-officers-following-shooting-of-venezuela-migrant/</link>
      <description>A group of violent anti-ICE protesters hurled fireworks and rocks at officers on a Minneapolis block where a federal immigration agent shot a Venezuelan migrant in the leg hours earlier Wednesday night.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US federal agent shoots Venezuelan man in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.rte.ie/news/us/2026/0115/1553182-minneapolis-us/</link>
      <description>A Venezuelan national ⁠pursued by US immigration agents during a &quot;targeted&quot; traffic stop in Minneapolis was shot in the leg by a federal officer, authorities said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>RTE</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal Officer Shoots Person In Leg In Minneapolis, Officials Say</title>
      <link>https://www.huffpost.com/entry/immigration-enforcement-ice-shooting_n_69685d9ce4b0774cc19ee4d5</link>
      <description>A federal officer has shot a person in the leg in Minneapolis after being attacked with a shovel during an arrest Wednesday, DHS said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>HuffPost</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another ICE shooting in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.lawyersgunsmoneyblog.com/2026/01/another-ice-shooting-in-minneapolis</link>
      <description>The CNN breaking news headline is that “Fed Officer Shot Suspect in Minneapolis After Shovel Ambush.” Rumors are flying about the identity of the shooting victim but we’ll see. The neighborhood in question appears to be a residential area close to downtown. A…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Lawyersgunsmoneyblog.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE agent shoots Venezuelan national in Minneapolis after shovel attack during ambush: DHS</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/ice-agent-shoots-venezuelan-national-minneapolis-shovel-attack-ambush-dhs</link>
      <description>A shooting involving an ICE agent unfolded in Minneapolis late Wednesday after a suspect allegedly assaulted a federal officer with a shovel, authorities said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis ICE shooting: Federal law enforcement involved in north Minneapolis incident, city says</title>
      <link>https://www.fox9.com/news/minneapolis-ice-shooting-federal-law-enforcement-north-minneapolis-jan-14</link>
      <description>A person from Venezuela was shot by ICE in north Minneapolis Wednesday night after federal officials say they attacked an officer following a traffic stop. This comes exactly a week after an ICE officer fatally shot Renee Good. Find live updates on the incide…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 02:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>FOX 9</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Omar, Dems demand Noem impeachment, paint Minnesota woman shot by ICE as 'poet' who chose 'love'</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/omar-dems-demand-noem-impeachment-paint-minnesota-woman-shot-ice-poet-chose-love</link>
      <description>Democrats demand the impeachment of Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem after the fatal ICE-involved shooting of Renee Nicole Good in Minnesota.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The FBI Thinks Renee Good's Anti-ICE Activism Is Relevant in Deciding Whether Killing Her Was Justified</title>
      <link>https://reason.com/2026/01/14/the-fbi-thinks-renee-goods-anti-ice-activism-is-relevant-in-deciding-whether-killing-her-was-justified/</link>
      <description>It is hard to see how, since that question hinges on what happened the morning that an ICE agent shot her.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Reason</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE’s Violence Is “By Design” Under Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2026/01/former-ice-workers-trump-violence-by-design-renee-good/</link>
      <description>After a US Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killed Renée Good in Minneapolis last Wednesday, Trump administration officials were quick to come out in the agent’s defense. Violent interactions with the public aren’t surprising, a former ICE…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mother Jones</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BACOLOD: Negros Or police shootings draw scrutiny, demand accountability</title>
      <link>https://rpnradio.com/bacolod-negros-or-police-shootings-draw-scrutiny-demand-accountability/</link>
      <description>BACOLOD CITY — Police Brig. Gen. Arnold Thomas Ibay, director of the Police Regional Office–Negros Island Region, said justice will prevail for the victims of two shooting incidents involving a police officer that left a civilian and three policemen dead, inc…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 02:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Rpnradio.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man who threatened bystanders, cops in hospital before police shooting was former NYPD officer</title>
      <link>https://www.police1.com/man-fatally-shot-by-police-after-brandishing-edged-weapon-in-hospital-was-former-nypd-officer</link>
      <description>The suspect barricaded himself in a hospital room with the weapon before cutting himself and threatening to injure others</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Police1.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over the top? ICE agent shoots soccer mom, blames ‘domestic terrorism’</title>
      <link>https://www.rt.com/news/630866-us-ice-soccer-mom/</link>
      <description>The death of an apparently innocent woman at the hands of immigration police does no favors to the split plaguing American society Read Full Article at RT.com</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>RT</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal Expert Analysis: ICE Agent Was Fully in His Rights to Shoot Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://www.westernjournal.com/legal-expert-analysis-ice-agents-fully-rights-shoot-renee-good/</link>
      <description>An ICE agent fatally shot 37-year-old Renee Good inside her vehicle after she obstructed an immigration enforcement operation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Westernjournal.com</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
