<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 06:49:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>BACOLOD: Negros Or police shootings draw scrutiny, demand accountability</title>
      <link>https://rpnradio.com/bacolod-negros-or-police-shootings-draw-scrutiny-demand-accountability/</link>
      <description>BACOLOD CITY — Police Brig. Gen. Arnold Thomas Ibay, director of the Police Regional Office–Negros Island Region, said justice will prevail for the victims of two shooting incidents involving a police officer that left a civilian and three policemen dead, inc…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 02:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Rpnradio.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man who threatened bystanders, cops in hospital before police shooting was former NYPD officer</title>
      <link>https://www.police1.com/man-fatally-shot-by-police-after-brandishing-edged-weapon-in-hospital-was-former-nypd-officer</link>
      <description>The suspect barricaded himself in a hospital room with the weapon before cutting himself and threatening to injure others</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Police1.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeffries says DHS Secretary Noem 'should be run out of town' amid ICE shooting backlash</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/jeffries-says-dhs-secretary-noem-should-be-run-out-of-town-ice-shooting-fallout</link>
      <description>The top House Democrat is accusing the DHS secretary of &quot;depraved indifference&quot; after an ICE agent shot U.S. citizen Renee Nicole Good during a Minneapolis operation.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 23:36:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump dodges on ICE immunity claim after agent kills Minnesota mother</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/ice-2674875260/</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump appeared confused and evasive when pressed about claims that an ICE agent who fatally shot 37-year-old Renee Nicole Good is shielded from prosecution, delivering a rambling response that left reporters stunned. The comments followed Vic…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 23:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bill Ackman Gave $10,000 to ICE Agent GoFundMe Created by User Linked to Nazi Salute Image (Jacqueline Sweet/The Intercept)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260112/p128</link>
      <description>Jacqueline Sweet / The Intercept:
Bill Ackman Gave $10,000 to ICE Agent GoFundMe Created by User Linked to Nazi Salute Image  —  After a U.S. Immigrations and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killed Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis last week, rival GoFund…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 23:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Is in Mourning. It’s Also Very, Very Pissed Off</title>
      <link>http://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-features/minneapolis-renee-nicole-good-grief-anger-1235498385/</link>
      <description>In the hours after an ICE officer shot and killed Rennee Nicole Good, the city came together — and found a difficult balance of grief and rage.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Rolling Stone</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over the top? ICE agent shoots soccer mom, blames ‘domestic terrorism’</title>
      <link>https://www.rt.com/news/630866-us-ice-soccer-mom/</link>
      <description>The death of an apparently innocent woman at the hands of immigration police does no favors to the split plaguing American society Read Full Article at RT.com</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>RT</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crowd yells ‘cowards!’ after federal agents crash into a car and fire tear gas in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.bostonherald.com/2026/01/12/federal-officers-crash-car-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>The scene Monday was just a few blocks from where an immigration officer fatally shot Renee Good last week.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 20:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Boston Herald</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manitoba Tories suspend board member over online comments following fatal ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/manitoba/tories-suspend-patrick-allard-comments-ice-shooting-9.7042336</link>
      <description>The Tories are distancing themselves from a board member over social media comments he made after a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent fatally shot an American woman in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 19:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Billboard next to Southern California highway hijacked with pro-ICE messaging</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4361721/posts</link>
      <description>A billboard next to a Southern California freeway was hijacked with pro-ICE messaging and a chilling remark about the fatal federal officer-involved shooting of Renee Good.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump Totally Changes Excuse for Why Renee Good Deserved to Get Shot</title>
      <link>https://newrepublic.com/post/205161/donald-trump-minnesota-ice-shooting-renee-good-disrespectful</link>
      <description>President Donald Trump suggested that being “disrespectful” toward law enforcement justifies the deadly use of force. Speaking to reporters on Air Force One Sunday, Trump offered a new excuse for why an ICE officer shot and killed Renee Good in Minneapolis: S…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 15:16:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The New Republic</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Footage shows tense standoff before deadly police shooting in St. Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.wftv.com/news/local/footage-shows-tense-standoff-before-deadly-police-shooting-st-cloud/73SITMX34NBTDHYDOO4UTQDG7E/</link>
      <description>Police in Saint Cloud released video of a deadly officer-involved shooting that happened last month.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WFTV Orlando</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Constitutional crisis in a nutshell': Lawyer calls out JD Vance's latest 'lie'</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/jd-vance-2674873534/</link>
      <description>A prominent voting rights lawyer slammed Vice President JD Vance on Sunday for his latest &quot;lie&quot; about the lethal shooting in Minneapolis. Last week, an Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killed 37-year-old Renee Good as she was in her car tr…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump admin sending more agents to Minneapolis despite outrage over fatal shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/trump-admin-deploys-more-federal-agents-to-minneapolis/106219476</link>
      <description>US Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem says hundreds more federal agents are heading to Minneapolis, brushing aside demands by the city's Democratic leaders to leave after an immigration officer fatally shot a female protester.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News (AU)</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrities protest ICE on Golden Globes red carpet</title>
      <link>https://www.the-independent.com/arts-entertainment/films/news/golden-globes-anti-ice-protest-pins-b2898480.html</link>
      <description>Mark Ruffalo is among the names wearing a pin at the ceremony paying tribute to Renee Good after she was shot by ICE agents earlier this week</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 23:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The-independent.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump admin sends more agents to Minneapolis despite furor over woman’s killing</title>
      <link>https://www.digitaljournal.com/world/trump-admin-sends-more-agents-to-minneapolis-despite-furor-over-womans-killing/article</link>
      <description>US Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem said Sunday that hundreds more federal agents were heading to Minneapolis, brushing aside demands by the city’s Democratic leaders to leave after an immigration officer fatally shot a woman protester. In multiple TV …</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 21:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Digital Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kristi Noem Vows ‘Hundreds More’ ICE Agents Heading to Minnesota: It’s ‘Ground Zero’ for ‘Protecting Criminals’</title>
      <link>https://www.mediaite.com/politics/kristi-noem-vows-hundreds-more-ice-agents-heading-to-minnesota-its-ground-zero-for-protecting-criminals/</link>
      <description>DHS Secretary Kristi Noem announced “hundreds” of ICE agents are being sent to Minnesota today and tomorrow during an appearance on Sunday Morning Futures with Maria Bartiromo on Fox News. Their arrival comes days after an ICE agent shot and killed 37-year-ol…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 19:26:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mediaite</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHS shares new video of minutes before ICE shooting of Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://www.wgal.com/article/dhs-video-minutes-before-ice-shooting-renee-good/69966509</link>
      <description>New video shows the minutes before an ICE agent shot and killed Renee Good, showing her car partially blocking the street while several cars are able to pass it.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 14:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WGAL Susquehanna Valley Pa.</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-ICE protests erupt across Colorado after fatal Minnesota shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.denverpost.com/2026/01/10/colorado-anti-ice-protests-minnesota-shooting/</link>
      <description>Protests over immigration enforcement broke out across Colorado on Saturday after fatal and nonfatal officer-involved shootings in Minneapolis and Portland.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Denver Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NBA Coach Steve Kerr Condemns ICE for Minnesota ‘Murder’ and Trump Adminstration’s ‘Shameful’ Response</title>
      <link>https://www.mediaite.com/media/sports/nba-coach-steve-kerr-condemns-ice-for-minnesota-murder-and-trump-adminstrations-shameful-response/</link>
      <description>Warriors coach Steve Kerr accused ICE of &quot;commit[ing] murder&quot; when an agent shot and killed protestor Renee Good in Minnesota
The post NBA Coach Steve Kerr Condemns ICE for Minnesota ‘Murder’ and Trump Adminstration’s ‘Shameful’ Response first appeared on Med…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mediaite</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tom Emmer pushes back on suggestion that Minnesota anti-ICE protesters have been peaceful</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/media/tom-emmer-pushes-back-suggestion-minnesota-anti-ice-protesters-have-been-peaceful</link>
      <description>Minneapolis protests continue after an ICE agent fatally shot a woman, with House Majority Whip Tom Emmer blaming Democratic leaders for ongoing tensions in the city.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controversy surrounding ICE killing incident in Minneapolis deepens as new footage of deadly encounter released</title>
      <link>https://www.globalsecurity.org/security/library/news/2026/01/sec-260110-globaltimes01.htm</link>
      <description>Controversy surrounding the incident in which a US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) officer fatally shot a mother of three Renee Nicole Good continued on Saturday. The White House on Friday reposted on social media a video taken from the cellphone of…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 09:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Globalsecurity.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal Expert Analysis: ICE Agent Was Fully in His Rights to Shoot Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://www.westernjournal.com/legal-expert-analysis-ice-agents-fully-rights-shoot-renee-good/</link>
      <description>An ICE agent fatally shot 37-year-old Renee Good inside her vehicle after she obstructed an immigration enforcement operation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Westernjournal.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trumpist lies about this ICE outrage demand a fierce response — including murder charges</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/raw-investigates/ice-shooting-2674862902/</link>
      <description>In Minneapolis, Minnesota, a masked Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent shot and killed another person, the 14
th
 ICE shooting under Trump to date
.Flexing Gestapo power in broad daylight, the agent shot a woman at close range
 as she was driving a…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Minnesota prosecute the federal immigration officer who just killed a woman?</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4361120/posts</link>
      <description>A federal officer shot and killed a woman in Minneapolis on Wednesday, shortly after the Trump administration deployed thousands of immigration agents to the city. Although the full circumstances of the killing remain unclear, video of the shooting shows an o…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 02:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Married couple shot by federal agents in Portland, FBI investigating</title>
      <link>https://www.israelnationalnews.com/news/420635</link>
      <description>Husband and wife hospitalized after being shot by federal agents in Portland, with the FBI leading the investigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 01:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Israelnationalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Ross military past, father and Iraq connection explained amid Minneapolis ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/jonathan-ross-military-past-father-and-iraq-connection-explained-amid-minneapolis-ice-shooting-renee-nicole-good-ice-officer-june-2025-arrest-in-bloomington/articleshow/126422528.cms</link>
      <description>Jonathan Ross military past, father and Iraq connection has come under focus after the ICE officer fatally shot Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis. Reports link Ross to prior ICE incidents, a possible military background, family Iraq references, and ongoing inv…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Times of India</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cops Are Taught Not to Shoot Into Cars. ICE Keeps Doing It Anyway.</title>
      <link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2026/01/renee-good-minneapolis-shooting-ice-trump-cops-taught-not-shoot-at-cars/</link>
      <description>On Wednesday, a masked federal immigration officer killed Renee Nicole Good, a 37-year-old mother and poet, shooting her at point-blank range in her car.  The incident, which has made headlines across the nation, is far from the first time immigration officer…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mother Jones</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis: Attempted ramming attack, suspect eliminated</title>
      <link>https://www.israelnationalnews.com/news/420554</link>
      <description>US officials say an ICE officer shot and killed a suspect who allegedly tried to ram federal agents with a vehicle during an enforcement operation in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Israelnationalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man with machete shot and killed by police, who then find 3 more dead inside home: officials</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/man-machete-shot-killed-police-find-3-more-dead-inside-home-officials</link>
      <description>Police shot and killed an individual armed with a knife in the Garden State on Monday, the New Jersey state attorney general's office noted in a press release.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 19:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-duty deputy shot and killed while working security job in Texas, suspect apprehended</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/off-duty-deputy-shot-killed-while-working-security-job-texas-suspect-apprehended</link>
      <description>Off-duty Caldwell County deputy shot and killed while working security at a nightclub in Austin, Texs. Police investigation ongoing.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 22:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-duty deputy shot and killed while working security job in Texas, suspect remains at large</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/off-duty-deputy-shot-killed-while-working-security-job-texas-suspect-remains-large</link>
      <description>Off-duty Caldwell County deputy shot and killed while working security at a nightclub in Austin, Texs. Police investigation ongoing.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 22:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
