<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:47:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>US ICE agent shoots mother of 3: Who is Clyde Emmons, the man behind the cryptic viral post calling the woman 'a domestic terrorist'</title>
      <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/etimes/trending/us-ice-agent-shoots-mother-of-3-who-is-clyde-emmons-the-man-behind-the-cryptic-viral-post-calling-the-woman-a-domestic-terrorist/articleshow/126519302.cms</link>
      <description>A man named Clyde Emmons launched a fundraiser for an ICE agent involved in a fatal shooting. The agent, Jonathan Ross, shot Renee Nicole Good during an operation. Emmons' fundraiser, intended to support Ross, has drawn significant attention and backlash onli…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 06:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Times of India</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Artist Is Chanting Renee Good’s Last Words Before She Was Fatally Shot by ICE Officer Outside the Agency’s New York Field Office</title>
      <link>https://www.artnews.com/art-news/news/artist-renee-good-last-words-new-york-ice-office-1234769759/</link>
      <description>&quot;As an immigrant and once undocumented American, I carry these words as both personal testimony and social critique,&quot; said artist Maria De Victoria.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 22:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ARTnews</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota protesters square off with ICE after deadly shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/video/newsfeed/2026/1/13/minnesota-protesters-square-off-with-ice-after-deadly-shooting</link>
      <description>Protesters in Minneapolis, Minnesota confronted federal agents days after an ICE agent fatally shot Renee Nicole Good.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Al Jazeera English</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Say Shooting by ICE Agent Was Not Justified</title>
      <link>https://politicalwire.com/2026/01/13/most-say-shooting-by-ice-agent-was-not-justified/</link>
      <description>Days after an ICE agent fatally shot a Minneapolis woman in an incident that was captured on video, voters say by 82% to 18% say they have seen a video and 53% think the shooting was not justified and 35% think it was justified, and 12% did not offer an opini…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 19:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Politicalwire.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE Agents Escalate Rampage in Minneapolis Streets, on Video</title>
      <link>https://www.tmz.com/2026/01/13/ice-agents-arrests-minneapolis-chaos/</link>
      <description>Federal agents are massively escalating their aggressive tactics in Minneapolis Tuesday as witnesses record absolute mayhem breaking out in the streets across the city ... a week after an ICE agent killed a woman on camera. Check out this intense…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:55:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>TMZ</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Day of reckoning, retribution’ coming to Minnesota amid ICE outrage: Trump</title>
      <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2026/1/13/day-of-reckoning-retribution-coming-to-minnesota-amid-ice-outrage-trump</link>
      <description>US president issues latest threat to midwestern state, where protests have continued after ICE agent killed woman.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Al Jazeera English</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FBI Now Investigating Past History of Minnesota Woman Killed by ICE</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4361890/posts</link>
      <description>Renee Good, the Minnesota mother killed by ICE agents last week, is being investigated by the FBI for ties to activist groups. The New York Times reports that federal agents are looking into whether Good was involved with organizations protesting the Trump ad…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BACOLOD: Negros Or police shootings draw scrutiny, demand accountability</title>
      <link>https://rpnradio.com/bacolod-negros-or-police-shootings-draw-scrutiny-demand-accountability/</link>
      <description>BACOLOD CITY — Police Brig. Gen. Arnold Thomas Ibay, director of the Police Regional Office–Negros Island Region, said justice will prevail for the victims of two shooting incidents involving a police officer that left a civilian and three policemen dead, inc…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 02:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Rpnradio.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man who threatened bystanders, cops in hospital before police shooting was former NYPD officer</title>
      <link>https://www.police1.com/man-fatally-shot-by-police-after-brandishing-edged-weapon-in-hospital-was-former-nypd-officer</link>
      <description>The suspect barricaded himself in a hospital room with the weapon before cutting himself and threatening to injure others</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Police1.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over the top? ICE agent shoots soccer mom, blames ‘domestic terrorism’</title>
      <link>https://www.rt.com/news/630866-us-ice-soccer-mom/</link>
      <description>The death of an apparently innocent woman at the hands of immigration police does no favors to the split plaguing American society Read Full Article at RT.com</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>RT</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crowd yells ‘cowards!’ after federal agents crash into a car and fire tear gas in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.bostonherald.com/2026/01/12/federal-officers-crash-car-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>The scene Monday was just a few blocks from where an immigration officer fatally shot Renee Good last week.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 20:28:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Boston Herald</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Billboard next to Southern California highway hijacked with pro-ICE messaging</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4361721/posts</link>
      <description>A billboard next to a Southern California freeway was hijacked with pro-ICE messaging and a chilling remark about the fatal federal officer-involved shooting of Renee Good.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Footage shows tense standoff before deadly police shooting in St. Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.wftv.com/news/local/footage-shows-tense-standoff-before-deadly-police-shooting-st-cloud/73SITMX34NBTDHYDOO4UTQDG7E/</link>
      <description>Police in Saint Cloud released video of a deadly officer-involved shooting that happened last month.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 11:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WFTV Orlando</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Constitutional crisis in a nutshell': Lawyer calls out JD Vance's latest 'lie'</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/jd-vance-2674873534/</link>
      <description>A prominent voting rights lawyer slammed Vice President JD Vance on Sunday for his latest &quot;lie&quot; about the lethal shooting in Minneapolis. Last week, an Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killed 37-year-old Renee Good as she was in her car tr…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 01:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump admin sending more agents to Minneapolis despite outrage over fatal shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/trump-admin-deploys-more-federal-agents-to-minneapolis/106219476</link>
      <description>US Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem says hundreds more federal agents are heading to Minneapolis, brushing aside demands by the city's Democratic leaders to leave after an immigration officer fatally shot a female protester.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:40:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News (AU)</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump admin sends more agents to Minneapolis despite furor over woman’s killing</title>
      <link>https://www.digitaljournal.com/world/trump-admin-sends-more-agents-to-minneapolis-despite-furor-over-womans-killing/article</link>
      <description>US Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem said Sunday that hundreds more federal agents were heading to Minneapolis, brushing aside demands by the city’s Democratic leaders to leave after an immigration officer fatally shot a woman protester. In multiple TV …</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 21:52:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Digital Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHS shares new video of minutes before ICE shooting of Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://www.wgal.com/article/dhs-video-minutes-before-ice-shooting-renee-good/69966509</link>
      <description>New video shows the minutes before an ICE agent shot and killed Renee Good, showing her car partially blocking the street while several cars are able to pass it.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 14:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WGAL Susquehanna Valley Pa.</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal Expert Analysis: ICE Agent Was Fully in His Rights to Shoot Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://www.westernjournal.com/legal-expert-analysis-ice-agents-fully-rights-shoot-renee-good/</link>
      <description>An ICE agent fatally shot 37-year-old Renee Good inside her vehicle after she obstructed an immigration enforcement operation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Westernjournal.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trumpist lies about this ICE outrage demand a fierce response — including murder charges</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/raw-investigates/ice-shooting-2674862902/</link>
      <description>In Minneapolis, Minnesota, a masked Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent shot and killed another person, the 14
th
 ICE shooting under Trump to date
.Flexing Gestapo power in broad daylight, the agent shot a woman at close range
 as she was driving a…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Minnesota prosecute the federal immigration officer who just killed a woman?</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4361120/posts</link>
      <description>A federal officer shot and killed a woman in Minneapolis on Wednesday, shortly after the Trump administration deployed thousands of immigration agents to the city. Although the full circumstances of the killing remain unclear, video of the shooting shows an o…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 02:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Married couple shot by federal agents in Portland, FBI investigating</title>
      <link>https://www.israelnationalnews.com/news/420635</link>
      <description>Husband and wife hospitalized after being shot by federal agents in Portland, with the FBI leading the investigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 01:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Israelnationalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Ross military past, father and Iraq connection explained amid Minneapolis ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/jonathan-ross-military-past-father-and-iraq-connection-explained-amid-minneapolis-ice-shooting-renee-nicole-good-ice-officer-june-2025-arrest-in-bloomington/articleshow/126422528.cms</link>
      <description>Jonathan Ross military past, father and Iraq connection has come under focus after the ICE officer fatally shot Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis. Reports link Ross to prior ICE incidents, a possible military background, family Iraq references, and ongoing inv…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Times of India</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cops Are Taught Not to Shoot Into Cars. ICE Keeps Doing It Anyway.</title>
      <link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2026/01/renee-good-minneapolis-shooting-ice-trump-cops-taught-not-shoot-at-cars/</link>
      <description>On Wednesday, a masked federal immigration officer killed Renee Nicole Good, a 37-year-old mother and poet, shooting her at point-blank range in her car.  The incident, which has made headlines across the nation, is far from the first time immigration officer…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mother Jones</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis: Attempted ramming attack, suspect eliminated</title>
      <link>https://www.israelnationalnews.com/news/420554</link>
      <description>US officials say an ICE officer shot and killed a suspect who allegedly tried to ram federal agents with a vehicle during an enforcement operation in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Israelnationalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man with machete shot and killed by police, who then find 3 more dead inside home: officials</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/man-machete-shot-killed-police-find-3-more-dead-inside-home-officials</link>
      <description>Police shot and killed an individual armed with a knife in the Garden State on Monday, the New Jersey state attorney general's office noted in a press release.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 19:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
