<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 07:12:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>After police shootings, Mamdani faces new pressure to overhaul NYC’s mental health crisis response</title>
      <link>https://gothamist.com/news/after-police-shootings-mamdani-faces-new-pressure-to-overhaul-nycs-mental-health-crisis-response</link>
      <description>Two 911 calls for help ended with police at the door. Experts say dispatch rules and limited B-HEARD coverage leave few non-police options.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Gothamist</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SWAT units shoot man barricaded in Lower Burrell home, accused of shooting at officers</title>
      <link>https://www.wpxi.com/news/local/swat-units-shoot-man-barricaded-lower-burrell-home-accused-shooting-officers/DUFVUKMRZBGCLGEJ3N7NQ3TTHI/</link>
      <description>Westmoreland County detectives are investigating an officer-involved shooting in Lower Burrell on Saturday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 04:55:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WPXI Pittsburgh</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cops Fatally Shoot Man With Knife at Arc de Triomphe</title>
      <link>https://www.newser.com/story/383738/cops-fatally-shoot-man-with-knife-at-arc-de-triomphe.html</link>
      <description>A man wielding a knife and scissors was fatally shot by police in Paris on Friday when he tried to attack an officer during a ceremony at the city's Arc de Triomphe monument, officials said. The suspect, a French national born in 1978 who'd previously been co…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Newser</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feds Open Perjury Probe After ICE Officer Shot Venezuelan</title>
      <link>https://www.newser.com/story/383719/feds-open-perjury-probe-after-ice-officer-shot-venezuelan.html</link>
      <description>Federal authorities have opened a criminal probe into whether two immigration officers lied under oath about a shooting in Minneapolis last month, as all charges were dropped against two Venezuelan men. Immigration and Customs Enforcement Director Todd Lyons …</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Newser</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terror convict, recently released, shot dead by Paris police after alleged knife attack near Arc de Triomphe</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/world/terror-convict-recently-released-shot-dead-paris-police-alleged-knife-attack-near-arc-de-triomphe</link>
      <description>Police shot a man who allegedly tried to attack an officer with a knife in Paris. The suspect was recently released from prison after serving a terrorism-related sentence.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man shot dead after attacking police near Arc de Triomphe in Paris</title>
      <link>https://japantoday.com/category/world/man-shot-dead-after-attacking-police-near-arc-de-triomphe-in-paris</link>
      <description>A man who tried to attack a police ‌officer with a knife near the Arc de Triomphe in Paris on Friday ‌was shot by police and ⁠later died of his ⁠injuries, France's ⁠anti-terrorism prosecution office said. The police ‌officer was not harmed and no one ⁠else ⁠w…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 00:41:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Japan Today</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A powerful tool of resistance is already in your hands</title>
      <link>https://www.theverge.com/policy/879273/alex-pretti-ice-cbp-trump-free-speech</link>
      <description>In an eyewitness video analyzed frame by frame by The New York Times, Alex Pretti raises one hand and holds a phone in the other. Federal agents tackle him, and one appears to find and remove a gun holstered on his hip. Then, an agent shoots - and a second fo…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Verge</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man Shot By ICE Has All Charges Dropped As Officers Face Federal Probe</title>
      <link>https://www.huffpost.com/entry/julio-sosa-celis-charges-dropped_n_698f870de4b0b886fd32334b</link>
      <description>Kristi Noem painted the Venezuelan man as an attempted murderer, but new evidence is &quot;materially inconsistent&quot; with the allegations.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 22:01:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>HuffPost</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paris: Knife-wielding man shot by police at Arc de Triomphe</title>
      <link>https://www.dw.com/en/paris-knife-wielding-man-shot-by-police-at-arc-de-triomphe/a-75964622</link>
      <description>A man was shot and injured after attacking police during a ceremonial lighting of an eternal flame under the Paris landmark.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 19:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>DW (English)</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DOJ Drops Charges Against Two Minneapolis Men It Accused of Attacking ICE Agents</title>
      <link>https://minnesotareformer.com/2026/02/13/doj-drops-charges-against-two-men-accused-of-attacking-federal-agent-in-ice-shooting/</link>
      <description>The federal government has shifted its view on the January 14 incident, when an agent shot one of the men.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 18:53:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Minnesotareformer.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prosecutor Seeks Dismissal of Charges Against Man Shot by ICE - The New York Times</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180786416</link>
      <description>Prosecutor Seeks Dismissal of Charges Against Man Shot by ICEThe New York Times Justice department moves to drop charges against men accused of hitting ICE officer in MinnesotaThe Guardian Government moves to dismiss charges against men in ICE-involved shooti…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 10:12:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Officer-involved shooting under investigation in Seattle’s Ballard neighborhood</title>
      <link>https://komonews.com/news/local/officer-involved-shooting-gun-violence-seattle-police-department-spd-law-enforcement-ballard-neighborhood-northwest-62nd-street-28th-avenue-west</link>
      <description>Seattle police are investigating an officer-involved shooting in the Ballard neighborhood Thursday evening.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 02:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>KOMO News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lawyers of Chicago woman shot by federal agents say documents show how DHS lies about investigations</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/lawyers-of-chicago-woman-shot-by-federal-agents-say-documents-show-how-dhs-lies-about-investigations</link>
      <description>Marimar Martinez, a teaching assistant and U.S. citizen, was shot five times by a Border Patrol agent in October while in her vehicle. She was charged with a felony after Homeland Security officials accused her of trying to ram agents with her vehicle. But th…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:13:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>PBS</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE accuses Honduran alien of ramming law enforcement vehicle before agent shoots out tires</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/ice-accuses-honduran-alien-ramming-law-enforcement-vehicle-before-agent-shoots-out-tires</link>
      <description>Dramatic video shows ICE agent drawing gun after Honduran illegal alien allegedly rammed a law enforcement vehicle during an arrest attempt in New Jersey.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 12:58:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lawyers of Chicago woman shot by federal agents say documents show how DHS lies about investigations - AP News</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180777398</link>
      <description>Lawyers of Chicago woman shot by federal agents say documents show how DHS lies about investigationsAP News Border patrol chief praised federal agent who shot US citizen in ChicagoThe Guardian Body camera footage and texts reveal details of Border Patrol agen…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 01:52:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A sword in the van driven by the 17-year-old Jaffna student who was shot dead after driving ignoring orders.</title>
      <link>https://english.gossiplankanews.com/2026/02/a-sword-in-van-driven-by-17-year-old.html</link>
      <description>A 17-year-old youth has died after police opened fire on a suspicious van that failed to stop when ordered by police in the Allapiddy area of the Kayts Police Division in Jaffna yesterday (10) morning.
&lt;!--gossip-below-article-Rs--&gt; (adsbygoogle = window.ads…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 03:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Gossiplankanews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 sent to hospital following officer-involved shooting in Hickory</title>
      <link>https://www.wsoctv.com/news/local/1-sent-hospital-following-officer-involved-shooting-hickory/BYLBESKQEZEWHKKHPWPCL6GF4E/</link>
      <description>Officers are on leave and a suspect is in the hospital after a shooting outside a church.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 16:44:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WSOC Charlotte</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police investigating officer-involved shooting at apartment in northeast Atlanta</title>
      <link>https://www.wsbtv.com/news/police-investigating-officer-involved-shooting-apartment-northeast-atlanta/U3YO74GMBJH33BQDT3TCSP2III/</link>
      <description>The Atlanta Police Department is investigating an officer-involved shooting in northeast Atlanta.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 14:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WSB Atlanta</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Senior Russian officer shot in Moscow in apparent assassination attempt</title>
      <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2026/2/6/senior-russian-officer-shot-in-moscow-in-apparent-assassination-attempt</link>
      <description>An unidentified individual has shot Lieutenant General Alekseyev before fleeing the scene, authorities say.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 09:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Al Jazeera English</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulse-Pounding Body Cam Footage Shows the Moment NYPD Officer Shoots Knife-Wielding Man in Self-Defense – NYC Mayor Mamdani Meets with Perp and Demands He Face NO CHARGES (VIDEO)</title>
      <link>https://www.thegatewaypundit.com/2026/02/pulse-pounding-body-cam-footage-shows-moment-nypd/</link>
      <description>Terrifying bodycam footage emerged this week showing the moment an NYPD officer shot a person in self-defense, prompting an outlandish reaction from New York City Mayor Zohran Mamdani.
The post Pulse-Pounding Body Cam Footage Shows the Moment NYPD Officer Sho…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Thegatewaypundit.com</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
