<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 07:02:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Good Morning, News: MultCo DA Doesn't Wanna FAFO, Police Shooting in the Pearl, Breaking: Democracy Dies in Darkness, and Shorting the Bitcoin Economy</title>
      <link>https://www.portlandmercury.com/good-morning-news/2026/02/06/48299131/good-morning-news-multco-da-doesnt-wanna-fafo-police-shooting-in-the-pearl-breaking-democracy-dies-in-darkness-and-shorting-the-bitcoin</link>
      <description>by Mercury Staff
 
 
 
 If you appreciate the Mercury's interesting and useful news &amp; culture reporting, consider making a small monthly contribution to support our editorial team. Your donation is tax-deductible. You can also subscribe and have our papers de…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Portland Mercury</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Effort to Dispatch Mental Health Workers Ends in Police Response 86% of the Time</title>
      <link>https://www.thecity.nyc/2026/02/06/jabez-chakraborty-911-mamdani-b-heard-police-mental-health/</link>
      <description>Reacting to the police shooting of Jabez Chakraborty, Mayor Mamdani plans to speed up the expansion of community responders, but a CITY analysis of existing efforts found that 911 dispatchers call in cops in the vast majority of cases.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 12:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>THE CITY</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mamdani-Tisch Relationship Isn’t Built to Last</title>
      <link>http://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/mamdani-tisch-police-shooting-nyc.html</link>
      <description>A police shooting was the first test of the uneasy equilibrium between Mayor Zohran Mamdani and NYPD Commissioner Jessica Tisch. It certainly won’t be the last.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 10:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Magazine</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Senior Russian officer shot in Moscow in apparent assassination attempt</title>
      <link>https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2026/2/6/senior-russian-officer-shot-in-moscow-in-apparent-assassination-attempt</link>
      <description>An unidentified individual has shot Lieutenant General Alekseyev before fleeing the scene, authorities say.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 09:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Al Jazeera English</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man Fatally Shot By Police in NW Portland</title>
      <link>https://www.portlandmercury.com/news/2026/02/05/48298319/man-fatally-shot-by-police-in-nw-portland</link>
      <description>Police say the victim tried to shoot security guards at a grocery store five days earlier, leaving behind a shotgun with shells containing &quot;threatening&quot; messages naming Donald Trump.
 
 by Courtney Vaughn
 
 
 
 Portland Police officers shot and killed a man …</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 02:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Portland Mercury</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pilot, trooper killed in helicopter crash during officer-involved shooting</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4365609/posts</link>
      <description>A helicopter responding to assist officers in Arizona with an active shooter situation crashed, killing both the pilot and a trooper who was a paramedic on board, authorities said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:10:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Winnipeg officer on scene when Eishia Hudson was killed tells inquest he thought he'd be hit by stolen vehicle</title>
      <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/manitoba/eishia-hudson-inquest-officer-testimony-9.7076117</link>
      <description>A Winnipeg officer who was on the scene of a fatal police shooting of 16-year-old Eishia Hudson told an inquest into her fatal shooting by police he thought his life was in danger.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:10:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mayor Mamdani Gets His First Big Test And All Sides In Officer-Involved Shooting Aren’t Happy With Him</title>
      <link>https://dailycaller.com/2026/02/05/zohran-mamdani-jabez-chakraborty-police-shooting-new-york-city/</link>
      <description>New York City Mayor Zohran Mamdani is catching heat for trying to play both sides of an officer-involved shooting.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:11:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Daily Caller</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Good Morning, News: Trump-Loving Suspect Indicted for Police Shooting, 2026 Winter Olympics Begin Friday, and Is Oregon Ready for Waymos?</title>
      <link>https://www.portlandmercury.com/good-morning-news/2026/02/05/48295898/good-morning-news-trump-loving-suspect-indicted-for-police-shooting-2026-winter-olympics-begin-friday-and-is-oregon-ready-for-waymos</link>
      <description>by Suzette Smith
 
 
 
 If you appreciate the Mercury's interesting and useful news &amp; culture reporting, consider making a small monthly contribution to support our editorial team. Your donation is tax-deductible. You can also subscribe and have our papers de…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Portland Mercury</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bodycam shows NYPD officer shooting man with knife as Mamdani calls for no criminal charges</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4365551/posts</link>
      <description>The New York City Police Department released body camera footage showing the moment an officer shot a mentally ill man who was allegedly charging him with a knife amid calls from Mayor Zohran Mamdani for mental health treatment instead of criminal charges. Ja…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulse-Pounding Body Cam Footage Shows the Moment NYPD Officer Shoots Knife-Wielding Man in Self-Defense – NYC Mayor Mamdani Meets with Perp and Demands He Face NO CHARGES (VIDEO)</title>
      <link>https://www.thegatewaypundit.com/2026/02/pulse-pounding-body-cam-footage-shows-moment-nypd/</link>
      <description>Terrifying bodycam footage emerged this week showing the moment an NYPD officer shot a person in self-defense, prompting an outlandish reaction from New York City Mayor Zohran Mamdani.
The post Pulse-Pounding Body Cam Footage Shows the Moment NYPD Officer Sho…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 16:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Thegatewaypundit.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recording immigration agents in public is a constitutional right. Here’s what the law says.</title>
      <link>https://www.poynter.org/fact-checking/2026/is-it-legal-to-record-ice/</link>
      <description>A federal agent in Minnesota grabbed a woman’s phone as it recorded him approaching her Jan. 9, two days after a federal agent shot a U.S. citizen. “Have y’all not […]
The post Recording immigration agents in public is a constitutional right. Here’s what the …</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 11:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Poynter</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police helicopter crashes in Arizona after shooting involving officer</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/police-helicopter-crashes-in-arizona-after-shooting-involving-officer/</link>
      <description>A police helicopter crashed near the scene of what authorities in Flagstaff, Arizona called &quot;an active officer-involved shooting investigation,&quot; according to police in Page, Arizona.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heart-pounding bodycam footage shows moment NYPD cop shoots knife-wielding man with ‘history of mental issues’</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/02/04/us-news/heart-pounding-bodycam-footage-shows-moment-nypd-cop-shoots-knife-wielding-man/</link>
      <description>The Jan. 26 police shooting of schizophrenic man Jabez Chakraborty has prompted backlash from the family, and fueled a renewed push from Mayor Zohran Mamdani for his proposed Department of Community Safety to deal with mental health crises.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 21:46:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brothers of Renee Good, woman fatally shot by ICE, tell public forum 'what a beautiful American we have lost'</title>
      <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/renee-good-brothers-speak-ice-minneapolis-9.7073253</link>
      <description>Luke and Brent Ganger, Renee Good's brothers, spoke lovingly of their sister during a public forum hosted by U.S. Congressional Democrats to discuss the use of force by federal agents carrying out the Trump administration’s immigration crackdown. Good, a 37-y…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 03:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WATCH: Brothers of Renee Good, woman fatally shot by ICE, remember their sister with lawmakers</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/watch-brothers-of-renee-good-woman-fatally-shot-by-ice-remember-their-sister-with-lawmakers</link>
      <description>Luke Ganger and Brent Ganger spoke about the distress the family has felt since an Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent fatally shot the 37-year-old mother and U.S. citizen.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 23:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>PBS</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Smear campaign' exposed as DHS attacks on shot immigrants immediately unravel in court</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/smear-campaign-exposed-as-dhs-on-shot-immigrants-immediately-unravel-in-court/</link>
      <description>After a US Border Patrol Agent shot two Venezuelan immigrants in Portland, Oregon, in January, the Department of Homeland Security claimed
 that the two victims were “vicious Tren de Aragua gang members” who “weaponized their vehicle” against federal agents,…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'Smear Campaign' Detected as DHS Claims About Pair Shot by Border Patrol Unravel in Court</title>
      <link>https://www.commondreams.org/news/border-patrol-portland-shooting</link>
      <description>After a US Border Patrol Agent shot two Venezuelan immigrants in Portland, Oregon in January, the Department of Homeland Security claimed that the two victims were &quot;vicious Tren de Aragua gang members&quot; who &quot;weaponized their vehicle&quot; against federal agents, wh…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Common Dreams</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Minneapolis’s ICE Watch Network - One of the city’s protest organizations stoked a raging fire.</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-chat/4365248/posts</link>
      <description>n less than a month, two “ICE watchers” have been shot and killed by immigration enforcement agents in Minneapolis. On January 24, a federal agent shot and killed 37-year-old Alex Pretti, a Veterans Affairs ICU nurse. His death follows that of Renée Good, a 3…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:25:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alex Pretti’s death ruled homicide after Minneapolis shooting by federal agents</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4365188/posts</link>
      <description>The death of Alex Pretti, the Minneapolis man killed by federal agents, has been ruled a homicide, the Hennepin County medical examiner’s office said. Pretti was shot Jan. 24 during a chaotic encounter with federal immigration officers in Minneapolis. Citing …</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arizona man accused of human smuggling is a repeat offender who once 'threw rocks' at Army helicopter: docs</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/arizona-man-accused-human-smuggling-repeat-offender-who-once-threw-rocks-army-helicopter-docs</link>
      <description>Suspected human smuggler shot by federal agents near Arizona border is repeat offender, officials say. Patrick Schlegel allegedly fired at agents.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 13:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shooting in Georgia hotel room leaves 1 officer killed, another seriously wounded: 'Unprovoked attack'</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/shooting-georgia-hotel-room-leaves-1-officer-killed-another-seriously-wounded-unprovoked-attack</link>
      <description>A Georgia police officer was killed and another was wounded after a suspect allegedly opened fire in a hotel room as he was being questioned.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 08:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police officer killed, another critically wounded in shooting at Georgia hotel - ABC News</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180718578</link>
      <description>Police officer killed, another critically wounded in shooting at Georgia hotelABC News Gwinnett County officer dead, another officer injured in ‘unprovoked attack’ at hotelWSB-TV Gwinnett Police: Suspect who killed one officer, injured another had long crimin…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 03:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police officer killed, another critically wounded in shooting at Georgia hotel</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/police-officer-killed-critically-wounded-shooting-georgia-hotel-129755947</link>
      <description>Gunfire broke out after two officers were dispatched on a call reporting fraud.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 20:25:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s A Reason Many Police Dept’s Ban Shooting At Moving Vehicles: It Saves Lives Without Putting Officers In Greater Danger</title>
      <link>https://www.techdirt.com/2026/01/28/theres-a-reason-many-police-depts-ban-shooting-at-moving-vehicles-it-saves-lives-without-putting-officers-in-greater-danger/</link>
      <description>Minneapolis is once again the focus of debates about violence involving law enforcement after an Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killed Renee Nicole Good, a 37-year-old mother, in her car. The incident quickly prompted dueling narratives.…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 23:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Techdirt</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
