<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 06:52:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Why the Song Used in This ICE Recruitment Post Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.newser.com/story/382016/why-the-song-used-in-this-ice-recruitment-post-matters.html</link>
      <description>Two days after an ICE agent fatally shot a woman in Minneapolis, the Department of Homeland Security posted a recruitment call on Instagram set to a song embraced by neo-Nazi circles, Austin Campbell reports at the Intercept . The DHS post, aimed at hiring ne…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 21:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Newser</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whistles and walkie-talkies: Minneapolis keeps guard over schools amid ICE arrests</title>
      <link>https://japantoday.com/category/world/whistles-and-walkie-talkies-minneapolis-keeps-guard-over-schools-amid-ice-arrests1</link>
      <description>Peter Brown's gray mustache and beard were matted with ice as he stood watch on a frigid Friday afternoon outside Green Central Elementary, not far from where a U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent fatally shot Renee Good last week. Wearing a neon g…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 21:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Japan Today</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>911 transcripts, incident reports and videos show how an ICE agent shot a mother of 3 at ‘point blank range’</title>
      <link>https://krdo.com/news/2026/01/17/911-transcripts-incident-reports-and-videos-show-how-an-ice-agent-shot-a-mother-of-3-at-point-blank-range/</link>
      <description>By Zoe Sottile, Alisha Ebrahimji, Karina Tsui, CNN (CNN) — Emergency call logs and reports detailing last week’s fatal shooting of Renee Good by a</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>KRDO</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agent Who Shot Renee Good in Minneapolis Was Trained to Track and Apprehend Fugitives - The New York Times</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180604942</link>
      <description>Agent Who Shot Renee Good in Minneapolis Was Trained to Track and Apprehend FugitivesThe New York Times Video Analysis of ICE Shooting Sheds Light on Contested MomentsThe New York Times 911 transcripts, incident reports and videos show how an ICE agent shot a…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 09:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>911 transcripts, documents detail chaotic scene after ICE agent fatally shot Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/911-transcripts-documents-detail-chaotic-scene-after-ice-agent-fatally-shot-renee-good</link>
      <description>Renee Nicole Good suffered four gunshot wounds, according to newly released reports. Witnesses described the chaotic scene and said she was shot at 'point-blank' range.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 03:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family of man shot by ICE in Minneapolis disputes key aspects of DHS account - The Washington Post</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180603366</link>
      <description>Family of man shot by ICE in Minneapolis disputes key aspects of DHS accountThe Washington Post Federal Agent Shoots Man in Minneapolis, Prompting Tense ProtestsThe New York Times Minneapolis ICE shooting: Agent shoots immigrant, officer also hurtFOX 9 Minnea…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:32:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHS Releases More Details About the Three Violent Criminal Illegal Aliens Who Violently Beat a Law Enforcement Officer with Weapons - Homeland Security (.gov)</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180602950</link>
      <description>DHS Releases More Details About the Three Violent Criminal Illegal Aliens Who Violently Beat a Law Enforcement Officer with WeaponsHomeland Security (.gov) Federal Agent Shoots Man in Minneapolis, Prompting Tense ProtestsThe New York Times Family of man shot …</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 22:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump's Gestapo can be defanged</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/ice-gestapo-2674900738/</link>
      <description>ICE and Border Patrol agents must be reined in. I’ll tell you how in a moment.Since Renee Nicole Good’s death, clashes between ICE and the residents of Minneapolis have escalated. On Wednesday night, an ICE agent shot and wounded someone who, ICE claimed, was…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Putting a Stop to Trump's Gestapo Begins With You</title>
      <link>https://www.commondreams.org/opinion/trump-s-gestap</link>
      <description>Since Renee Good’s death, clashes between ICE and the residents of Minneapolis have escalated. On Wednesday night, an ICE agent shot and wounded someone who, ICE claimed, was fleeing arrest. (Sure, just like Good supposedly was trying to run them over when sh…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Common Dreams</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slog AM: Women Don't Want to Work at SPD, Trump Has the Nobel Peace Prize Now, ICE Teargassed Six Children in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.thestranger.com/slog-am/2026/01/16/80421664/slog-am-women-dont-want-to-work-at-spd-trump-has-the-nobel-peace-prize-now-ice-teargassed-six-children-in-minneapolis</link>
      <description>The Stranger's morning news roundup.
 
 by Nathalie Graham
 
 
 
 911 Calls from Good Shooting: The New York Times obtained the 911 calls and first responder reports from the day an ICE officer shot and killed Renee Good. The first ones came in at 9:38 a.m., …</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>TheStranger.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Police, Fire department reports reveal chaotic moments after ICE officer fatally shot Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/minneapolis-police-fire-department-reports-reveal-chaotic-moments-ice-rcna254362</link>
      <description>Official reports have shed light on the moments immediately after Renee Nicole Good was fatally shot by a U.S.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:41:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>NBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuelan shot in another federal agent action in U.S. Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.globalsecurity.org/security/library/news/2026/01/sec-260115-pdo02.htm</link>
      <description>A U.S. federal agent shot and injured a Venezuelan man Wednesday night in Minneapolis, the largest city in the state of Minnesota, said the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Globalsecurity.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Police Chief: Rioters 'Are Engaging in Unlawful Acts'</title>
      <link>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2026/01/15/minneapolis-police-chief-rioters-are-engaging-unlawful-acts/</link>
      <description>Minneapolis Police Chief Brian O'Hara noted rioters gathered in response to Wednesday's officer-involved shooting were &quot;engaging in unlawful acts.&quot;
The post Minneapolis Police Chief: Rioters ‘Are Engaging in Unlawful Acts’ appeared first on Breitbart.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Breitbart News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE officer shoots Venezuelan man in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.salon.com/2026/01/15/ice-officer-shoots-venezuelan-man-in-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>The shooting escalated tensions in the city as more protests erupted in response</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Salon</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHS says man shot in leg during Minneapolis scuffle, federal officer hospitalized (Tara Suter/The Hill)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260115/p72</link>
      <description>Tara Suter / The Hill:
DHS says man shot in leg during Minneapolis scuffle, federal officer hospitalized  —  The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) said that a federal officer shot a man during a scuffle in Minneapolis that involved multiple people — an in…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-ICE threat spray-painted on vehicle believed to be used by federal officers during Minneapolis unrest</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/anti-ice-threat-spray-painted-vehicle-believed-used-federal-officers-during-minneapolis-unrest</link>
      <description>Minneapolis rioters vandalized vehicles with anti-ICE messages and threats after a federal agent shot an illegal immigrant during an alleged ambush.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live updates: Minneapolis ICE shooting, tensions flare after man is shot in leg after allegedly assaulting federal agent | CNN</title>
      <link>https://www.cnn.com/us/live-news/minneapolis-ice-shooting-protests-01-15-26</link>
      <description>Law enforcement and demonstrators clashed last night near where a federal agent shot and injured a man after he allegedly assaulted the agent. The city is reeling over last week’s fatal shooting by an ICE agent of Renee Good sparked nationwide protests. Follo…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CNN</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overnight: 3rd DHS-Involved Shooting in a Week - Officer Shoots Suspect After Being Ambushed by Men With Pole Weapons</title>
      <link>https://www.westernjournal.com/overnight-3rd-dhs-involved-shooting-week-officer-shoots-suspect-ambushed-men-pole-weapons/</link>
      <description>&quot;As the officer was being ambushed and attacked by the two individuals, the original subject got loose and began striking the officer...&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Westernjournal.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal Agent Shoots Man In Minneapolis As Protests Continue</title>
      <link>https://www.forbes.com/sites/siladityaray/2026/01/15/federal-agent-shoots-man-in-minneapolis-as-protests-continue/</link>
      <description>The DHS claimed the agent fired a defensive shot after he was attacked with a shovel and broom stick.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Forbes</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tensions Flare in Minneapolis as Federal Agent Shoots A Venezuelan National Following Alleged Shovel and Broom Assault</title>
      <link>https://www.ibtimes.com/tensions-flare-minneapolis-federal-agent-shoots-venezuelan-national-following-alleged-shovel-3795367</link>
      <description>Tensions flare in Minneapolis as federal agent shoots Venezuelan national in leg after alleged assault during immigration stop. Protests clash with police amid second ICE incident in a week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>International Business Times</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis anti-ICE protesters hurl fireworks, rocks at officers following shooting of Venezuelan migrant</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/01/15/us-news/minneapolis-anti-ice-protesters-hurl-fireworks-rocks-at-officers-following-shooting-of-venezuela-migrant/</link>
      <description>A group of violent anti-ICE protesters hurled fireworks and rocks at officers on a Minneapolis block where a federal immigration agent shot a Venezuelan migrant in the leg hours earlier Wednesday night.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US federal agent shoots Venezuelan man in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.rte.ie/news/us/2026/0115/1553182-minneapolis-us/</link>
      <description>A Venezuelan national ⁠pursued by US immigration agents during a &quot;targeted&quot; traffic stop in Minneapolis was shot in the leg by a federal officer, authorities said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>RTE</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal Officer Shoots Person In Leg In Minneapolis, Officials Say</title>
      <link>https://www.huffpost.com/entry/immigration-enforcement-ice-shooting_n_69685d9ce4b0774cc19ee4d5</link>
      <description>A federal officer has shot a person in the leg in Minneapolis after being attacked with a shovel during an arrest Wednesday, DHS said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:33:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>HuffPost</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another ICE shooting in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.lawyersgunsmoneyblog.com/2026/01/another-ice-shooting-in-minneapolis</link>
      <description>The CNN breaking news headline is that “Fed Officer Shot Suspect in Minneapolis After Shovel Ambush.” Rumors are flying about the identity of the shooting victim but we’ll see. The neighborhood in question appears to be a residential area close to downtown. A…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Lawyersgunsmoneyblog.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE agent shoots Venezuelan national in Minneapolis after shovel attack during ambush: DHS</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/ice-agent-shoots-venezuelan-national-minneapolis-shovel-attack-ambush-dhs</link>
      <description>A shooting involving an ICE agent unfolded in Minneapolis late Wednesday after a suspect allegedly assaulted a federal officer with a shovel, authorities said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BACOLOD: Negros Or police shootings draw scrutiny, demand accountability</title>
      <link>https://rpnradio.com/bacolod-negros-or-police-shootings-draw-scrutiny-demand-accountability/</link>
      <description>BACOLOD CITY — Police Brig. Gen. Arnold Thomas Ibay, director of the Police Regional Office–Negros Island Region, said justice will prevail for the victims of two shooting incidents involving a police officer that left a civilian and three policemen dead, inc…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 02:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Rpnradio.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man who threatened bystanders, cops in hospital before police shooting was former NYPD officer</title>
      <link>https://www.police1.com/man-fatally-shot-by-police-after-brandishing-edged-weapon-in-hospital-was-former-nypd-officer</link>
      <description>The suspect barricaded himself in a hospital room with the weapon before cutting himself and threatening to injure others</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:33:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Police1.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Over the top? ICE agent shoots soccer mom, blames ‘domestic terrorism’</title>
      <link>https://www.rt.com/news/630866-us-ice-soccer-mom/</link>
      <description>The death of an apparently innocent woman at the hands of immigration police does no favors to the split plaguing American society Read Full Article at RT.com</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>RT</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
