<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 06:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>A list of LA protests this weekend over Renee Good, the woman shot and killed by ICE in Minnesota - LAist</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180561838</link>
      <description>A list of LA protests this weekend over Renee Good, the woman shot and killed by ICE in MinnesotaLAist Minneapolis ICE shooting: Anti-ICE protests held across Chicago area in response to deadly federal agent shooting of Renee GoodABC7 Chicago Protestors gathe…</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 04:53:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cellphone video fuels local debate over ICE agent's deadly force in Minneapolis shooting</title>
      <link>https://komonews.com/news/local/minneapolis-shooting-cellphone-video-fuels-local-debate-over-ice-agents-deadly-force-ice-border-patrol-protest-seattle-washington-state-pierce-county-sheriff-keith-swank</link>
      <description>Protests across the U.S. and locally in western Washington continue for a fourth day after an ICE agent shot and killed Renee Good.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 02:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>KOMO News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rallies in US after woman shot and killed by ICE agent</title>
      <link>https://www.rte.ie/news/us/2026/0111/1552485-rallies-in-us-after-woman-shot-and-killed-by-ice-agent/</link>
      <description>Thousands of demonstrators took to the streets of Minneapolis chanting the name of the woman killed by a federal agent in the city, amid widespread anger at use of force in the Trump administration's immigration crackdown.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 01:55:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>RTE</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protesters rally in Fayette County after woman shot, killed by ICE agent</title>
      <link>https://www.wpxi.com/news/local/protesters-rally-fayette-county-after-woman-shot-killed-by-ice-agent/6IOGU747N5CAFHU7F4HRANYCVQ/</link>
      <description>Protesters in Fayette County joined others across the country, demonstrating after an ICE agent shot and killed a woman in Minnesota.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 01:25:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WPXI Pittsburgh</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-ICE protests erupt across Colorado after fatal Minnesota shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.denverpost.com/2026/01/10/colorado-anti-ice-protests-minnesota-shooting/</link>
      <description>Protests over immigration enforcement broke out across Colorado on Saturday after fatal and nonfatal officer-involved shootings in Minneapolis and Portland.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Denver Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Colorado protesters rally in solidarity with Renee Good, killed by ICE agent in Minnesota</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/colorado/news/colorado-protesters-rally-renee-good-killed-ice-minnesota/</link>
      <description>Hundreds of protesters rallied across Colorado on Saturday in solidarity with Renee Good, the woman who was shot and killed by an ICE agent in Minneapolis on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>'We had whistles. They had guns,' says wife of Minnesota woman killed by ICE agent</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4361446/posts</link>
      <description>WASHINGTON (AP) — The wife of Renee Good, the woman shot and killed in her car by a federal immigration agent in Minneapolis, says the couple had stopped to support their neighbors on the day of the shooting and described the mother of three as leaving a lega…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 22:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NBA Coach Steve Kerr Condemns ICE for Minnesota ‘Murder’ and Trump Adminstration’s ‘Shameful’ Response</title>
      <link>https://www.mediaite.com/media/sports/nba-coach-steve-kerr-condemns-ice-for-minnesota-murder-and-trump-adminstrations-shameful-response/</link>
      <description>Warriors coach Steve Kerr accused ICE of &quot;commit[ing] murder&quot; when an agent shot and killed protestor Renee Good in Minnesota
The post NBA Coach Steve Kerr Condemns ICE for Minnesota ‘Murder’ and Trump Adminstration’s ‘Shameful’ Response first appeared on Med…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mediaite</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tom Emmer pushes back on suggestion that Minnesota anti-ICE protesters have been peaceful</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/media/tom-emmer-pushes-back-suggestion-minnesota-anti-ice-protesters-have-been-peaceful</link>
      <description>Minneapolis protests continue after an ICE agent fatally shot a woman, with House Majority Whip Tom Emmer blaming Democratic leaders for ongoing tensions in the city.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liberals Now Living In Fear Of Being Senselessly Shot By ICE Agents They’re Running Over</title>
      <link>https://babylonbee.com/news/liberals-now-living-in-fear-of-being-senselessly-shot-by-ice-agents-theyre-trying-to-run-over</link>
      <description>U.S. — Following the events in Minneapolis this past week, liberals across America are now living under the constant terror of being senselessly shot by the ICE agents they're hitting with cars.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Babylonbee.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portland Police Chief Begins To Cry As He Reluctantly Confirms Two People Shot By CBP Were Connected To Tren De Aragua</title>
      <link>https://dailycaller.com/2026/01/10/portland-police-chief-cries-tren-de-aragua-shot-cbp/</link>
      <description>Portland Police Chief Bob Day started crying during a press conference Friday after admitting two people shot by federal agents were linked to Tren de Aragua.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Daily Caller</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controversy surrounding ICE killing incident in Minneapolis deepens as new footage of deadly encounter released</title>
      <link>https://www.globalsecurity.org/security/library/news/2026/01/sec-260110-globaltimes01.htm</link>
      <description>Controversy surrounding the incident in which a US Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) officer fatally shot a mother of three Renee Nicole Good continued on Saturday. The White House on Friday reposted on social media a video taken from the cellphone of…</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 09:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Globalsecurity.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hundreds protest in Moorhead for woman killed by ICE agent</title>
      <link>https://www.inforum.com/news/moorhead/hundreds-protest-in-moorhead-for-woman-killed-by-ice-agent</link>
      <description>The group gathered for a peaceful protest on the busy Eighth Street to honor the life of a woman shot and killed by a U.S. immigration agent earlier in the week in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>INFORUM</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mamdani’s tardy response to two NYPD shootings draws blowback — including a miffed Commish Tisch</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/01/09/us-news/mamdanis-tardy-response-to-two-nypd-shootings-draws-blowback-including-a-miffed-commish-tisch/</link>
      <description>Fledgling Mayor Zohran Mamdani is already facing blowback for his tardy, halfhearted response to back-to-back police shootings – including friction with NYPD Commissioner Jessica Tisch, The Post has learned. Mamdani – who backed off his ardent “defund the pol…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 23:39:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wife Of Woman Killed By ICE Agent Breaks Silence, Says They ‘Stopped To Support Our Neighbors’</title>
      <link>https://dailycaller.com/2026/01/09/renee-good-rebecca-statement-neighbors/</link>
      <description>'You want to come at us?'</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 23:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Daily Caller</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renee Nicole Good said ‘I’m not mad at you’ before Ice agent shot her, video shows</title>
      <link>https://www.irishtimes.com/world/us/2026/01/09/renee-nicole-good-said-im-not-mad-at-you-before-ice-agent-shot-her-video-shows/</link>
      <description>Clip first posted by partisan outlet Alpha News shows perspective of Ice agent as Good was fatally shot</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Irish Times</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WATCH: Cellphone video from officer shows moment leading up to fatal shooting of Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/video/cellphone-video-officer-shows-moment-leading-fatal-shooting-129068454</link>
      <description>Tensions continue to flare in Minneapolis after an Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer fatally shot the 37-year-old woman on Wednesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 22:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Couple Shot by Federal Agents in Portland Connected to Venezuela Gang, DHS Says</title>
      <link>https://www.dailysignal.com/2026/01/09/couple-shot-by-federal-agents-in-portland-connected-to-venezuela-gang-dhs-says/</link>
      <description>The state of Oregon is investigating the shooting of two people by a Customs and Border Patrol agent in Portland on Thursday. According to the... Read More
The post Couple Shot by Federal Agents in Portland Connected to Venezuela Gang, DHS Says appeared first…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 20:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Daily Signal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Federal agents shoot 2 in Portland after an ICE agent killed a woman in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.npr.org/2026/01/09/nx-s1-5672502/minneapolis-portland-ice-shootings</link>
      <description>Officials are calling for transparent investigations into controversial shootings involving federal agents. Here's a recap of the latest developments in Portland and Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>NPR</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surveillance footage shows immigration activist blocking road before fatal ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/surveillance-footage-shows-immigration-activist-blocking-road-before-fatal-ice-shooting</link>
      <description>Surveillance footage shows moments before immigration activist was allegedly shot by ICE agents during enforcement operation in Minneapolis area.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 18:25:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Border Patrol Officer Shot Two People in Portland</title>
      <link>http://www.thecut.com/article/portland-shooting-border-patrol-oregon.html</link>
      <description>A border patrol officer shot two people in Portland, a day after an ICE officer killed a woman, Renee Nicole Good, in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 17:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Cut</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inquest report exonerates Mountie in fatal shooting of machete-wielding attacker</title>
      <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/manitoba/inquest-report-exonerates-mountie-in-fatal-shooting-of-machete-wielding-attacker-9.7039277</link>
      <description>An inquest report into the fatal police shooting of a man — who moments earlier had used a machete to attack someone in a vehicle — praises the actions of the officer and makes no recommendations on how the incident could have been handled differently.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 16:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Legal Expert Analysis: ICE Agent Was Fully in His Rights to Shoot Renee Good</title>
      <link>https://www.westernjournal.com/legal-expert-analysis-ice-agents-fully-rights-shoot-renee-good/</link>
      <description>An ICE agent fatally shot 37-year-old Renee Good inside her vehicle after she obstructed an immigration enforcement operation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 11:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Westernjournal.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trumpist lies about this ICE outrage demand a fierce response — including murder charges</title>
      <link>https://www.rawstory.com/raw-investigates/ice-shooting-2674862902/</link>
      <description>In Minneapolis, Minnesota, a masked Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent shot and killed another person, the 14
th
 ICE shooting under Trump to date
.Flexing Gestapo power in broad daylight, the agent shot a woman at close range
 as she was driving a…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 10:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Raw Story</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Minnesota prosecute the federal immigration officer who just killed a woman?</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4361120/posts</link>
      <description>A federal officer shot and killed a woman in Minneapolis on Wednesday, shortly after the Trump administration deployed thousands of immigration agents to the city. Although the full circumstances of the killing remain unclear, video of the shooting shows an o…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 02:42:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Married couple shot by federal agents in Portland, FBI investigating</title>
      <link>https://www.israelnationalnews.com/news/420635</link>
      <description>Husband and wife hospitalized after being shot by federal agents in Portland, with the FBI leading the investigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 01:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Israelnationalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Ross military past, father and Iraq connection explained amid Minneapolis ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/jonathan-ross-military-past-father-and-iraq-connection-explained-amid-minneapolis-ice-shooting-renee-nicole-good-ice-officer-june-2025-arrest-in-bloomington/articleshow/126422528.cms</link>
      <description>Jonathan Ross military past, father and Iraq connection has come under focus after the ICE officer fatally shot Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis. Reports link Ross to prior ICE incidents, a possible military background, family Iraq references, and ongoing inv…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Times of India</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cops Are Taught Not to Shoot Into Cars. ICE Keeps Doing It Anyway.</title>
      <link>https://www.motherjones.com/politics/2026/01/renee-good-minneapolis-shooting-ice-trump-cops-taught-not-shoot-at-cars/</link>
      <description>On Wednesday, a masked federal immigration officer killed Renee Nicole Good, a 37-year-old mother and poet, shooting her at point-blank range in her car.  The incident, which has made headlines across the nation, is far from the first time immigration officer…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 21:35:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Mother Jones</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis: Attempted ramming attack, suspect eliminated</title>
      <link>https://www.israelnationalnews.com/news/420554</link>
      <description>US officials say an ICE officer shot and killed a suspect who allegedly tried to ram federal agents with a vehicle during an enforcement operation in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 18:37:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Israelnationalnews.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man with machete shot and killed by police, who then find 3 more dead inside home: officials</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/man-machete-shot-killed-police-find-3-more-dead-inside-home-officials</link>
      <description>Police shot and killed an individual armed with a knife in the Garden State on Monday, the New Jersey state attorney general's office noted in a press release.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 19:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-duty deputy shot and killed while working security job in Texas, suspect apprehended</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/off-duty-deputy-shot-killed-while-working-security-job-texas-suspect-apprehended</link>
      <description>Off-duty Caldwell County deputy shot and killed while working security at a nightclub in Austin, Texs. Police investigation ongoing.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 22:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off-duty deputy shot and killed while working security job in Texas, suspect remains at large</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/off-duty-deputy-shot-killed-while-working-security-job-texas-suspect-remains-large</link>
      <description>Off-duty Caldwell County deputy shot and killed while working security at a nightclub in Austin, Texs. Police investigation ongoing.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 22:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police officer shoots, kills man who fled traffic stop</title>
      <link>https://www.mlive.com/news/2025/12/police-officer-shoots-kills-man-who-fled-traffic-stop.html</link>
      <description>The 30-year-old man allegedly said he was armed during a foot pursuit, police say.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 22:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>mlive.com</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
