<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting Research Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-research/</link>
    <description>Recent academic research on police shootings and use of deadly force</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 14:43:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Police Violence and White Supremacist Terrorism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/9780197653463.003.0005</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Wolfendale, Jessica&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; American Torture and American Terrorism&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                  &lt;jats:p&gt;Chapter 4 takes up the issue of white supremacist terrorism in America. While much scholarship on this issue focuses on the (very real) threat posed by nonstate white supremacist terrorism, this chapter reveals the complex and longstanding relationship between state and nonstate white supremacist terrorism. The complexity of this relationship makes it difficult to draw a neat distinction between state and nonstate forms of white suprema...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>American Torture and American Terrorism</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police use of force data collection issues in Florida: A minor critique</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.polgeo.2025.103468</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Rose et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Political Geography</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Political Geography</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Enslaved by the Criminal Justice System’: Law, Racial Injustice, and Modern Slavery Failures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/9780198899631.003.0004</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Koch, Insa Lee&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Drugs, Race, and the Politics of Modern Slavery Law&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                  &lt;jats:p&gt;Chapter 4 shifts the focus from young drug dealers’ and their families’ experiences of welfare state failure to their encounters with the criminal justice system. The government’s modern slavery agenda was implemented against the backdrop of an entrenched racial neo-liberalism that continues to criminalize Black and minoritized working class youth as its constitutive ‘other’. I discuss cases of boys and young men who ostensibly meet the...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Drugs, Race, and the Politics of Modern Slavery Law</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Displaying deadly police violence against Black people through government memorials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1108/pijpsm-09-2025-0171</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Keyes &amp; Keyes&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Policing: An International Journal&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:sec&gt;
                    &lt;jats:title&gt;Purpose&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                    &lt;jats:p&gt;The purpose of this article is to explore the understudied intersection of government-sponsored memorials of Black people alongside the demographics of police officers who were involved in their deaths and the emergence of government-sponsored memorials for Black people slain by police.&lt;/jats:p&gt;
                  &lt;/jats:sec&gt;
                  &lt;jats:sec&gt;
                    &lt;jats:title&gt;Design/methodology/a...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Policing: An International Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who makes the right call? Examining relationships between personality traits and situational performance in police cadets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1108/pijpsm-02-2025-0037</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; AlSabah et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Policing: An International Journal&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:sec&gt;
                    &lt;jats:title&gt;Purpose&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                    &lt;jats:p&gt;Police institutions and practitioners often associate personality traits with an individual’s likelihood of success in policing, emphasizing certain psychological profiles as better suited for handling the stressful conditions inherent in police work. This study investigates personality traits and their potential relationship to critical aspects of police performance under stress–conceptualized as decisio...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Policing: An International Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Examining variations in sustained citizen complaint dispositions among large US police departments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1108/pijpsm-07-2025-0118</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Harris &amp; Perry&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Policing: An International Journal&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:sec&gt;
                    &lt;jats:title&gt;Purpose&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                    &lt;jats:p&gt;Investigating complaints against police misconduct is vital to accountability, and this task is commonly delegated to Internal Affairs (IA) units within large police departments. IA units vary considerably in the degree to which they find evidence of misconduct in their investigations, but there has been little exploration of this issue. Extant research suggests this variation could be attributable to eit...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Policing: An International Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gender-Based Violence Concerns, Trust in Police and Support for Defunding the Police</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/bjc/azaf119</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Updegrove &amp; Craig&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; The British Journal of Criminology&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                  &lt;jats:p&gt;Public opinion research has yet to fully consider the various contexts in which people evaluate calls to defund the police and how those contexts may relate to or interact with popular constructs like trust in police. Because Americans are socialized to view police as the primary response to gender-based violence, people concerned about gender-based violence may perceive that defunding would negatively impact responses to this issue. Us...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>The British Journal of Criminology</source>
      <priority>true</priority>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
