<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 07:00:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Republicans criticise immigration force but steer clear of Trump attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cj3vp84j1l3o</link>
      <description>Lawmakers are questioning the crackdown while anger grows over two citizens killed by federal agents.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 02:29:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>BBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 federal agents fired shots when Alex Pretti was killed in Minneapolis: U.S. official</title>
      <link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/alex-pretti-shooting-two-federal-agents-shot-9.7064190</link>
      <description>Two federal officers fired shots during the encounter that killed ICU nurse Alex Pretti in Minneapolis, a U.S. Customs and Border Protection official told Congress in a notice sent Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 01:32:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 feds fired guns in deadly Alex Pretti encounter</title>
      <link>https://www.bostonherald.com/2026/01/27/2-feds-fired-guns-in-deadly-alex-pretti-encounter/</link>
      <description>Two federal officers fired shots during the encounter that killed ICU nurse Alex Pretti in Minneapolis, a Customs and Border Protection official told Congress in a notice sent Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Boston Herald</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 federal officers fired shots during encounter that killed Alex Pretti, DHS tells Congress</title>
      <link>https://www.wpxi.com/news/local/2-federal-officers-fired-shots-during-encounter-that-killed-alex-pretti-dhs-tells-congress/L3RZPVPXOBFELGMDHKJ35YXUPE/</link>
      <description>Two federal officers fired shots during an encounter that killed ICU nurse Alex Pretti in Minneapolis, a Customs and Border Protection official told Congress in a notice sent Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 23:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WPXI Pittsburgh</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DHS: 2 Federal Officers Fired Shots During Encounter That Killed Alex Pretti</title>
      <link>https://www.huffpost.com/entry/alex-pretti-shooting-minneapolis_n_6979447ce4b0627b210f4ab9</link>
      <description>One Border Patrol officer fired his Glock and a CBP officer fired his, according to a notification to Congress obtained by The Associated Press.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 23:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>HuffPost</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trump laments shooting deaths of Good and Pretti, insists Minnesota personnel shuffle is not a 'pullback'</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/media/trump-laments-shooting-deaths-good-pretti-insists-minnesota-personnel-shuffle-not-pullback</link>
      <description>Trump laments deaths of Renee Good and Alex Pretti, both fatally shot by federal agents in Minnesota, calling incidents &quot;terrible&quot; while defending enforcement operations.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 23:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exclusive: Two officers fired their guns during Pretti encounter, Homeland Security says in initial report | CNN Politics</title>
      <link>https://www.cnn.com/2026/01/27/politics/pretti-shooting-two-officers-homeland-security-report</link>
      <description>Two officers fired their guns during the fatal encounter with Alex Pretti in Minneapolis over the weekend, according to an initial report to Congress from the Department of Homeland Security reviewed by CNN.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 22:38:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CNN</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Truly Scary Part of Minneapolis Protests</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4364185/posts</link>
      <description>The protesting in Minneapolis is not a great thing for anyone, contrary to what some might think. Alex Pretti's death was just the latest incident where someone who was involved ended up being killed by federal agents, though it's the less clear-cut case of a…</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:34:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knife-wielding nut allegedly asked Christian his religion – then stabbed him and dog before police shot him</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/knife-wielding-nut-allegedly-asked-christian-his-religion-then-stabbed-him-dog-before-police-shot-him</link>
      <description>Armed Washington suspect died after police shooting following alleged stabbing attack on man and dog that occurred after asking victim about Christian faith in Parkland on Sunday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A second U.S. citizen was killed by federal forces in Minneapolis. Here's what we know</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/a-second-u-s-citizen-was-killed-by-federal-forces-in-minneapolis-heres-what-we-know</link>
      <description>The fatal shooting of Alex Pretti, the second U.S. citizen to be killed by federal forces in Minnesota this month, has intensified the public outrage over tactics used by immigration agents in the state and united unlikely bedfellows in calling for a full inv…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>PBS</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Sickening lies’: Parents of man killed by federal agent in Minneapolis go nuclear on Trump’s ‘murdering thugs’</title>
      <link>https://www.wnd.com/2026/01/sickening-lies-parents-man-killed-federal-agent-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>'I do not throw around the hero term lightly. However his last thought and act was to protect a woman'</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Wnd.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOP Sen. Cassidy breaks with Trump over deadly shooting by Border Patrol agent in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/gop-sen-cassidy-breaks-trump-over-deadly-shooting-border-patrol-agent-minneapolis</link>
      <description>Republican Sen. Bill Cassidy calls for full investigation after a Border Patrol agent shot and killed a man in Minneapolis during a DHS operation on Saturday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 08:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pritzker urges 'unified response' from Democrat, Republican governors after Border Patrol shoots armed man</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/pritzker-urges-unified-response-democrat-republican-governors-border-patrol-shoots-armed-man</link>
      <description>Illinois Gov. JB Pritzker and New York Gov. Kathy Hochul slammed thee Trump administration after Border Patrol shot an armed man in Minneapolis.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 19:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
