<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:01:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Maryland AG finds mental health to be a factor in police shootings</title>
      <link>https://www.thebanner.com/community/criminal-justice/maryland-police-killings-mental-health-crisis-QED6OXAGIRERZMUB5DUUJ4RO4I/</link>
      <description>Since 2021, the Maryland Office of the Attorney General has reviewed 86 cases in which someone was killed by police — and 20 of those cases involved mental health crises, according to a report released Thursday.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Thebanner.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 days before he was shot and killed by ICE, Alex Pretti kicked out a vehicle taillight and got wrestled to the ground</title>
      <link>https://fortune.com/2026/01/29/alex-pretty-new-videos-show-previous-conflict-with-ice/</link>
      <description>At no point in the newly uncovered videos does Pretti reach for his gun and it is unclear whether the federal agents saw it.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 14:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fortune</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MORNING GLORY: Minnesota tragedies aren't instant replay calls you make from the couch</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/opinion/morning-glory-minnesota-tragedies-arent-instant-replay-calls-make-couch</link>
      <description>America's criminal justice system requires patience and complete evidence, not instant replay mentality, argues Fox News contributor Hugh Hewitt following Minnesota police shootings.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 10:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There’s A Reason Many Police Dept’s Ban Shooting At Moving Vehicles: It Saves Lives Without Putting Officers In Greater Danger</title>
      <link>https://www.techdirt.com/2026/01/28/theres-a-reason-many-police-depts-ban-shooting-at-moving-vehicles-it-saves-lives-without-putting-officers-in-greater-danger/</link>
      <description>Minneapolis is once again the focus of debates about violence involving law enforcement after an Immigration and Customs Enforcement officer shot and killed Renee Nicole Good, a 37-year-old mother, in her car. The incident quickly prompted dueling narratives.…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 23:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Techdirt</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Officer-involved shooting reported at Cobb County police headquarters</title>
      <link>https://www.wsbtv.com/news/local/cobb-county/officer-involved-shooting-reported-cobb-county-police-headquarters/F6BSWV56Y5GCPKNMVCFOLCUHR4/</link>
      <description>Police are investigating a shooting involving an officer at the Cobb County Police Department headquarters.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 22:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WSB Atlanta</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Officer-involved shooting reported in Allegheny County</title>
      <link>https://www.wpxi.com/news/local/officer-involved-shooting-reported-allegheny-county/KSJH2H347FCYZFGCDUCOJTRXGU/</link>
      <description>The Allegheny County Police Department says the shooting happened in the 1100 block of Penn Center Boulevard in Wilkins Township.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 19:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>WPXI Pittsburgh</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Knife-wielding nut allegedly asked Christian his religion – then stabbed him and dog before police shot him</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/knife-wielding-nut-allegedly-asked-christian-his-religion-then-stabbed-him-dog-before-police-shot-him</link>
      <description>Armed Washington suspect died after police shooting following alleged stabbing attack on man and dog that occurred after asking victim about Christian faith in Parkland on Sunday.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A second U.S. citizen was killed by federal forces in Minneapolis. Here's what we know</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/nation/a-second-u-s-citizen-was-killed-by-federal-forces-in-minneapolis-heres-what-we-know</link>
      <description>The fatal shooting of Alex Pretti, the second U.S. citizen to be killed by federal forces in Minnesota this month, has intensified the public outrage over tactics used by immigration agents in the state and united unlikely bedfellows in calling for a full inv…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 21:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>PBS</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘Sickening lies’: Parents of man killed by federal agent in Minneapolis go nuclear on Trump’s ‘murdering thugs’</title>
      <link>https://www.wnd.com/2026/01/sickening-lies-parents-man-killed-federal-agent-minneapolis/</link>
      <description>'I do not throw around the hero term lightly. However his last thought and act was to protect a woman'</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 14:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Wnd.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GOP Sen. Cassidy breaks with Trump over deadly shooting by Border Patrol agent in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/gop-sen-cassidy-breaks-trump-over-deadly-shooting-border-patrol-agent-minneapolis</link>
      <description>Republican Sen. Bill Cassidy calls for full investigation after a Border Patrol agent shot and killed a man in Minneapolis during a DHS operation on Saturday.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 08:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
