<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 06:42:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>ICE's growing lawlessness, briefly explained (Cameron Peters/Vox)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260122/p138</link>
      <description>Cameron Peters / Vox:
ICE's growing lawlessness, briefly explained  —  Trump's nascent police state is coming into focus. … In the just over two weeks since an ICE agent shot and killed Renee Good in Minneapolis, we have seen the Trump administration:  — Wron…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 01:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monterey County Black Caucus calls for transparency in deadly traffic-stop shooting</title>
      <link>https://freerepublic.com/focus/f-news/4363468/posts</link>
      <description>MARINA, Calif. — Community leaders in Monterey County are calling for transparency and accountability after an officer fatally shot a man. On Jan. 18, 2026, 31-year-old Ronald Chyron Tinsley was fatally shot by Marina police during a traffic stop near Marina …</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 20:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Freerepublic.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WATCH LIVE: Vance speaks in Minneapolis after deadly ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/watch-live-vance-speaks-in-minneapolis-after-deadly-ice-shooting</link>
      <description>Vice President JD Vance plans to meet with Immigration and Customs Enforcement agents in Minneapolis, which has been roiled by protests since an agent fatally shot Renee Good. The Republican vice president has played a leading role in defending that agent and…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>PBS</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vance heads to Minneapolis and says ‘far left’ should stop resisting immigration enforcement</title>
      <link>https://www.denverpost.com/2026/01/22/vance-minnesota/</link>
      <description>Protests have erupted in the city after an agent fatally shot Renee Good this month.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Denver Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renee Good’s autopsy details revealed; Minnesota mother was shot in the 'side of the head' by ICE agent</title>
      <link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/us/renee-goods-autopsy-details-revealed-minnesota-mother-was-shot-three-times-by-ice-agent/articleshow/127165320.cms</link>
      <description>US News: An independent autopsy into the death of Renee Nicole Good, the 37-year-old woman shot by federal immigration agent Jonathan Ross in Minneapolis, has .</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Times of India</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man injured in southern Colorado police chase, shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.denverpost.com/2026/01/22/walsenburg-police-chase-shooting/</link>
      <description>A Walsenburg police officer shot at a fleeing domestic violence suspect on Wednesday, according to the Colorado Bureau of Investigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Denver Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vance heads to Minneapolis amid tension over ICE crackdown</title>
      <link>https://www.thestar.com.my/news/world/2026/01/22/vance-heads-to-minneapolis-amid-tension-over-ice-crackdown</link>
      <description>MINNEAPOLIS, Jan 22 (Reuters) - Vice President ‌JD Vance is expected to visit Minneapolis on Thursday to show support for a massive federal law enforcement operation underway in a city that ‌has been on edge since an ICE officer shot dead a 37-year-old mother…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Star Online</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Court Record, Official Describes Assault Before ICE Agent Shot Man in Minneapolis - The New York Times</title>
      <link>https://slashdot.org/firehose.pl?op=view&amp;amp;id=180633372</link>
      <description>In Court Record, Official Describes Assault Before ICE Agent Shot Man in MinneapolisThe New York Times Aftermath video of latest ICE shooting in Minneapolis involving an undocumented Venezuelan nationalCNN 2nd federal officer shooting in Minneapolis prompts p…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Slashdot.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New reports say Renee Good still had a pulse after being shot by ICE — medics were delayed</title>
      <link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international/us/new-reports-say-renee-good-still-had-a-pulse-after-being-shot-by-ice-medics-were-delayed/articleshow/126983733.cms</link>
      <description>The fatal shooting of 37-year-old Renee Nicole Good by an ICE officer in Minneapolis has resulted in intense scrutiny. Minnesota Public Radio (MPR) News analysis disclosed that Good had a pulse, stated as “thready and irregular”, six minutes following the inc…</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:17:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Times of India</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ABC, NBC and CBS delivered 93% negative coverage on ICE after fatal Renee Good shooting, study finds</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/media/abc-nbc-cbs-delivered-93-negative-coverage-ice-after-fatal-renee-good-shooting-study-finds</link>
      <description>Study finds ABC, NBC, CBS were 93% negative about ICE following an officer-involved shooting, with 68 negative sound bites vs. only 5 positive clips analyzed.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mother of officer killed by illegal migrant criticizes Minnesota leaders' 'warped view' of police</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/media/mother-officer-killed-illegal-migrant-criticizes-minnesota-leaders-warped-view-police</link>
      <description>Angel mom Mary Ann Mendoza defends ICE agents facing 'hate and unrest' after her police officer son was killed by an illegal migrant in 2014 on &quot;The Faulkner Focus.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 22:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man charged after being shot by Richmond police at GRTC headquarters</title>
      <link>https://richmond.com/news/local/crime/article_8f687c0b-d5a0-47d7-bb2c-1f48bdef505b.html</link>
      <description>Richmond police detectives have charged the suspect in an officer-involved shooting that occurred at GRTC headquarters on Saturday night.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 02:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Richmond.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When the News Doesn’t See You</title>
      <link>https://scienceblog.com/when-the-news-doesnt-see-you/</link>
      <description>THE boy was twelve years old, holding a toy gun. But that's not what some news outlets called him when Cleveland police shot Tamir Rice in 2014. Instead,</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:44:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ScienceBlog.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuelan shot in another federal agent action in U.S. Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.globalsecurity.org/security/library/news/2026/01/sec-260115-pdo02.htm</link>
      <description>A U.S. federal agent shot and injured a Venezuelan man Wednesday night in Minneapolis, the largest city in the state of Minnesota, said the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Globalsecurity.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Police Chief: Rioters 'Are Engaging in Unlawful Acts'</title>
      <link>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2026/01/15/minneapolis-police-chief-rioters-are-engaging-unlawful-acts/</link>
      <description>Minneapolis Police Chief Brian O'Hara noted rioters gathered in response to Wednesday's officer-involved shooting were &quot;engaging in unlawful acts.&quot;
The post Minneapolis Police Chief: Rioters ‘Are Engaging in Unlawful Acts’ appeared first on Breitbart.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Breitbart News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-ICE threat spray-painted on vehicle believed to be used by federal officers during Minneapolis unrest</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/anti-ice-threat-spray-painted-vehicle-believed-used-federal-officers-during-minneapolis-unrest</link>
      <description>Minneapolis rioters vandalized vehicles with anti-ICE messages and threats after a federal agent shot an illegal immigrant during an alleged ambush.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live updates: Minneapolis ICE shooting, tensions flare after man is shot in leg after allegedly assaulting federal agent | CNN</title>
      <link>https://www.cnn.com/us/live-news/minneapolis-ice-shooting-protests-01-15-26</link>
      <description>Law enforcement and demonstrators clashed last night near where a federal agent shot and injured a man after he allegedly assaulted the agent. The city is reeling over last week’s fatal shooting by an ICE agent of Renee Good sparked nationwide protests. Follo…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CNN</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overnight: 3rd DHS-Involved Shooting in a Week - Officer Shoots Suspect After Being Ambushed by Men With Pole Weapons</title>
      <link>https://www.westernjournal.com/overnight-3rd-dhs-involved-shooting-week-officer-shoots-suspect-ambushed-men-pole-weapons/</link>
      <description>&quot;As the officer was being ambushed and attacked by the two individuals, the original subject got loose and began striking the officer...&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Westernjournal.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tensions Flare in Minneapolis as Federal Agent Shoots A Venezuelan National Following Alleged Shovel and Broom Assault</title>
      <link>https://www.ibtimes.com/tensions-flare-minneapolis-federal-agent-shoots-venezuelan-national-following-alleged-shovel-3795367</link>
      <description>Tensions flare in Minneapolis as federal agent shoots Venezuelan national in leg after alleged assault during immigration stop. Protests clash with police amid second ICE incident in a week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>International Business Times</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis anti-ICE protesters hurl fireworks, rocks at officers following shooting of Venezuelan migrant</title>
      <link>https://nypost.com/2026/01/15/us-news/minneapolis-anti-ice-protesters-hurl-fireworks-rocks-at-officers-following-shooting-of-venezuela-migrant/</link>
      <description>A group of violent anti-ICE protesters hurled fireworks and rocks at officers on a Minneapolis block where a federal immigration agent shot a Venezuelan migrant in the leg hours earlier Wednesday night.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 06:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>New York Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US federal agent shoots Venezuelan man in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.rte.ie/news/us/2026/0115/1553182-minneapolis-us/</link>
      <description>A Venezuelan national ⁠pursued by US immigration agents during a &quot;targeted&quot; traffic stop in Minneapolis was shot in the leg by a federal officer, authorities said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:06:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>RTE</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another ICE shooting in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.lawyersgunsmoneyblog.com/2026/01/another-ice-shooting-in-minneapolis</link>
      <description>The CNN breaking news headline is that “Fed Officer Shot Suspect in Minneapolis After Shovel Ambush.” Rumors are flying about the identity of the shooting victim but we’ll see. The neighborhood in question appears to be a residential area close to downtown. A…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:31:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Lawyersgunsmoneyblog.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE agent shoots Venezuelan national in Minneapolis after shovel attack during ambush: DHS</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/ice-agent-shoots-venezuelan-national-minneapolis-shovel-attack-ambush-dhs</link>
      <description>A shooting involving an ICE agent unfolded in Minneapolis late Wednesday after a suspect allegedly assaulted a federal officer with a shovel, authorities said.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
