<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 06:43:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Victim-Blaming in the Fatal Minnesota Shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/bias-fundamentals/202601/victim-blaming-in-the-fatal-minnesota-shooting</link>
      <description>After an ICE agent fatally shot a woman in Minnesota, responses have ranged from compassion for the victim to extreme criticism and unsubstantiated attacks. How can we address such victim-blaming?</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 23:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Psychology Today</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘The Uniform’: First Look At Fremantle’s Crime Drama Series About Aftermath Of A Police Shooting</title>
      <link>http://deadline.com/2026/01/the-uniform-first-look-images-fremantle-1236694225/</link>
      <description>EXCLUSIVE: Here’s your first look at The Uniform, the upcoming Danish police drama series. The Miso Film crime drama for Denmark’s pubcaster, DR, follows the criminal investigation into a fatal police shooting that threatens the credibility of the entire inst…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:09:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Deadline</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Anyone Can Pull Off a General Strike, It’s Minnesotans</title>
      <link>https://newrepublic.com/article/205318/minnesota-general-strike-ice-protest</link>
      <description>Christin Crabtree lives just a few
blocks from where an Immigration and Customs Enforcement agent shot Renee Nicole Macklin Good, on the south side of Minneapolis. A mother, like Good, Crabtree
has been organizing with her neighbors against the invasion of IC…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The New Republic</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ICE's growing lawlessness, briefly explained (Cameron Peters/Vox)</title>
      <link>https://www.memeorandum.com/260122/p138</link>
      <description>Cameron Peters / Vox:
ICE's growing lawlessness, briefly explained  —  Trump's nascent police state is coming into focus. … In the just over two weeks since an ICE agent shot and killed Renee Good in Minneapolis, we have seen the Trump administration:  — Wron…</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 01:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Memeorandum.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WATCH LIVE: Vance speaks in Minneapolis after deadly ICE shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/watch-live-vance-speaks-in-minneapolis-after-deadly-ice-shooting</link>
      <description>Vice President JD Vance plans to meet with Immigration and Customs Enforcement agents in Minneapolis, which has been roiled by protests since an agent fatally shot Renee Good. The Republican vice president has played a leading role in defending that agent and…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>PBS</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man injured in southern Colorado police chase, shooting</title>
      <link>https://www.denverpost.com/2026/01/22/walsenburg-police-chase-shooting/</link>
      <description>A Walsenburg police officer shot at a fleeing domestic violence suspect on Wednesday, according to the Colorado Bureau of Investigation.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 14:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Denver Post</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vance heads to Minneapolis amid tension over ICE crackdown</title>
      <link>https://www.thestar.com.my/news/world/2026/01/22/vance-heads-to-minneapolis-amid-tension-over-ice-crackdown</link>
      <description>MINNEAPOLIS, Jan 22 (Reuters) - Vice President ‌JD Vance is expected to visit Minneapolis on Thursday to show support for a massive federal law enforcement operation underway in a city that ‌has been on edge since an ICE officer shot dead a 37-year-old mother…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>The Star Online</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ABC, NBC and CBS delivered 93% negative coverage on ICE after fatal Renee Good shooting, study finds</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/media/abc-nbc-cbs-delivered-93-negative-coverage-ice-after-fatal-renee-good-shooting-study-finds</link>
      <description>Study finds ABC, NBC, CBS were 93% negative about ICE following an officer-involved shooting, with 68 negative sound bites vs. only 5 positive clips analyzed.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:59:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Man charged after being shot by Richmond police at GRTC headquarters</title>
      <link>https://richmond.com/news/local/crime/article_8f687c0b-d5a0-47d7-bb2c-1f48bdef505b.html</link>
      <description>Richmond police detectives have charged the suspect in an officer-involved shooting that occurred at GRTC headquarters on Saturday night.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 02:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Richmond.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When the News Doesn’t See You</title>
      <link>https://scienceblog.com/when-the-news-doesnt-see-you/</link>
      <description>THE boy was twelve years old, holding a toy gun. But that's not what some news outlets called him when Cleveland police shot Tamir Rice in 2014. Instead,</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:44:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ScienceBlog.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venezuelan shot in another federal agent action in U.S. Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.globalsecurity.org/security/library/news/2026/01/sec-260115-pdo02.htm</link>
      <description>A U.S. federal agent shot and injured a Venezuelan man Wednesday night in Minneapolis, the largest city in the state of Minnesota, said the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 11:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Globalsecurity.org</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minneapolis Police Chief: Rioters 'Are Engaging in Unlawful Acts'</title>
      <link>https://www.breitbart.com/politics/2026/01/15/minneapolis-police-chief-rioters-are-engaging-unlawful-acts/</link>
      <description>Minneapolis Police Chief Brian O'Hara noted rioters gathered in response to Wednesday's officer-involved shooting were &quot;engaging in unlawful acts.&quot;
The post Minneapolis Police Chief: Rioters ‘Are Engaging in Unlawful Acts’ appeared first on Breitbart.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Breitbart News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-ICE threat spray-painted on vehicle believed to be used by federal officers during Minneapolis unrest</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/anti-ice-threat-spray-painted-vehicle-believed-used-federal-officers-during-minneapolis-unrest</link>
      <description>Minneapolis rioters vandalized vehicles with anti-ICE messages and threats after a federal agent shot an illegal immigrant during an alleged ambush.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Live updates: Minneapolis ICE shooting, tensions flare after man is shot in leg after allegedly assaulting federal agent | CNN</title>
      <link>https://www.cnn.com/us/live-news/minneapolis-ice-shooting-protests-01-15-26</link>
      <description>Law enforcement and demonstrators clashed last night near where a federal agent shot and injured a man after he allegedly assaulted the agent. The city is reeling over last week’s fatal shooting by an ICE agent of Renee Good sparked nationwide protests. Follo…</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CNN</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overnight: 3rd DHS-Involved Shooting in a Week - Officer Shoots Suspect After Being Ambushed by Men With Pole Weapons</title>
      <link>https://www.westernjournal.com/overnight-3rd-dhs-involved-shooting-week-officer-shoots-suspect-ambushed-men-pole-weapons/</link>
      <description>&quot;As the officer was being ambushed and attacked by the two individuals, the original subject got loose and began striking the officer...&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Westernjournal.com</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tensions Flare in Minneapolis as Federal Agent Shoots A Venezuelan National Following Alleged Shovel and Broom Assault</title>
      <link>https://www.ibtimes.com/tensions-flare-minneapolis-federal-agent-shoots-venezuelan-national-following-alleged-shovel-3795367</link>
      <description>Tensions flare in Minneapolis as federal agent shoots Venezuelan national in leg after alleged assault during immigration stop. Protests clash with police amid second ICE incident in a week.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:13:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>International Business Times</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
