<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting Research Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-research/</link>
    <description>Recent academic research on police shootings and use of deadly force</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 07:06:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Tanzanian pupils' perspectives on the &quot;Don't Touch Me&quot; song: recall, demonstration and understanding of a police-led sexual violence awareness intervention</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55056/ed.968</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Nemes &amp; Rwabishugi&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Educational Dimension&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Child sexual violence (CSV) is a critical issue in Tanzania, with reported cases rising significantly. This qualitative study examines the perspectives of Tanzanian pupils on the &quot;Don't Touch Me&quot; song, which was used by Police Gender and Children's Desk officers in a child sexual violence awareness intervention in Chamwino District. Guided by Albert Bandura's social learning theory, the research explores pupils' ability to recall and demonstrate the song, investigating its influence on t...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2027 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Educational Dimension</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use of lethal weapons to kill protesters by Bangladesh police: A discussion analyzing 253 deaths of July 24 revolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.dialog.2026.100277</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Siddik et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Dialogues in Health</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Dialogues in Health</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police Violence and White Supremacist Terrorism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/9780197653463.003.0005</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Wolfendale, Jessica&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; American Torture and American Terrorism&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                  &lt;jats:p&gt;Chapter 4 takes up the issue of white supremacist terrorism in America. While much scholarship on this issue focuses on the (very real) threat posed by nonstate white supremacist terrorism, this chapter reveals the complex and longstanding relationship between state and nonstate white supremacist terrorism. The complexity of this relationship makes it difficult to draw a neat distinction between state and nonstate forms of white suprema...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>American Torture and American Terrorism</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incidents with recreational nitrous oxide use before and after legislation: poisonings and police incidents in the Netherlands between 2020 and 2025</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.drugpo.2026.105170</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Hondebrink et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; International Journal of Drug Policy</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>International Journal of Drug Policy</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Police use of force data collection issues in Florida: A minor critique</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.polgeo.2025.103468</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Rose et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Political Geography</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Political Geography</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Criminalizing homelessness: Longitudinal associations of police encounters and homeless sweeps with psychosocial health among the unhoused community in Los Angeles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2026.119033</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Chien et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Social Science &amp;amp; Medicine</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Social Science &amp;amp; Medicine</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transparency, Accountability, Open Justice, and Public Facts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/9780198925149.003.0004</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Hadjimatheou, Katerina&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; The Crimes of Others&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                  &lt;jats:p&gt;This chapter argue that respect for democratic transparency, accountability, and open justice is compatible with respect for the rights and interests of people with criminal records. Presumptions in favour of publicity or, conversely, of confidentiality should differ between different areas of the criminal justice system, such as courts, policing, and probation, as conflicts between individual rights to privacy and the public right to k...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>The Crimes of Others</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Representation of Police Reputation and Image:  A Bibliometric Analysis of Police Reputation and Image in Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.35516/hum.2026.10136</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Sani et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Dirasat: Human and Social Sciences&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Objectives: Public perception of the police is influenced by media coverage. This study aims to map research related to the image and reputation of the police in media coverage.
Methods: This research uses a bibliometrics approach. The research data was obtained from the Scopus database.
Results: Our results found 433 articles and provide an overview of the evolution and current state of research in police reputation and image in the last 28 years. The study found that the trend of polic...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Dirasat: Human and Social Sciences</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BUILDING POLICE CAPACITY IN FRAGILE SECURITY SETTINGS: EVIDENCE FROM RECRUITMENT AND TRAINING PRACTICES IN NIGERIA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.70382/mejaimr.v11i2.098</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; ODUNTAN et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; International Journal of African Innovation and Multidisciplinary Research&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Police effectiveness constitutes a foundational element of state capacity, particularly in fragile security environments where violent crime, insurgency, and public distrust undermine governance and social order (World Bank, 2023; UNDP, 2022). In Nigeria, persistent weaknesses in policing manifested in corruption, brutality, low investigative capacity, and strained police–community relations have endured despite repeated reform initiatives, most notably following the 2020 #EndSARS protes...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>International Journal of African Innovation and Multidisciplinary Research</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From adoption to accountability: a 1997–2024 bibliometric cartography of ICT in SMEs with accounting &amp;amp; sustainability overlays</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s13731-026-00621-0</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Dinanti et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Journal of Innovation and Entrepreneurship&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:title&gt;Abstract&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                  &lt;jats:p&gt;
                    This study investigates the performance and science mapping of ICT adoption in SMEs through a bibliometric analysis of Scopus-indexed publications. We examine how the ICT-in-SMEs literature evolved over 1997–2024 and where accounting and sustainability themes are situated within that corpus. Proxies are operationalized via author and index keywords, co-word structures, and controlled overlays linking ERP, e-invoicin...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Journal of Innovation and Entrepreneurship</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of the Civil Service Police Unit (Satpol PP) in Increasing Local Revenue through Local Taxes and Levies in Simalungun Regency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.70471/w10q8e77</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Gabriel Saragih et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Asian Multidisciplinary Research Journal of Economy and Learning&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;This study aims to analyze the role of the Civil Service Police Unit (Satpol PP) in increasing Local Revenue (PAD) in Simalungun Regency through the supervision of local taxes and levies. The research method used is descriptive qualitative with a case study approach. Data were collected through interviews with Satpol PP officers, officials from the Regional Finance and Revenue Management Agency (BPKPD), and business actors involved in local taxes and levies. The results show that Satpol ...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Asian Multidisciplinary Research Journal of Economy and Learning</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlation between physical fitness, psychophysiological parameters and performance in a firearm proficiency test in military police officers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2025.1736902</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Junger et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Frontiers in Psychology&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:sec&gt;
                    &lt;jats:title&gt;Introduction&lt;/jats:title&gt;
                    &lt;jats:p&gt;Military police officers must combine physical conditioning, emotional control, and technical skills to act effectively in high-stress scenarios. However, evidence on the relationship between physical and psychophysiological indicators and performance in firearm proficiency remains scarce.&lt;/jats:p&gt;
                  &lt;/jats:sec&gt;
                  &lt;jats:sec&gt;
                    &lt;jats:title&gt;Methods&lt;/jat...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Frontiers in Psychology</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-escalation techniques on daily duty: A body-worn camera analysis of police-civilian interactions in the Netherlands</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/r3z47_v1</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; van Lith et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Journal&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Purpose – This study examines the de-escalation techniques police officers employ during everyday encounters with civilians and assesses how the use of these techniques varies when civilians exhibit different emotional and behavioral states. Design/methodology/approach – We systematically analyzed body-worn camera footage from 82 real-life police-civilian interactions in the Netherlands, coding 35 distinct de-escalation techniques. Using Firth’s logistic regression with cluster bootstrap, we ...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Unknown Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acting on instinct: Policing violence against women and girls in the night-time economy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/14613557251410772</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Mitchell &amp; Rowe&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; International Journal of Police Science &amp;amp; Management&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Globally, violence against women and girls (VAWG) is a pervasive issue which has wide-scale consequences. This paper focuses on VAWG in the context of the night-time economy (NTE), and the policing strategies targeted at its prevention. Using a mixed-methods approach, it identifies the centrality of police officer knowledge to operational practice. Original insight suggests that this provides, at best, a partial basis for effective interventions and demonstrates a limited understanding o...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>International Journal of Police Science &amp;amp; Management</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cost-benefits of empowering teachers on Public Service Acts of Misconduct Regulations of 2000 as Amended in 2001 to curb indiscipline in Zimbabwe</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55559/sjahss.v4i11.549</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Kabungaidze &amp; Mafa&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Sprin Journal of Arts, Humanities and Social Sciences&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;It is so colourful to empower secondary teachers with public service acts of misconduct as a mitigating measure to curb indiscipline. Indiscipline is an academic scar that undermines the education system in Zimbabwe. Indiscipline is a product of bad leadership practices. The objective of this study was to determine the cost-benefits of empowering or capacitating secondary school teachers on Public Service acts of misconduct regulations to address the frequent occurrence of teacher indisc...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Sprin Journal of Arts, Humanities and Social Sciences</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personal and Structural Barriers Reporting Intimate Partner Violence to the Police: A Systematic Review of Women’s Experiences and Societal Influences</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/15248380251409827</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Vicente-Garcia et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Trauma, Violence, &amp;amp; Abuse&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;
                    Barriers to reporting intimate partner violence (IPV) to the police represent a critical public health problem affecting women. Using a critical perspective, this systematic review aims to analyze the interconnection of the barriers to police reporting encountered by women experiencing IPV, particularly as these are exacerbated by immigration status, ethnicity, and minority background. A systematic review of the published literature from 2013 to 2024 was conducted us...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Trauma, Violence, &amp;amp; Abuse</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Article 13: Trauma-Informed Comprehensive Critical Incident Responses for Officer Suicide Prevention</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.65264/hiiw8249</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Frost &amp; Nahikian&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Advancing Corrections Journal&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;Correction officers in High Income Countries are at higher risk for suicide than those in almost any other occupation, including other protective service occupations. Suicide prevention for correction officers requires attending to the long-term impacts of violence and suicide exposures on their health and wellbeing. We argue for a two-pronged approach: one that focuses on prevention, through attention to critical incident exposures involving serious violence, injury or death, and compre...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Advancing Corrections Journal</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction: Officer-involved shootings: testing the effect of question timing on memory accuracy for stressful events</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11292-025-09696-3</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Porter et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Journal of Experimental Criminology</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Journal of Experimental Criminology</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peran Social Media Officer pada Akun @Bukaproject dalam Membangun Brand Awareness</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22236/komunika.v13i1.22039</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Azzahra et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; KOMUNIKA&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;jats:p&gt;This study examines the role of the Social Media Officer (SMO) in managing the @bukaproject Instagram account to build brand awareness for Buka Project, a creative industry company located in Bogor, using the Honeycomb Model framework approach. This study used a descriptive qualitative method through participant observation, in-depth interviews, and document studies during the internship period. The analysis results show that of the seven Honeycomb functional blocks, Buka Project's socia...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>KOMUNIKA</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Chutes and Ladders: Collecting Records of Police Shootings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/9780691260839-004</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Authors&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Deadly Force</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Deadly Force</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter Seven Conflict between Active Shooter Policy and Police Culture at Uvalde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/9798855804539-009</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Authors&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; School Shootings in American Culture</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>School Shootings in American Culture</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1. THE CONTEXT OF POLICE SHOOTINGS AND PROTEST: DENVER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7312/dura20210-003</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Authors&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Justice Required</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Justice Required</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Who Do the Police Shoot?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/9780691260839-008</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Authors&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Deadly Force</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Deadly Force</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2. DIVERGENT LIFE CHANCES FOR GETTIN’ SHOT BY THE POLICE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7312/dura20210-004</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Unknown Authors&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Justice Required</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Justice Required</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Striking or grappling? Comparing public and officers' perceptions of police use of force</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcrimjus.2026.102601</link>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Eleuterio-da-Rocha et al.&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Journal of Criminal Justice</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>research</category>
      <source>Journal of Criminal Justice</source>
      <priority>true</priority>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
