<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>U.S. Police Shooting News Tracker</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/police-shooting-news/</link>
    <description>Automated news aggregation tracking police-involved shootings in the United States</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:30:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Jan. 6 plaque made to honor law enforcement. It's nowhere to be found at the Capitol</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/jan-6-plaque-made-honor-law-enforcement-found-128905408</link>
      <description>Approaching the fifth anniversary of the Jan. 6, 2021, attack on the Capitol, the official plaque honoring the police who defended democracy is nowhere to be found</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Japan is fighting back against a surge of bear attacks</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/world/asia/japan-bear-attacks-fight-back-rcna246727</link>
      <description>ODATE, Japan — Before students can come out to play at his school, Yoji Hikage has to give the all clear.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 10:50:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>NBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Guard arrives in New Orleans for 1st New Year's since Bourbon Street attack</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/national-guard-arrives-new-orleans-1st-new-years-128792537</link>
      <description>Nearly a year after a New Year's Day truck attack on Bourbon Street left 14 dead, New Orleans officials are still seeking permanent security solutions</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 01:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Guard deploying to New Orleans as city marks 1 year since terror attack</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/national-guard-new-orleans-year-after-bourbon-street-terror-attack/</link>
      <description>The Guard members will stay through Carnival season, when residents and tourists descend on the Big Easy to partake in costumed celebrations and massive parades before ending with Mardi Gras.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 02:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>National Guard to patrol New Orleans for New Year's a year after deadly attack</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/national-guard-patrol-new-orleans-new-years-year-128766113</link>
      <description>A National Guard deployment in New Orleans authorized by President Donald Trump will begin Tuesday as part of a heavy security presence for New Year’s celebrations</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Families of Bondi Beach victims demand more federal action on antisemitism and security failures</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/families-bondi-beach-victims-demand-federal-action-antisemitism-128744170</link>
      <description>Families of victims of the recent Sydney massacre are urging more federal action to investigate rising antisemitism and security failures</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 06:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Delaware State Police say DMV gunman let customers leave, fired at approaching officers</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/delaware-state-police-dmv-gunman-customers-leave-fired-128708544</link>
      <description>Investigators say a man accused of fatally shooting a Delaware State Police trooper at a DMV office allowed customers to leave and then fired at approaching officers before being killed</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:45:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia announces bravery award for heroes of Bondi Beach attack</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/australia-bravery-award-heroes-bondi-beach-antisemitic-attack/</link>
      <description>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has announced a national bravery award to honor those who confronted an antisemitic terror attack.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 21:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Albanese announces bravery award for heroes of Bondi antisemitic attack</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/albanese-announces-bravery-award-heroes-bondi-antisemitic-attack-128689526</link>
      <description>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has announced a national bravery award to honor those who confronted an antisemitic terror attack</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 04:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pentagon to send 350 National Guard troops to New Orleans as violent crime surges ahead of major events</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/pentagon-send-350-national-guard-troops-new-orleans-violent-crime-surges-ahead-major-events</link>
      <description>More than 300 national Guard troops will assist law enforcement in New Orleans through Mardi Gras as officials work to combat rising violent crime.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 20:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bureaucratic mishap delayed gun license for accused Bondi Beach shooter in Australia</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/bureaucratic-mishap-delayed-gun-license-accused-bondi-beach-128641695</link>
      <description>An Australian state leader says a man accused of killing 15 people at Sydney’s Bondi Beach faced a lengthy gun license delay due to bureaucracy, not suspicion</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thousands of mourners gather at Bondi Beach to honor attack victims</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/bondi-beach-mourners-antisemitic-attack-victims/</link>
      <description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese, whose government earlier this year recongized a Palestinian state, was booed by the crowd.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 13:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One week on from Bondi Beach attack, Australia orders security review as thousands attend memorial</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/world/australia/one-week-bondi-beach-attack-australia-orders-security-review-rcna250290</link>
      <description>Thousands turned out for a memorial on Sunday, one week on from the Bondi Beach mass shooting that shook Australia, as officials announced a review of the country's law enforcement and intelligence agencies</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 12:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>NBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia marks Day of Reflection for Bondi Beach shooting victims</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/australia-marks-day-reflection-bondi-beach-shooting-victims-128590005</link>
      <description>Australians are lighting candles Sunday to remember the victims of a mass shooting at a Jewish festival in Sydney's Bondi Beach</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:46:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After Bondi Beach attack, 'intifada' chants face restrictions in Australia and the U.K.</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/world/australia/bondi-beach-attack-intifada-chants-face-restrictions-uk-rcna250196</link>
      <description>LONDON — Authorities in Britain and Australia are tightening restrictions on pro-Palestinians protests in response to the Islamic State-inspired Bondi Beach massacre targeting a Jewish gathering that killed 15 people</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 16:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>NBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deadly attacks in Australia and Syria show a diminished ISIS is still a threat</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/world/middle-east/isis-resurgence-deadly-attacks-australia-syria-rcna250085</link>
      <description>A pair of deadly attacks in Syria and Australia has shone a fresh spotlight on the Islamic State, the militant group.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>NBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Families mourn loved ones lost in Bondi Beach terror attack: ‘No words can describe the pain’</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/world/families-mourn-loved-ones-lost-bondi-beach-terror-attack-no-words-can-describe-pain</link>
      <description>Families of Bondi Beach shooting victims share heartbreaking tributes to their loved ones killed in the deadly terror attack during Hanukkah celebration.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 09:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phil Mickelson pushes back on Australian PM's push for even tougher gun laws after Hanukkah terror attack</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/sports/phil-mickelson-pushes-back-australian-pms-push-even-tougher-gun-laws-after-hanukkah-terror-attack</link>
      <description>Phil Mickelson responded to Australia shooting debate while heroic bystanders Boris and Sofia Gurman died trying to stop the Bondi Beach gunmen during the massacre.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alleged Bondi Beach gunman charged with 15 counts of murder, police say</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/International/alleged-bondi-beach-gunman-charged-15-counts-murder/story?id=128475208</link>
      <description>The man who allegedly opened fire on a Jewish gathering at Australia’s Bondi Beach has been charged with 15 counts of murder, New South Wales Police said.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plans for attack in New Orleans thwarted, authorities say</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/plans-attack-new-orleans-thwarted-authorities-128472623</link>
      <description>Authorities say plans for an attack in New Orleans were thwarted after an ex-Marine was arrested</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 04:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10-year-old girl, Holocaust survivor among victims of deadly Australia Hanukkah attack</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/world/10-year-old-girl-holocaust-survivor-among-victims-deadly-australia-hanukkah-attack</link>
      <description>Bondi Beach terror attack during Hanukkah celebration leaves at least 15 dead in Sydney, including 10-year-old girl and a Holocaust survivor.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 20:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Washington man allegedly lures police with bogus 911 call, slashes officer in face</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/us/washington-man-allegedly-lures-police-bogus-911-call-slashes-officer-face</link>
      <description>Man charged after stabbing Bellevue police officer in face during ambush attack following a bogus 911 call at a transit center near Seattle on Tuesday.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bystanders seen confronting Australian gunman during ISIS-inspired deadly rampage</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/world/bystanders-seen-confronting-australian-gunman-during-isis-inspired-deadly-rampage</link>
      <description>Heroic bystanders were seen on video disarming an ISIS-inspired gunman on a deadly shooting rampage in Sydney, Australia, during a Hanukkah celebration.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 13:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New video shows elderly couple trying to tackle Bondi gunman</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/world/australia/new-video-shows-elderly-couple-disarm-bondi-beach-gunman-rcna249446</link>
      <description>Dramatic new footage has emerged showing an elderly couple who were killed in the Bondi Beach shooting attempt to stop and disarm one of the gunmen.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 12:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>NBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pope Leo XIV condemns 'antisemitic violence' after massacre in Sydney: 'We must eliminate hatred'</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/world/pope-leo-xiv-condemns-antisemitic-violence-massacre-sydney-we-must-eliminate-hatred</link>
      <description>Pope Leo XIV offered prayers and condemned &quot;antisemitic violence&quot; following a shooting at a Hanukkah celebration in Sydney killed 15 victims.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 21:37:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Australia moves to tighten gun laws after Hanukkah mass shooting leaves 15 dead at Bondi Beach</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/world/australia-moves-tighten-gun-laws-after-hanukkah-mass-shooting-leaves-15-dead-bondi-beach</link>
      <description>Australia is vowing to enact tougher gun controls after a targeted Hanukkah shooting at Bondi Beach leaves 15 dead and many people injured.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 21:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mamdani condemns ‘antisemitic terror’ after Hanukkah massacre — but mum on ‘globalize the intifada’</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/politics/mamdani-condemns-antisemitic-terror-after-hanukkah-massacre-mum-globalize-intifada</link>
      <description>NYC mayor-elect Zohran Mamdani condemns Australia Hanukkah attack as &quot;vile antisemitic terror&quot; but stops short of condemning controversial phrase.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What we know about the father and son suspects in the Bondi Beach attack</title>
      <link>https://www.nbcnews.com/world/australia/bondi-beach-attack-suspects-father-son-rcna249258</link>
      <description>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said the suspects in the shooting at the Hanukkah event in Sydney were “clearly” motivated by extremist ideology.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:36:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>NBC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>‘We warned them’ Jewish leader says after Bondi Beach terror attack that kills 15</title>
      <link>https://www.foxnews.com/world/we-warned-them-jewish-leader-says-after-bondi-beach-terror-attack-kills-15</link>
      <description>Jewish leader says government ignored warnings before deadly Bondi Beach terror attack at Hanukkah event killed 15. &quot;We warned them this would happen.&quot;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>Fox News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photos show the scene of a deadly attack on Sydney's Bondi Beach</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/photos-show-scene-deadly-attack-sydneys-bondi-beach-128390339</link>
      <description>Two gunmen shot dead at least 11 people on Sunday during a Jewish holiday celebration at Sydney’s Bondi Beach, Australian authorities said, declaring it a terrorist attack. One gunman was fatally shot by police and the second arrested.

___

This is a photo g…</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suspects in deadly Bondi Beach attack identified as father and son</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/australia-bondi-beach-suspects-father-and-son/</link>
      <description>The 50-year-old father was shot and killed by police, and the 24-year-old son is hospitalized, New South Wales Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon said.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 22:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mass shootings are rare in Australia. Here is a look at some previous attacks</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/mass-shootings-rare-australia-previous-attacks-128389759</link>
      <description>Police say at least 11 people were killed Sunday in a shooting attack on a Jewish community event at Sydney’s Bondi Beach</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gunmen kill 9 people at Sydney's Bondi Beach with 1 shooter dead and another arrested</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/International/wireStory/gunmen-kill-9-people-sydneys-bondi-beach-1-128388377</link>
      <description>Two gunmen have shot dead nine people at Sydney’s Bondi Beach</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 10:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>general</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A list of deadly shootings on college campuses in the US</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/list-deadly-shootings-college-campuses-us-128384701</link>
      <description>The latest shooting on a college campus in the U.S. unfolded Saturday at Brown University in Providence, Rhode Island</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 02:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Family of 16-year-old killed by police in San Diego to receive $30 million settlement</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/video/family-of-16-year-old-killed-by-police-in-san-diego-to-receive-30-million-settlement/</link>
      <description>The family of Konoa Wilson will receive $30 million from the city of San Diego after the 16-year-old was shot and killed by a police officer in January while fleeing gunfire. Carter Evans reports.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$30 million settlement approved for family of teen killed by San Diego police</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/news/konoa-wilson-death-settlement-teen-killed-san-diego-police/</link>
      <description>The settlement approved for Konoa Wilson's family exceeds the $27 million the city of Minneapolis agreed to pay the family of George Floyd.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:47:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>San Diego officials approve $30M settlement for family of teen killed by police</title>
      <link>https://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/san-diego-officials-approve-30m-settlement-family-teen-128256496</link>
      <description>The San Diego City Council has approved a $30 million payment to the family of a 16-year-old killed by police</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:56:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>ABC News</source>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Baltimore County police shootings raise concerns over mental health response</title>
      <link>https://www.cbsnews.com/baltimore/news/baltimore-county-shootings-police-mental-health-maryland/</link>
      <description>All four incidents where people were killed by Baltimore County police this year involved subjects with mental health issues, according to family members.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 01:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>incident</category>
      <source>CBS News</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
