<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Justin Nix</title>
    <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Justin Nix</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Body-worn cameras and transparency: Experimental evidence of inconsistency in police executive decision-making</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/35-jq-bwc-transparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/35-jq-bwc-transparency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SUMMARY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Body-worn cameras (BWCs) have &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/1098611120917937&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rapidly diffused&lt;/a&gt; throughout US policing over the last decade. As of 2016, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bjs.gov/content/pub/pdf/bwclea16.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;47 percent&lt;/a&gt; of all general-purpose law enforcement agencies had acquired BWCs. The general idea is that BWCs will increase transparency and accountability - and maybe even improve police-citizen interactions. The extant literature is rather mixed, but BWCs have consistently been shown to reduce complaints against officers.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Yet, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/1745-9133.12412&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;recent meta review&lt;/a&gt; of 70 evaluation studies by Cynthia Lum and her colleagues concluded that &amp;ldquo;expectations and concerns surrounding BWCs among police leaders and citizens have not yet been realized by and large in the ways anticipated by each&amp;rdquo; (p. 93).&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing my coauthors and I have noticed is how inconsistent agencies seem to be about releasing footage of critical incidents (e.g., use of force incidents) to the public. According to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncsl.org/research/civil-and-criminal-justice/body-worn-cameras-interactive-graphic.aspx#/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;National Conference of State Legislatures&lt;/a&gt;, 23 states and the District of Columbia have legislation pertaining to how BWC footage is addressed under open record laws. Yet even in those states, there are many exemptions that give police leaders the discretion to delay or withhold footage. To be sure, there may be legitimate reasons to do so (e.g., protecting victims or informants). But one thing seems clear: the public expects BWC footage of critical incidents to be released quickly. When it isn&amp;rsquo;t, agencies risk diminishing their legitimacy in the eyes of the public - many of whom might suspect they&amp;rsquo;re hiding something. Ironically, then, BWCs &lt;em&gt;reduce&lt;/em&gt; transparency if agencies have them but fail to release footage of critical incidents quickly.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our new experimental study forthcoming in &lt;em&gt;Justice Quarterly&lt;/em&gt;, we presented a nationally representative sample&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of police chiefs (N=476) with the following hypothetical vignette:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While on patrol, officers from your agency are dispatched to a home invasion in progress in a residential area. The caller describes the suspect as a [Black/white] male. One of your officers arrives on-scene and makes contact with a [Black/white] male who fits this description in front of the house. The suspect has his hands in his pockets and does not comply with your officer’s commands to show his hands. The suspect then quickly removes his hands from his pocket holding an object. Your officer fires at the suspect, killing him on the scene. Afterward, the officer finds that the object was a [handgun/cellphone]. The officer’s BWC captures full audio and video of the incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the suspect&amp;rsquo;s race was randomly assigned, as was the object he pulled from his pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then asked the chiefs a series of questions about how they envisioned the aftermath of the shooting, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How they believed the incident would be portrayed by the media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How important they felt it would be to state publicly that the shooting was justified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How important they personally felt it would be (regardless of law or policy) to release the footage quickly, make a statement to the media within 24 hours, keep the community updated on social media, and so on (see p. 9 of the post-print linked above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For detailed results, download the full text. But the big picture takeaway is that chiefs&amp;rsquo; attitudes and decision-making were inconsistent. In addition to the suspect&amp;rsquo;s race and whether he was armed or unarmed, the size of responding chiefs&amp;rsquo; agencies (in terms of the number of sworn officers) seemed to affect their views about the incident. For example, chiefs in the smallest agencies seemed to think media coverage of the shooting would be similar regardless of whether the suspect had pulled a gun or a cellphone from his pocket. But in larger agencies - and particularly in the largest agencies - chiefs clearly felt media coverage would be more hostile if the object had been a cellphone:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jnix.netlify.app/img/jq_bwcs_media.png&#34; alt=&#34;bwc_trans1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So clearly something about agency size conditions the way executives view shootings like these, and how they respond to them when they&amp;rsquo;re recorded by BWCs. We were able to rule out urbanicity and violent crime (see Appendix E), but perhaps it has more to do with an agency&amp;rsquo;s recent history (or lack thereof) with critical incidents akin to the one we described (h/t to the peer reviewers for suggesting this supplemental analysis).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the broadest sense, our results suggest that legislation dictating when BWC footage must be released might be necessary. &lt;strong&gt;Details about an incident - such as whether the victim is Black or white, or whether he was armed or unarmed - should not influence whether the public gets to see the footage.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;It is unclear &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; they reduce complaints, however. Maybe they improve officer behavior, maybe citizens are less likely to file frivolous complaints, maybe a little bit of both.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;I believe this team also has a meta analysis of experimental and quasi-experimental evaluation studies forthcoming in &lt;em&gt;Campbell Systematic Reviews.&lt;/em&gt; 
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;As I write this, people are protesting in Rochester after BWC footage of Daniel Prude&amp;rsquo;s March 23rd arrest was just released (Prude wound up on life support and died 7 days later). Or consider the fatal shooting of Keith Lamont Scott in Charlotte. The incident was recorded by BWCs, but footage wasn&amp;rsquo;t released for 4 days. During that time, violent protests resulted in dozens of civilian injuries and one death. Or consider the altercation between an Alameda County sheriff&amp;rsquo;s deputy and Masai Ujiri (president of basketball operations for the Toronto Raptors) during the 2019 NBA finals. For whatever reason, BWC footage wasn&amp;rsquo;t made publicly available until over a year later, as a result of a countersuit Ujiri filed against the deputy. The footage &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usatoday.com/story/sports/nba/raptors/2020/08/18/new-video-officer-shoves-masai-ujiri-during-altercation-nba-finals/3398114001/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;seems to depict&lt;/a&gt; the deputy as the aggressor. 
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;We mailed surveys to a stratified random sample of 2,496 police chiefs. We stratified on agency size: 0-24, 25-49, 50-99, or 100+ full-time, sworn officers. We achieved a 27% response rate. But don&amp;rsquo;t get me started on whether that&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bad.&amp;rdquo;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;^&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the challenges associated with the study of police use of deadly force in the United States: A response to Schwartz &amp; Jahn</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/34-plosone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/34-plosone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original article I comment on is freely available &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article/file?type=printable&amp;amp;id=10.1371/journal.pone.0229686&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gun victimization in the line of duty: Fatal and non-fatal firearm assaults on police officers in the United States, 2014-2019</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/33-cpp-gva/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/33-cpp-gva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replication files are available at the top of this page. All analyses were performed in Stata v15.1. For Figure 4, you will need to install Michael Stepner&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://michaelstepner.com/maptile/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;maptile and spmap&lt;/a&gt; commands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procedural Justice in Policing</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/chapter-pj-critical_issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/chapter-pj-critical_issues/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defunding or disbanding the police is a dangerous idea if done hastily</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/32-wapo-defunding-oped/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/32-wapo-defunding-oped/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding body-worn camera diffusion in U.S. policing</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/31-pq-bwc-diffusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/31-pq-bwc-diffusion/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Police Killings of Unarmed Persons Really Have Spillover Effects? Reanalyzing Bor et al. (2018)</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/preprint-bor_replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/preprint-bor_replication/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considering Violence Against Police by Citizen Race/Ethnicity to Contextualize Representation in Officer-Involved Shootings</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/30-jcj-oisbenchmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/30-jcj-oisbenchmarks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My co-author &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Shjarback_CCJ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;John Shjarback&lt;/a&gt; summarizes the paper nicely in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Shjarback_CCJ/status/1204790201714958344&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Twitter thread&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Domestic Disturbances Really More Dangerous to Police? Findings from the 2016 National Incident Based Reporting System</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/29-domestics-nibrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/29-domestics-nibrs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a Theoretical Model of Perceived Audience Legitimacy: The Neglected Linkage in the Dialogic Model of Police–community Relations</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/28-perceived-aud-legit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/28-perceived-aud-legit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compliance, Noncompliance, and the In-between: Causal Effects of Civilian Demeanor on Police Officers’ Cognitions and Emotions</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/27-demeanor-experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/27-demeanor-experiments/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Research, Officer Surveys, and Response Rates</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/22-response-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/22-response-rates/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of 2018 Use of Deadly Force by the Phoenix Police Department</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/report-pf_phx_ois/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/report-pf_phx_ois/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demeanor and Police Culture: Theorizing How Civilian Cooperation Influences Police Officers</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/26-pjc-demeanor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/26-pjc-demeanor/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disparity Does Not Mean Bias: Making Sense of Observed Racial Disparities in Fatal Officer-involved Shootings with Multiple Benchmarks</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/23-disparity-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/23-disparity-bias/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Las Vegas Mass Shooting: An Analysis of Blood Component Administration and Blood Bank Donations</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/24-lvshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/24-lvshooting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ecological Structuring of Police Officers’ Perceptions of Citizen Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/19-ecological-cooperation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/19-ecological-cooperation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Officers’ Attitudes Toward Citizen Advisory Councils</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/21-citizen-oversight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/21-citizen-oversight/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing a Social Schematic Model of Police Procedural Justice</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/20-rjs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/20-rjs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Management-level Officers’ Experiences with the Ferguson effect</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/16-mgmt-ferguson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/16-mgmt-ferguson/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Domestic Disturbances and Fatal Police Shootings: An Analysis of the Washington Post’s Data</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/17-domestic-ois/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/17-domestic-ois/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Number of Citizens Fatally Shot by Police Increasing in the Post-Ferguson Era?</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/15-are-fatalois-increasing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/15-are-fatalois-increasing/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Managers’ Self-Control and Support for Organizational Justice</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/18-mgmt-sc-oj/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/18-mgmt-sc-oj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command-level Police Officers&#39; Perceptions of the &#39;War on Cops&#39; and De-policing</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/14-perceived-war-on-cops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/14-perceived-war-on-cops/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demeanor, Race, and Police Perceptions of Procedural Justice: Evidence from Two Randomized Experiments</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/13-demeanor-pj-experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/13-demeanor-pj-experiments/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Perceptions of Their External Legitimacy in High and Low Crime Areas of the Community</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/10-ext-legit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/10-ext-legit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of _When Police Kill_</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/bookreview-when_police_kill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/bookreview-when_police_kill/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A War on Cops? The Effects of Ferguson on the Number of U.S. Police Officers Murdered in the Line of Duty</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/8-war-on-cops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/8-war-on-cops/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the Police Believe That Legitimacy Promotes Cooperation From the Public?</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/11-extlegit-coop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/11-extlegit-coop/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third-person Perceptions, Hostile Media Effects, and Policing: Developing a Theoretical Framework for Assessing the Ferguson Effect</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/12-hostile-media-efx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/12-hostile-media-efx/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Police Officers&#39; Trust in Their Agency: Does Self-Legitimacy Protect Against Supervisor Procedural Injustice?</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/9-police-trust-in-agency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/9-police-trust-in-agency/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bird&#39;s Eye View of Civilians Killed by Police in 2015: Further Evidence of Implicit Bias</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/6-birds-eye/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/6-birds-eye/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Negative Publicity on Police Self-legitimacy</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/7-negpub-selflegit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/7-negpub-selflegit/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensitivity to the Ferguson Effect: The Role of Managerial Organizational Justice</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/4-sensitivity-to-ferg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/4-sensitivity-to-ferg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Use of Social Media by Alleged Members of Mexican Cartels and Affiliated Drug Trafficking Organizations</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/5-cartels/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/5-cartels/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Effect of Procedural Justice on Police Legitimacy Invariant? Testing the Generality of Procedural Justice and Competing Antecedents of Legitimacy</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/3-invariance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/3-invariance/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of _Pulled Over: How Police Stops Define Race and Citizenship_</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/bookreview-pulled_over/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/bookreview-pulled_over/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alleged Ferguson Effect and Police Willingness to Engage in Community Partnership</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/2-alleged-ferg-effect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/2-alleged-ferg-effect/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust in the Police:  The Influence of Procedural Justice and Perceived Collective Efficacy</title>
      <link>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/1-trust-in-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jnix.netlify.app/publication/1-trust-in-police/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
